<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
    xmlns:mi="http://schemas.ingestion.microsoft.com/common/"
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
    xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
    xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Newsweek feed for VMG</title>
        <link>https://feeds.newsweek.com/feeds/1zfgy.rss</link>
        <atom:link href="https://feeds.newsweek.com/feeds/1zfgy.rss" rel="self"
            type="application/rss+xml" />
        <description />
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Yankees May Need Outfield Replacement After $80 Million Acquisition's 'Mixed' Returns ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ The New York Yankees traded for Cody Bellinger in the offseason from the Chicago Cubs but has an opt out at the end of the year and could leave in free agency. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <div><p>The New York Yankees will have work to do to keep Cody Bellinger in the Bronx.</p> <p>After trading for the 29-year-old outfielder in the offseason, the Yankees thought they had locked down their center fielder of the future. However, it's possible they have to start over at the end of the year.</p> <p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.nytimes.com/athletic/6367630/2025/05/21/mlb-free-agents-2025-2026-offseason-kyle-tucker-alex-bregman/" target="_blank">Jim Bowden of The Athletic</a> believes Bellinger could opt out after the season.</p> <p>"We didn't know how Bellinger would do changing leagues and how he'd handle New York," wrote Bowden. "The Yankees certainly hoped the small right-field confines at Yankee Stadium would help get his power back to at least the 25-30 homer range. The early returns have been mixed as Bellinger is batting .258 with seven homers, four steals and a 123 OPS+. His above-average defense at all three outfield positions and first base helps his value, but he needs to be more consistent at the plate to land a long-term contract."</p> <p>Bellinger has the possibility to leave his three-year, $80 million contract through a player option ahead of next season with a buyout of $5 million. The Yankees will be hoping this season is enough to keep him in New York.</p> <p>The former Dodgers and Cubs outfielder has had an up-and-down career to this point, but he could bet on himself when the opportunity arises. He didn't do so after last season as a result of hitting .266 -- a lower number by his standards.</p> <p>Bellinger will need to step it up the rest of the season if he's searching for a major long-term extension.</p> <p><em><strong>More MLB: </strong><strong><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/mlb/mets-outfield-target-admits-hes-not-good-trade-candidate-right-now-2075400" target="_blank">Mets Outfield Target Admits He's Not 'Good Trade Candidate' Right Now</a></strong></em></p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/mlb/padres-71-million-starting-pitcher-may-opt-out-dodgers-pursue-2075506">Padres $71 Million Starting Pitcher May Opt Out; Dodgers to Pursue?</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/mlb/no-chance-pirates-superstar-pitcher-gets-traded-team-struggles-2075497">'No Chance' Pirates Superstar Pitcher Gets Traded As Team Struggles</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/mlb/former-phillies-brewers-mariners-all-star-announces-sudden-retirement-mlb-2075505">Former Phillies, Brewers, Mariners All-Star Announces Sudden Retirement From MLB</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/mlb/dodgers-yankees-linked-two-time-all-star-bo-bichette-ahead-offseason-2075428">Dodgers, Yankees Linked to Two-Time All-Star Bo Bichette Ahead of Offseason</a></li></ul></p></div> ]]>
</content:encoded>

            <link>
                https://www.newsweek.com/sports/mlb/yankees-may-need-outfield-replacement-after-80-million-acquisitions-mixed-returns-2075512</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 07:30:50 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075512</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Drew VonScio ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ MLB ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T07:30:50-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T07:30:50-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content
                url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649345/new-york-yankees-outfielder-cody-bellinger.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="2500" height="1712">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ New York Yankees, Outfielder, Cody Bellinger ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Al Bello/Getty Images ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ NEW YORK, NEW YORK - MAY 18: Cody Bellinger #35 of the New York Yankees hits a grand slam home run against Génesis Cabrera #92 of the New York Mets in the eighth inning during their game at Yankee Stadium on May 18, 2025 in New York City. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3080/mlb-2025-predictions-here-1743200245.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="69">
                <guid>616154</guid>
                <media:thumbnail
                    url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2617265/baseball-mlb-2025-opening.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ MLB Expert Predictions for Entire 2025 Season ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ The 2025 MLB season is here at last. Which teams will emerge victorious in each division? What will the playoffs feature? Who will be the award winners at season's end? Here are projections for the complete 2025 season's outcomes. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ various sources ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ South Africa's president ribs Trump: "I don't have a plane to give you" ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ "I'm sorry I don't have a plane to give you," South African President Cyril Ramaphosa told Trump during a tense Oval Office meeting. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>South African President Cyril Ramaphosa ribbed President <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/donald-trump" data-sys="1">Donald Trump</a> during a tense Oval Office meeting on Wednesday, saying he didn't have a plane to gift him after the U.S. accepted a luxury jet from Qatar.</p><h2>The Context</h2><p>Democrats and <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/republicans" data-sys="1">Republicans</a> alike have raised concerns about whether Qatar could be gifting the $400 million jet to the U.S. to influence Trump's foreign policy decisions.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/pentagon" data-sys="1">Pentagon</a> confirmed Wednesday that it has formally accepted the plane, described as a "palace in the sky," and tasked the U.S. Air Force with upgrading the jet so Trump can use it as a new Air Force One.</p><h2>What To Know</h2><p>NBC's Peter Alexander asked Trump about the Pentagon accepting the plane during Trump's Oval Office meeting with Ramaphosa on Wednesday.</p><p>The question came after Trump spent several minutes showing Ramaphosa photos, videos and newspaper articles that he claimed were proof of a "white genocide" happening in South Africa.</p><p>"Mr. President, the Pentagon announced that it would be accepting a Qatari jet to be used as Air Force One..." Alexander said, before Trump cut him off. The president called Alexander an "idiot" and accused <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/nbc" data-sys="1">NBC</a> of trying to distract from his allegations against South Africa by asking about the Qatari jet.</p><p>Trump also suggested NBC executives should be "investigated" and later elaborated on why Qatar was gifting the plane to the Pentagon.</p><p>"Why did a country give an airplane to the United States Air Force?...So they could help us out, because we need an Air Force One," Trump said. He then gestured to Alexander, saying, "That's what that idiot talks about, after viewing a thing where thousands of people are dead."</p><p>Ramaphosa cut in, saying, "I'm sorry I don't have a plane to give you."</p><p>"I wish you did," Trump responded, drawing laughter from Ramaphosa. "I would take it. If your country offered the United States Air Force a plane, I would take it."</p><p>"Okay," the South African president replied.</p><p>He then turned back to Trump's claims of white farmers being persecuted in South Africa, saying he would like to discuss the issue with Trump "calmly."</p><p>"We were taught by Nelson Mandela that whenever there are problems, people need to sit down around a table and talk about them," Ramaphosa said.</p><p>"Well, there are problems," Trump said.</p><p>The Trump administration has repeatedly accused the South African government of taking land from white farmers without any compensation and that white people in the country are being killed en masse. South Africa has categorically denied the allegations and the country's Ministry of International Relations and Cooperation told its American counterparts earlier this month that the claims were unfounded.</p><p>In February, a South African court ruled that claims of a white genocide were "clearly imagined" and "not real." Police figures showed around 44 murders on farms and agricultural land in 2024, with eight farmers among them.</p><p>The Trump administration nevertheless granted refugee status to Afrikaners&mdash;despite cracking down on asylum-seekers from virtually all other countries&mdash;and welcomed the first group of Afrikaners to the U.S. earlier this month.</p><h2>What People Are Saying</h2><p><strong>Pentagon spokesperson Sean Parnell said in a statement Wednesday: </strong>"The secretary of defense has accepted a Boeing 747 from Qatar in accordance with all federal rules and regulations. The Department of Defense will work to ensure proper security measures and functional-mission requirements are considered for an aircraft used to transport the president of the United States."</p><p><strong>Senate Majority Leader John Thune said this month Congress will dig into how the Qatari jet will be used as Air Force One: </strong>"If and when it's no longer a hypothetical, I can assure you there will be plenty of scrutiny of whatever that arrangement might look like."</p><h2>What Else Did Trump Say to Ramaphosa?</h2><p>During the Oval Office meeting, Trump confronted Ramaphosa with a video featuring South African political figures chanting "kill the Boer, kill the farmer."</p><p>Trump used this footage to support his claims of alleged persecution of white South Africans. When questioned about the location of alleged grave sites of white farmers, Trump simply responded, "South Africa."</p><p>Ramaphosa condemned the chants but pushed back against claims of persecution against white South Africans.</p><h2><strong>What Happens Next</strong></h2><p>When a reporter asked Trump what it would take to be convinced that there is no genocide against white South Africans, Ramaphosa jumped in and said: "It will take President Trump listening to the voices of South Africa&mdash;some of them are his friends."</p><p><em>Update 5/21/25 2:26 p.m. ET: This article has been updated with additional information and context.</em></p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/map-shows-where-manufacturing-growing-2075521">Map Shows Where Manufacturing Is Growing</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/trump-giving-very-serious-consideration-major-mortgage-companies-move-2075572">Trump Giving 'Very Serious Consideration' to Major Mortgage Companies Move</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/new-us-iran-nuclear-talks-tensions-rise-2075575">New US-Iran Nuclear Talks as Tensions Rise</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/what-moodys-credit-rating-cut-means-us-economy-2075325">What Credit Rating Cut Means for America's Economy</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>https://www.newsweek.com/south-africa-president-ramaphosa-trump-plane-2075371</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 13:58:36 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075371</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Sonam Sheth ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ Politics ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-21T13:58:36-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T07:30:43-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649162/trump-ramaphosa.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="2500" height="1667">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Trump Ramaphosa ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Evan Vucci/AP ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ President Donald Trump meets South African President Cyril Ramaphosa in the Oval Office of the White House, Wednesday, May 21, 2025, in Washington. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3098/sa-plane-1747849653.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="10">
                <guid>619638</guid>
                <media:thumbnail
                    url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649169/south-africas-president-ribs-trump-i-dont.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Ramaphosa Teases Trump: 'I Don't Have A Plane To Give You' ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ South African President Cyril Ramaphosa joked with President Donald Trump over the Qatari jet set to become the new Air Force One. "I'm sorry I don't have a plane to give you." ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Newsweek/AP ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Trump's 'big beautiful bill' passed by US House ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ U.S. House of Representatives narrowly passes sweeping budget package. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>The U.S. House of Representatives narrowly passed President <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/donald-trump" data-sys="1">Donald Trump</a>'s sweeping budget package, marking the first major legislative milestone of his second term in office.</p><p>In a razor-thin 215&mdash;214 vote held early Thursday morning, the Republican-led House pushed through the more-than-1,000-page bill after days of tense negotiations among deeply divided GOP factions.</p><p>The budget bill now moves to the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/senate" data-sys="1">Senate</a>, where <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/republicans" data-sys="1">Republicans</a> maintain a slim majority.</p><h2>Two Republicans Vote Against Bill</h2><p><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/full-list-republicans-voted-against-trump-big-beautiful-bill-2075522" target="_blank">Two Republicans broke ranks and joined every House Democrat in voting against the bill</a>, Representative <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/thomas-massie" data-sys="1">Thomas Massie</a> of Kentucky and Representative Warren Davidson of Ohio. Representative Andy Harris of Maryland, the chair of the House Freedom Caucus, voted "present." Two Republicans, Representatives David Schweikert of Arizona and Andrew Garbarino of New York, did not vote.</p><h2>Why It Matters</h2><p>The legislation would make permanent the individual income and estate tax cuts passed during Trump's first term and add fresh exemptions for tipped income, overtime pay, and interest on certain auto loans&mdash;moves designed to appeal to working-class voters.</p><p>To help offset the anticipated revenue shortfall, estimated at roughly $3.8 trillion, the bill would repeal or fast-track the expiration of clean energy tax credits enacted under President <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/joe-biden" data-sys="1">Joe Biden</a>. That rollback would substantially reduce the net cost of the package.</p><p>Among the temporary measures included is a boost to the standard deduction: an increase of $1,000 for individual taxpayers, bringing it to $16,000, and a $2,000 increase for joint filers, raising their deduction to $32,000. The deduction directly reduces taxable income.</p><p>The child tax credit would also see a temporary $500 increase, rising to $2,500 for tax years 2025 through 2028, before reverting to $2,000. Future adjustments would be pegged to inflation.</p><p>In a significant win for wealthier households, the estate tax exemption would climb to $15 million, with annual inflation adjustments ensuring it continues to rise over time.</p><h2>New work requirements for Medicaid</h2><p>A focal point of the package is nearly $700 billion in reduced spending in the Medicaid program, according to the Congressional Budget Office.</p><p>To be eligible for Medicaid, there would be new "community engagement requirements" of at least 80 hours per month of work, education or service for able-bodied adults without dependents. The new requirements would begin on Dec. 31, 2026. People would also have to verify their eligibility for the program twice a year, rather than just once.</p><h2>What People Are Saying</h2><p><strong>Congressman Tony Gonzales</strong> said: "After four years of disastrous national security and economic policies, we're putting America back on the right track.</p><p>"This morning, I voted yes on the House reconciliation package, which includes funding to reimburse our state for Operation Lone Star costs, a priority I've fought for since House budget talks began. Through my seat on the House Homeland Security Committee, I helped shape the bill's border security provisions, which include funding for checkpoint upgrades, new technology and infrastructure, Operation Stonegarden law enforcement grants, and CBP bonuses. This legislation also extends critical tax cuts, protecting TX-23 families from a 24% tax hike, and streamlines natural gas permitting to boost energy production in West Texas and lower energy costs."</p><p><em>This is a breaking news story&mdash;more to follow.</em></p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/right-wing-culture-war-scam-comes-full-circle-opinion-2075404">The Right-Wing Culture War Scam Comes Full Circle | Opinion</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/tax-cuts-child-credit-big-beautiful-bill-trump-2075472">Trump's 'Big, Beautiful Bill' Passes: What Taxpayers Should Know</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/map-shows-where-manufacturing-growing-2075521">Map Shows Where Manufacturing Is Growing</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/trump-giving-very-serious-consideration-major-mortgage-companies-move-2075572">Trump Giving 'Very Serious Consideration' to Major Mortgage Companies Move</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>https://www.newsweek.com/trumps-big-beautiful-bill-passed-us-house-2075670</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 07:05:28 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075670</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Barney Henderson ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ Politics ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T07:05:28-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T07:30:32-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2450666/breaking-news.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="1200" height="800">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Breaking News ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ There have been multiple arrests made in connection with the death of Matthew Perry, including at least one doctor, per TMZ. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Israeli embassy couple "about to get engaged" killed in DC shooting ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ Yaron Lischinsky had bought a ring for Sarah Milgrim, the ambassador said after the young couple were killed leaving the Capital Jewish Museum. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>Israeli embassy staff members killed in a shooting in Washington D.C. on Wednesday evening have been identified as young couple Yaron Lischinsky and Sarah Milgrim, who were about to get engaged.</p><p>Israeli Ambassador to the U.S. Yechiel Leiter said Lischinsky had bought a ring and planned to propose to Milgrim next week in Jerusalem. The Israeli embassy said the couple were "in the prime of their lives" before the attack outside the Capital Jewish Museum.</p><p>The couple were leaving an event at the museum when a gunman approached a group of four people and opened fire, Metropolitan Police Chief Pamela Smith said at a news conference.</p><p>Police have identified 30-year-old Elias Rodriguez from Chicago as the suspect. The suspect shouted "free, free Palestine" after he was arrested, Smith said.</p><h2>What To Know</h2><p>The Israeli Foreign Ministry identified the victims in a statement posted on social media early Thursday.</p><p>"We are shocked and horrified this morning by the news of the brutal terrorist attack that claimed the lives of two of our Embassy staff members in Washington &mdash; Yaron Lischinsky and Sarah Lynn Milgrim," the statement said. "May their memory be a blessing."</p><p>At a news conference, Leiter said the couple were soon to be engaged. "The young purchased a ring this week with the intention of proposing to his girlfriend next week in Jerusalem," he said.</p><p>Lischinsky, who was Christian, moved to Israel from Germany when he was 16, according to the Times of Israel. He had dual German-Israeli citizenship, the German newspaper <em>Der Spiegel</em> reported.</p><p>Lischinsky served in the Israel Defense Forces between August 2013 to August 2016 and later got a bachelor's degrees in international relations from the Hebrew University of Jerusalem and a master's degree in government, diplomacy and strategy from Reichman University, <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/yaron-lischinsky/" target="_blank">according</a> to his LinkedIn page. He had been working as a research assistant focusing on Middle East and North African affairs at the Israeli embassy in Washington, D.C. since September 2022, according to the profile.</p><p>Milgrim graduated with a bachelor's degree in environmental studies from the University of Kansas in 2021. She later earned a masters degree in international relations rom American University and another in national resources and sustainable development from the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/united-nations" data-sys="1">United Nations</a>' University for Peace, <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sarah-milgrim/details/education/" target="_blank">according</a> to her LinkedIn page. She worked at Tech2Peace, a nongovernmental organization that provides tech training to young Israelis and Palestinians, before starting a role in the Israeli embassy's department of public diplomacy in November 2023, according to the page.</p><p>"My passion lies at the intersection of peacebuilding, religious engagement, and environmental work," she wrote on the page.</p><p>The couple were shot as they were leaving the American Jewish Committee's annual Young Diplomats Reception.</p><p>The sold-out event was organized by AJC ACCESS, the committee's division for young professionals, <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/ajc-access-young-diplomats-reception-tickets-1312062246499">according</a> to its Eventbrite page. The event's location was not listed on the Eventbrite page, but it was shared with those who signed up to attend, the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/bbc" data-sys="1">BBC</a> reported.</p><p>The event was described as "bringing together Jewish young professionals (22-45) and the diplomatic community. The event's description said the theme this year was "turning pain into purpose" and attendees would hear from members of the Multifaith Alliance and IsraAID about "how a coalition of organizations - from the region and for the region - are working together in response to humanitarian crises throughout the Middle East and North Africa."</p><p>Hamas militants killed 1,200 people and took 250 hostages in an attack on Israel on October 7, 2023. Since then, Israel's offensive in Gaza has killed more than 53,000 Palestinians, the Associated Press reported, citing local Hamas-run health authorities.</p><p>Israel recently expanded its campaign against Palestinian group <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/hamas">Hamas</a> in the Gaza Strip, with Netanyahu promising to defeat Hamas in a "total victory."</p><h2>What People Are Saying</h2><p><strong>The Israeli Embassy to the U.S.</strong> said in a post on X: "The entire embassy staff is heartbroken and devastated by their murder. No words can express the depth of our grief and horror at this devastating loss. Our hearts are with their families, and the embassy will be by their side during this terrible time."</p><p><strong>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu</strong> said in a statement: "We are witnessing the terrible price of antisemitism and wild incitement against Israel."</p><p>He added: "My heart aches for the families of the beloved young man and woman, whose lives were cut short by a heinous anti-Semitic murderer."</p><p><strong>The Israel Foreign Ministry's</strong> statement added: "Israeli diplomats and representatives around the world stand on the frontlines of Israel's diplomatic efforts &mdash; defending the country with their very lives.</p><p>"We will not be deterred by terror. We will continue our mission across the globe, with unwavering commitment to represent Israel with pride."</p><p><strong>American Jewish Committee CEO Ted Deutch</strong> said in a statement: "We are devastated that two cherished friends and partners from the Israeli embassy were shot and killed as they left an American Jewish Committee (AJC) event at the Capital Jewish Museum earlier this evening. This is a shocking act of violence and our community is holding each other tighter tonight."</p><p><strong>President Donald Trump</strong> wrote on Truth Social: "These horrible D.C. killings, based obviously on antisemitism, must end, NOW! Hatred and Radicalism have no place in the USA. Condolences to the families of the victims. So sad that such things as this can happen! God Bless You ALL!"</p><h2>What's Next</h2><p>The Metropolitan Police Department and the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/fbi" data-sys="1">FBI</a> are investigating the shooting.</p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/right-wing-culture-war-scam-comes-full-circle-opinion-2075404">The Right-Wing Culture War Scam Comes Full Circle | Opinion</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/elias-rodriguez-dc-shooting-suspect-latest-israel-blames-toxic-incitement-live-updates-2075655">Elias Rodriguez, DC Shooting Suspect Latest, Israel Blames 'Toxic Incitement': Live Updates</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/who-elias-rodriguez-suspect-named-israeli-embassy-staff-killings-2075558">Who Is Elias Rodriguez? Suspect Named in Israeli Embassy Staff Killings</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/washington-dc-israeli-embassy-shooting-witness-2075565">Suspect 'Returned to Museum' after Killing Israel Embassy Staff: Eyewitness</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>
                https://www.newsweek.com/yaron-lischinsky-sarah-milgram-israeli-embassy-staff-shot-dc-2075591</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 04:05:16 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075591</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Shane Croucher ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Khaleda Rahman ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ News ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T04:05:16-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T07:30:06-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content
                url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649481/sara-milgrim-yaron-lishinksy.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="3000" height="2000">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Sara Milgrim and Yaron Lishinksy ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Embassy of Israel to the USA ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ Sara Milgrim and Yaron Lishinksy. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3098/israel-shooting-1747904564.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="55">
                <guid>619664</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649413/shooting.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Two Israeli Embassy Staff Killed In DC Shooting ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ Two Israeli embassy staff were shot dead as they left an event at the Capital Jewish Museum in Washington, DC, by a suspect who shouted "free, free Palestine" as he was arrested, police said. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ AP ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ How to Watch Charles Schwab Challenge: Live Stream PGA TOUR Golf, TV Channel ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ The PGA TOUR is back in action this week at Colonial Country Club in Texas, where some of the world's top players will compete in the Charles Schwab Challenge. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>The PGA TOUR is back in action this week at Colonial Country Club in Texas, where some of the world's top players will compete in the Charles Schwab Challenge, and you can catch all the action with <a href="https://go.web.plus.espn.com/c/5720935/931309/9070?subId1=Charles%20Schwab%20Challenge%20PGA&amp;sharedid=Newsweek%20Sports" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">ESPN+</a>.</p> <h2><strong>How to Watch Charles Schwab Challenge:</strong></h2> <ul> <li>Date: Thursday, May 22, 2025 - Sunday, May 25, 2025</li> <li>Time: 8:00 AM ET (Coverage Begins)</li> <li>Stream: ESPN+ (<strong><a rel="nofollow" href="https://go.web.plus.espn.com/c/5720935/931309/9070?subId1=Charles%20Schwab%20Challenge%20PGA&amp;sharedid=Newsweek%20Sports" target="_blank">WATCH NOW</a></strong>)</li> </ul> <p>Scottie Scheffler will compete this week, fresh off his win at the PGA Championship. Scheffler continues his dominant run as the best golfer in the world and will look to add another win to his growing list. He is starting to feel like <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/tiger-woods" data-sys="1">Tiger Woods</a> in his prime, where every time he takes the course, it is him versus the field.</p> <p>Other notable competitors include Jordan Spieth, Hideki Matsuyama, Tommy Fleetwood, and Rickie Fowler. All missed the cut last weekend, except Fleetwood, who finished tied for 41st at one under.</p> <p>Someone is going to have to step up and challenge Scheffler. It could be one of the established veterans on tour, or it might end up being one of the underdogs that no one is talking about.</p> <p>This is a great PGA TOUR event, and you do not want to miss any of the action; tune in all week to catch your favorite players on the course.</p> <p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://go.web.plus.espn.com/c/5720935/931309/9070?subId1=Charles%20Schwab%20Challenge%20PGA&amp;sharedid=Newsweek%20Sports" target="_blank"><strong>ESPN+</strong></a><strong> provides coverage of this event throughout the week, beginning early in the morning and continuing through the rest of the day. The coverage includes the main feed, marquee group, featured groups, and featured holes.</strong></p> <p><strong>Live stream Charles Schwab Challenge with ESPN+: <a rel="nofollow" href="https://go.web.plus.espn.com/c/5720935/931309/9070?subId1=Charles%20Schwab%20Challenge%20PGA&amp;sharedid=Newsweek%20Sports" target="_blank">Start your subscription now</a>!</strong></p> <p><em>Regional restrictions may apply. If you purchase a product or register for an account through one of the links on our site, we may receive compensation.</em></p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/tiger-woods-cryptic-post-continued-length-2075544">Tiger Woods Drops Cryptic 'To Be Continued' Post Looking for Length</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/john-daly-inks-deal-hooters-keep-company-alive-2074508">John Daly Inks Deal with Hooters Trying to Keep Company Alive</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/paige-spiranac-golf-story-chris-pratt-chuckling-2075442">Paige Spiranac's Chris Pratt Golf Story Will Leave You Chuckling</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/rory-mcilroy-follows-bryson-dechambeau-footsteps-dp-world-tour-history-2075464">Rory McIlroy Follows Bryson DeCambeau's Footsteps Making History</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>
                https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/how-watch-charles-schwab-challenge-live-stream-pga-tour-golf-tv-channel-2075531</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 07:30:01 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075531</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Ben Verbrugge ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ Golf ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T07:30:01-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T07:30:01-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649358/golf.jpg" type="image/jpeg"
                medium="image" expression="full" width="2500" height="1667">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Golf ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Sam Hodde/Getty Images ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ Scottie Scheffler of the United States lines up a putt on the ninth green during the third round of the Charles Schwab Challenge at Colonial Country Club on May 25, 2024 in Fort Worth, Texas. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3086/rory-mcllroy-1744655760.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="47">
                <guid>617216</guid>
                <media:thumbnail
                    url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2627033/rory-mcilroy-masters-golf-winner-2025.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Rory McIlroy Breaks Down Amid Winning the Masters ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ After 11 years of perseverance and determination, Rory McIlroy finally secured his elusive Grand Slam win, donning the iconic green jacket with tears of joy streaming down his face. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Getty images ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Full list of Republicans who voted against Trump's "big, beautiful bill" ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ Trump scored a massive legislative victory when his "big, beautiful bill" narrowly passed the House of Representatives. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>Some <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/republicans" data-sys="1">Republicans</a> broke ranks and joined every House Democrat in voting against the "big, beautiful bill" for which President <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/donald-trump" data-sys="1">Donald Trump</a> and House GOP leadership spent weeks wrangling votes.</p><p>The critical <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/trumps-big-beautiful-bill-passed-us-house-2075670" target="_blank">reconciliation bill narrowly passed the House on Thursday morning by a vote of 215-214</a>, marking a major legislative victory for Trump, who championed the huge tax breaks, spending cuts and additional funding for immigration enforcement and border security included in the plan.</p><h2>The Context</h2><p>The passage of the GOP-backed bill comes after weeks of back-and-forth in which House Speaker <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/mike-johnson" data-sys="1">Mike Johnson</a> attempted to secure votes from Republicans in competitive districts who had concerns about constituents losing critical benefits, and from the ultraconservative House Freedom Caucus, which called for further budget cuts.</p><p>For each bloc of Republicans Johnson managed to appease, he risked alienating another.</p><p>Before Thursday's vote, Johnson and Trump met at the White House with a group of GOP holdouts, aiming to convince them to vote in favor of the bill. The House speaker emerged from the meeting confident that it would pass, telling reporters at the Capitol on Wednesday, "I believe we're going to land this airplane. The 'America First' agenda is wrapped up in this one big, beautiful bill."</p><h2>Which Republicans Voted Against Trump's Bill?</h2><p>The House of Representatives has 220 Republicans and 212 <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/democrats" data-sys="1">Democrats</a>, meaning that Johnson could only afford to lose three GOP votes heading into the floor vote.</p><p>The spending bill's fate was still uncertain heading into the vote, with some House Freedom Caucus members signaling that they were hard no's from the onset, while other Republicans who were initially opposed later flipped their votes and supported the measure.</p><p>Here are the Republicans who voted against the Trump-backed bill:</p><ul> <li>Representative Thomas Massie of Kentucky.</li> <li>Representative Warren Davidson of Ohio.</li> </ul><p>Representative Andy Harris of Maryland, the chair of the House Freedom Caucus, voted "present." Two Republicans, Representatives David Schweikert of Arizona and Andrew Garbarino of New York, did not vote.</p><p>Trump's bill, called the "One Big, Beautiful Bill Act," includes a temporary boost in the standard tax deduction&mdash;a $1,000 increase for individuals, bringing it to $16,000 for individual filers, and a $2,000 boost for joint filers, bringing it to $32,000.</p><p>The measure also includes a $500 increase in the child tax credit, bringing it to $2,500 for the next three years. It will then revert to $2,000 and increase to account for inflation.</p><p>The bill cuts spending on the Supplemental Nutrition and Assistance Program by roughly $267 billion over 10 years and introduces new work requirements to qualify for the food benefits.</p><p>It also introduces additional work requirements for people seeking Medicaid, which Democrats say could result in millions of older Americans and those with disabilities losing health coverage.</p><h2>What People Are Saying</h2><p><strong>Massie unleashed on his fellow Republican colleagues while negotiations were still underway, writing on X, formerly Twitter:</strong> "Major provisions of the big beautiful bill are still being negotiated and written, yet we are being told we will vote on it today. Shouldn't we take more than a few hours to read a bill this big and this consequential?"</p><p>Massie added in a follow-up post: "It's in our rules that we will have 72 [hours] to read every bill. Yet it's been circumvented this week by a 'manager's amendment' which substantially changes the bill but should only contain technical clarifications."</p><h2>What Happens Next</h2><p>The bill now heads to the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/senate" data-sys="1">Senate</a>, where it will almost certainly be significantly changed as several Senate Republicans have expressed opposition to the Medicaid cuts in the measure that they say would harm their constituents.</p><p><em>The Associated Press contributed to this article.</em></p><p><em>Update 5/22/25 7:25 a.m. ET: This story has been updated with additional information.</em></p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/what-moodys-credit-rating-cut-means-us-economy-2075325">What Credit Rating Cut Means for America's Economy</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/republican-gives-mike-johnson-one-piece-advice-updated-trump-bill-2075533">Republican Gives Mike Johnson One Piece of Advice on Updated Trump Bill</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/gerry-connolly-death-representatives-hear-during-committee-meeting-washington-dc-2075221">Livestream Captures Moment Reps Hear About Gerry Connolly's Death</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/nancy-mace-shows-nude-photos-house-subcommittee-hearing-2074881">Nancy Mace Shares Nude Photo of Herself During House Hearing</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>
                https://www.newsweek.com/full-list-republicans-voted-against-trump-big-beautiful-bill-2075522</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 07:12:17 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075522</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Sonam Sheth ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ Politics ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T07:12:17-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T07:26:39-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649319/johnson-trump.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="3513" height="2342">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Johnson and Trump ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Associated Press ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ Speaker of the House Mike Johnson, R-La., and President Donald Trump arrive for a House Republican conference meeting, Tuesday, May 20, 2025, at the U.S. Capitol in Washington. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3097/johnson-paints-peachy-gop-mood-over-budget-bill-1747822341.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="49">
                <guid>619566</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2648737/picture-video.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Mike Johnson Paints Peachy GOP Mood Over Budget Bill ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ House Speaker Mike Johnson says his party is in a "good mood" after the president visited Capitol Hill. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ AP ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Elias Rodriguez, DC shooting suspect latest, Israel blames "toxic incitement": live updates ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ Follow Newsweek for live updates after the killing of two Israeli embassy staff. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>Tributes are pouring in for the two Israeli embassy staff shot dead outside an event at the Capital Jewish Museum in Washington, DC, on Wednesday night.</p> <p>Police named the suspect as Elias Rodriguez, 30, from Chicago, and we are learning more about him.</p> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/who-elias-rodriguez-suspect-named-israeli-embassy-staff-killings-2075558" target="_blank">Suspect shouted "free, free Palestine"</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/yaron-lischinsky-sarah-milgram-israeli-embassy-staff-shot-dc-2075591" target="_blank">Victims named as Yaron Lischinsky and Sarah Milgrim</a></li> <li>Pair were couple due to be engaged</li> <li>Israeli minister blames "incitement that has been absolutely toxic"</li> <li>Eyewitnesses say suspect <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/washington-dc-israeli-embassy-shooting-witness-2075565" target="_blank">returned to museum after shooting</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/netanyahu-reacts-after-israeli-embassy-staff-killed-dc-shooting-2075555" target="_blank" title="Netanyahu Reacts After Israeli Embassy Staff Killed in DC Shooting">Netanyahu tightens security for Israeli officials</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/donald-trump-responds-isreali-embassy-shooting-washington-dc-2075553" target="_blank">Trump: "Hatred and Radicalism have no place in the USA."</a></li> </ul> <p><strong>Follow Newsweek for live updates.</strong></p> <p>Information has been trickling out about Elias Rodriguez, the 30-year-old man from Chicago who police named as the suspect in the shooting of two Israeli embassy staff outside D.C.'s Capital Jewish Museum.</p> <p>Here's some of the things to know about him so far:</p> <ul> <li>Rodriguez was a leftist activist with <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/elias-rodriguez-not-member-says-socialist-party-linked-dc-suspect-2075632" target="_blank" title="Elias Rodriguez 'Not a Member' Says Socialist Party Linked to DC Suspect">previous ties to a socialist party</a></li> <li>He shouted "free, free Palestine" as he was arrested</li> <li>A LinkedIn profile bearing his name shows he works in content</li> <li>He has been linked to a 900-word manifesto</li> </ul> <p><strong><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/who-elias-rodriguez-suspect-named-israeli-embassy-staff-killings-2075558" target="_blank">Read more</a>.</strong></p> <p>There are reports in the German media that Yaron Lischinsky is a dual German-Israeli national.</p> <p>Lischinsky references his German connections on his LinkedIn profile, including his membership of the youth forum of the Israeli-German Association.</p> <p>"Having made Aliyah from Germany at the age of 16, I have the privilege of calling both Jerusalem and Nuremberg my home," Lischinsky wrote on his profile.</p> <figure><img src="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649526/pam-bondi-jeanine-pirro.jpg" /><figcaption>Attorney General Pam Bondi, center, and U.S. Attorney for the District of Columbia Jeanine Pirro, second right, walk to cars as law enforcement work the scene after two staff members of the Israeli Embassy in Washington were shot and killed outside the Capital Jewish Museum, Thursday, May 22, 2025, in Washington.<span class="copyright">AP Photo/Rod Lamkey, Jr.</span></figcaption></figure> <p>Images show U.S. Attorney General Pam Bondi and U.S. Attorney for the District of Columbia Jeanine Pirro both at the scene of the shooting on Wednesday night.</p> <p>Bondi spoke to Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu to share condolences and give him more information about the suspect in the shooting, promising to bring him to justice. She also said President Donald Trump was involved in the management of the situation.</p> <p>"Praying for the victims of this violence as we work to learn more," Bondi posted to X.</p> <p>Zineb Riboua, a research fellow with Hudson Institute's Center for Peace and Security in the Middle East, paid tribute to Yaron Lischinsky, who she described as "the finest friend I've ever had, brilliant, kind, and endlessly thoughtful."</p> <p>"A devout Christian and a gifted linguist, he spoke German, Hebrew, and Japanese," Riboua wrote in a post on X.</p> <p>"He was full of curiosity and always brimming with ideas. I don't think we ever had a conversation that didn't leave me inspired to write something new.</p> <p>"He loved America. He was excited about the future, about finally visiting Texas, and about the life he and his beloved fiancée were building together. I was supposed to meet her today.</p> <p>"They are both gone. And the loss is immeasurable. The world has lost two extraordinary souls. And I have lost a dear friend who made every moment brighter."</p> <p>Katie Kalisher, who was at the Capital Jewish Museum event, gave an account of what happened during the shooting and immediately after as she came—unknowingly at first—face to face with the suspect.</p> <p>"Suddenly, we heard some gunshots coming from outside the building. Maybe 10, 15 gunshots," Kalisher told Fox &amp; Friends on Thursday morning.</p> <p>"We didn't really understand what was going on, but there was a man who came in and he's saying like 'call the police' and he's covered in rain and he looks very distressed.</p> <p>"So we're trying to offer him some help. Even one of my friends asks him, 'Are you OK? Can I get you some water?'"</p> <p>The suspect said he would like some water, and Kalisher asked if he liked the museum.</p> <p>"And he's kind of like playing dumb with me. He's like, 'Oh, what kind of museum is this?'" Kalisher said. "I'm like, it's a Jewish museum. And he asks, 'Do you think that's why they did it?' in reference to the gunshots we had heard.</p> <p>"I was like, 'Yeah, maybe. I don't know, but I don't think so. I hope not.'</p> <p>"That's when he reaches into his bag and pulls out a keffiyah and says to me, 'I did it. I did this for Gaza.' And then he starts shouting 'free, free Palestine'."</p> <p>Yoni Kalin was inside the Capital Jewish Museum when the shooting occurred. He gave more details about the nature of the event to The Associated Press.</p> <p>"This event was about humanitarian aid," Kalin said.</p> <p>"How can we actually help both the people in Gaza and the people in Israel? How can we bring together Muslims and Jews and Christians to work together to actually help innocent people?</p> <p>"And then here he is just murdering two people in cold blood."</p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/elias-rodriguez-not-member-says-socialist-party-linked-dc-suspect-2075632">Elias Rodriguez 'Not a Member' Says Socialist Party Linked to DC Suspect</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/who-elias-rodriguez-suspect-named-israeli-embassy-staff-killings-2075558">Who Is Elias Rodriguez? Suspect Named in Israeli Embassy Staff Killings</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>
                https://www.newsweek.com/elias-rodriguez-dc-shooting-suspect-latest-israel-blames-toxic-incitement-live-updates-2075655</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 06:23:49 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075655</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Shane Croucher ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ News ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T06:23:49-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T07:25:30-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content
                url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649428/sara-milgram-yaron-lishinksy.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="2070" height="1380">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Sara Milgram and Yaron Lishinksy ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Embassy of Israel to the USA ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ Sara Milgram and Yaron Lishinksy. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3098/israel-fm-1747909391.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="56">
                <guid>619683</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649511/israeli-fm.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Israeli FM Identifies Victims Killed In Washington DC Shooting ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ Israeli Foreign Minister Gideon Saar identified the victims of a shooting in Washington, DC, on May 22 as Yaron Lischinsky and Sarah Milgrim. Lischinsky was a research assistant, and Milgrim organized visits and missions to Israel. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ AP ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Padres $71 Million Starting Pitcher May Opt Out; Dodgers to Pursue? ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ The San Diego Padres have a strong duo at the top of the rotation, and one former general manager believes one of them could opt out from his contract. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>The San Diego Padres have a strong rotation, but things could change heading into the offseason.</p> <p>Dylan Cease is set to hit the free agent market, and there's a chance Michael King could leave as well.</p> <p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.nytimes.com/athletic/6367630/2025/05/21/mlb-free-agents-2025-2026-offseason-kyle-tucker-alex-bregman/" target="_blank">Baseball insider and former general manager Jim Bowden</a> believes King could become a free agent through a mutual option.</p> <p>"King has vaulted to the top of these starting pitcher rankings simply by outperforming the field," wrote Bowden. "He has posted a sub-3.00 ERA in each of the past four seasons, including last year, when he went 13-9 with a 2.95 ERA over 31 appearances (30 starts). This season, he has a 2.59 ERA over 10 starts with 64 strikeouts and 17 walks."</p> <p>King's ERA ranks 13th among all starting pitchers in baseball, just behind phenom Paul Skenes. His performance has helped keep the Padres in contention for the National League West division title. The Padres entered Thursday 1 1/2 games out of first place.</p> <p>Bowden also mentions one thing that adds to King's value.</p> <p>"That he has only 477 major-league innings on his pitching odometer also increases his value," wrote Bowden. "He has a $15 mutual option for 2026 that's expected to be bought out for $3.75 million."</p> <p>If King hits the market, he will be one of the most highly sought starting pitchers at just 29 years old. With all of the pitching injuries the Los Angeles Dodgers have seen this year, it's expected they will pursue King.</p> <p>Spotrac expects King to sign a four-year deal worth $71 million in the offseason, but the Padres will look to extend him.</p> <p><em><strong>More MLB: </strong><strong><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/mlb/rafael-devers-back-third-base-alex-bregman-likely-opt-out-insider-says-2075412" target="_blank">Rafael Devers Back to Third Base? Alex Bregman 'Likely' to Opt Out, Insider Says</a></strong></em></p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/mlb/no-chance-pirates-superstar-pitcher-gets-traded-team-struggles-2075497">'No Chance' Pirates Superstar Pitcher Gets Traded As Team Struggles</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/mlb/former-phillies-brewers-mariners-all-star-announces-sudden-retirement-mlb-2075505">Former Phillies, Brewers, Mariners All-Star Announces Sudden Retirement From MLB</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/mlb/dodgers-yankees-linked-two-time-all-star-bo-bichette-ahead-offseason-2075428">Dodgers, Yankees Linked to Two-Time All-Star Bo Bichette Ahead of Offseason</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/mlb/three-external-options-replace-jose-alvarado-phillies-bullpen-2075406">Three External Options to Replace Jose Alvarado in Phillies Bullpen</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>
                https://www.newsweek.com/sports/mlb/padres-71-million-starting-pitcher-may-opt-out-dodgers-pursue-2075506</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 07:25:01 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075506</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Drew VonScio ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ MLB ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T07:25:01-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T07:25:01-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content
                url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649340/san-diego-padres-starting-pitcher-michael-king.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="2500" height="1667">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ San Diego Padres, Starting Pitcher, Michael King ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Orlando Ramirez/Getty Images ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ SAN DIEGO, CALIFORNIA - MAY 18: Michael King #34 of the San Diego Padres pitches against the Seattle Mariners during the first inning at Petco Park on May 18, 2025 in San Diego, California. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3080/mlb-2025-predictions-here-1743200245.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="69">
                <guid>616154</guid>
                <media:thumbnail
                    url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2617265/baseball-mlb-2025-opening.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ MLB Expert Predictions for Entire 2025 Season ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ The 2025 MLB season is here at last. Which teams will emerge victorious in each division? What will the playoffs feature? Who will be the award winners at season's end? Here are projections for the complete 2025 season's outcomes. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ various sources ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Trump's "Big, Beautiful Bill" passes house vote: What taxpayers should know ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ President Donald Trump's "Big, Beautiful Bill" cements his economic agenda into law, reshaping tax policy and federal spending. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>President <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/donald-trump">Donald Trump</a>'s sweeping legislative package, dubbed the "Big, Beautiful Bill," has officially passed in the House of Representatives.</p> <p>The vote sets the stage for weeks of debate in the Republican-led <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/senate" data-sys="1">Senate</a>, before the fiscal package can be signed into law.</p> <p>The legislation will modify U.S. tax and spending policies while introducing some new reforms aimed at families and small businesses.</p> <h2>What Is the 'Big, Beautiful Bill'?</h2> <p>The 1,116-page legislation, which Trump described as "the most beautiful piece of policy ever written," bundles tax reforms, budget cuts and immigration enforcement funding.</p> <p>Key provisions include permanent individual tax rate reductions, expanded deductions for small-business owners and an enhanced child tax credit.</p> <p>The legislation also mandates <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/medicaid-changes-get-new-timeline-whos-impacted-2074775" target="_blank">stricter requirements</a> for <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/donald-trump-spending-bill-progress-medicaid-cuts-2073954" target="_blank">Medicaid recipients</a> and introduces new rules that affect <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/donald-trump-mexico-remittance-tax-plan-immigration-2073195" target="_blank">immigrants who complete remittance transfers</a>, or money transfers sent to family or friends in their home country.</p> <p>According to a summary from the U.S. House <a rel="nofollow" href="https://waysandmeans.house.gov/2025/05/12/the-one-big-beautiful-bill-delivers-on-president-trumps-priorities-to-restore-and-expand-trump-era-growth-and-relief-for-families-workers-and-small-businesses/">Committee</a> on Ways and Means, the bill expands "tax relief for middle class and low-income Americans."</p> <h2>Tax Reform</h2> <p>The bill extends Trump's 2017 tax cuts, which were due to expire in 2026, and introduces several new tax code adjustments. The bill prevents a 22 percent tax hike for average taxpayers, as previously reported by<em> <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/donald-trump-spending-bill-chatgpt-2074549" target="_blank">Newsweek</a>. </em></p> <h3>New Tax Deductions</h3> <p>Under the bill, overtime wages, as well as tips for service workers, will not be taxed.</p> <p>Per the Associated Press, the bill includes a temporary boost in the standard deduction: a $1,000 increase for individuals, or bringing it to $16,000 for individual filers, and $2,000 for joint filers, bringing it up to $32,000. The deduction reduces the amount of income that is actually subject to income tax.</p> <p>Further, people purchasing a car can temporarily deduct up to $10,000 in car loan interest payments if they buy an American-made vehicle, under the provision.</p> <p>Small businesses are also eligible to subtract 23 percent of qualifying income from taxes.</p> <h3><span>Child Tax Credit</span></h3> <p>The child tax credit will increase to $2,500 per child and indexes it to inflation. The change is functional through 2028, then reverts to $2,000.</p> <p>Further, children under 8 are eligible for $1,000 in federal contributions for parents to open "Money Accounts for Growth and Investment," or a "MAGA" savings account.</p> <h2>What Is the SALT Deduction Cap?</h2> <p>The state and local tax (SALT) deduction cap permits taxpayers to write off a portion of state and local taxes on their federal returns, per Jackson Hewitt Tax Services.</p> <p>The bill sets the cap on the state and local tax deduction at $40,000. It's a step up from the previously set $10,000 cap. An earlier version of the fiscal bill only raised it to $30,000.</p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/map-shows-where-manufacturing-growing-2075521">Map Shows Where Manufacturing Is Growing</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/trump-giving-very-serious-consideration-major-mortgage-companies-move-2075572">Trump Giving 'Very Serious Consideration' to Major Mortgage Companies Move</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/new-us-iran-nuclear-talks-tensions-rise-2075575">New US-Iran Nuclear Talks as Tensions Rise</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/what-moodys-credit-rating-cut-means-us-economy-2075325">What Credit Rating Cut Means for America's Economy</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>https://www.newsweek.com/tax-cuts-child-credit-big-beautiful-bill-trump-2075472</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 06:58:50 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075472</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Kate Nalepinski ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ Business ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T06:58:50-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T07:21:22-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content
                url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649306/donald-trump-mike-johnson.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="2500" height="1667">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Donald Trump and Mike Johnson ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Francis Chung/POLITICO via AP Images ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ President Donald Trump and House Speaker Mike Johnson speak with reporters after a House Republican Conference meeting at the U.S. Capitol on May 20, 2025. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3098/trumps-tax-and-spending-bill-narrowly-passed-by-the-house-1747912519.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="21">
                <guid>619691</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649568/picture-video.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Trump’s Tax And Spending Bill Narrowly Passes The House ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ President Donald Trump's multitrillion-dollar tax breaks package has narrowly passed the House with a 215-214 vote, and it now goes to the Senate. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ C-SPAN ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Are there really grown men buying out Pokémon in stores? The scalping trend, explained ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ Here's why adults can be seen buying out Pokémon collections in stores on social media. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/toy" target="_blank">Toy</a> scalping—the practice of buying up limited-edition or high-demand toys and reselling them at significantly marked-up prices—has been around for years, but <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/viral" target="_blank">viral</a> posts lately have thrown the people who do it into sharper focus.</p> <p>Scalpers often target limited-edition action figures and collectible <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/lego" target="_blank">Lego</a> sets, as well as franchise-branded toys like <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/star-wars" target="_blank">Star Wars</a>, <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/marvel" target="_blank">Marvel</a> and <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/pokemon" target="_blank">Pokémon</a> which often feature the most rabid fans, thus the highest resale value.</p> <p>In a new viral post on the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/reddit" target="_blank" data-sys="1">Reddit</a> forum r/TikTokCringe, Redditors discussed a <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/TikTokCringe/comments/1kqgtl3/pokemon_scalpers_continue_to_ruin_the_hobby_for/?share_id=_TRWODYF2JsQtp-taZR71&amp;utm_content=1&amp;utm_medium=ios_app&amp;utm_name=ioscss&amp;utm_source=share&amp;utm_term=1" target="_blank">video</a> in which numerous Pokémon scalpers could be seen buying out a <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/stores" target="_blank">store</a>'s Pokémon inventory.</p> <p>"Pokémon scalpers continue to ruin the hobby for actual <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/kids" target="_blank">kids</a>," the title, from user ambachk, read.</p> <p><em><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/" target="_blank">Newsweek</a></em> reached out to users requesting further comment on Wednesday, May 21.</p> <h3>Why People Scalp Pokémon</h3> <p>Pokémon card scalpers often target booster packs in hopes of pulling rare, high-value cards that can fetch hundreds, or even thousands, of dollars on the resale market.</p> <p>These include holographic or full-art cards, limited-run promotional prints and ultra-rare variants, like the Charizard VMAX or Illustrator Pikachu.</p> <p>Pack contents are unpredictable, so scalpers often buy in bulk, banking on the statistical odds of landing chase cards sought after by collectors and <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/competition" target="_blank">competitive</a> players.</p> <p>The potential for a single card to recoup or exceed the cost of multiple packs makes Pokémon sets a prime target in the broader toy and collectibles scalping market.</p> <h3>Redditors React</h3> <p>Many people, however, feel that scalpers are ruining the point of toys—for <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/children" target="_blank">children</a> to play with or collect them.</p> <p>"Watching in horror lest the butt crack of an adult wearing PJ's at a store is revealed while he is desperately scrambling for Pokémon cards is my most dystopian experience to date," one critic wrote in a highly upvoted comment.</p> <p>"These morons are the ones who cause my 8-year-old daughter to ask why people are so greedy," another user commented.</p> <p>"She gets sad the kiosks always say sold out, or Pokémon store shelving is usually empty. When it is in stock, she takes her one or two pack(s) and is happy as can be."</p> <h3>'This ain't it'</h3> <p>A fellow contributor said they used to <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/dating" target="_blank">date</a> "one of these people," adding that the person was, "Obsessed with making <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/money" target="_blank">money</a> and thinking they will get to a point that they're peak <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/happiness" target="_blank">happiness</a> if they make enough monthly off of these cards.</p> <p>"Meanwhile, they <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/work" target="_blank">work</a> eight hours at a <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/jobs" target="_blank">job</a> and spend their free time talking to other scalpers, trying to sell cards for the highest price. They end up not living and making basically no money.</p> <p>"It's fascinating to watch."</p> <p>Multiple Redditors noted how much that <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/lifestyle" target="_blank">lifestyle</a> sounded like a <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/gambling" target="_blank">gambling</a> <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/addiction" target="_blank">addiction</a>.</p> <p>"This is all 'hustle' culture," another person noted.</p> <p>Finally, one pundit pointed out that there's a distinction for adults who still love Pokémon.</p> <p>"Nothing against collecting though, do your thing," they wrote, "But this ain't it."</p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/entertainment/video-games/pokemon-go-finally-adding-remote-shadow-raids-max-battles-2069667">Pokémon Go is Finally Adding Remote Shadow Raids and Max Battles</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/entertainment/video-games/pokemon-scarlet-violet-become-second-best-selling-games-series-2069650">Pokémon Scarlet and Violet Become Second Best-Selling Games in the Series</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/entertainment/video-games/pokemon-tcg-pockets-next-expansion-coming-next-week-focuses-alola-2063603">Pokémon TCG Pocket's Next Expansion is Coming Next Week and Focuses on Alola</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/entertainment/video-games/guide-all-battle-tasks-rewards-pokemon-tcg-pockets-pawmot-event-2056218">Guide: All Battle Tasks and Rewards in Pokémon TCG Pocket's Pawmot Event</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>https://www.newsweek.com/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 07:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075320</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Thomas Westerholm ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ News ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T07:20:00-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T07:20:00-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649064/pokemon.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="2500" height="1626">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Pokemon ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Photo by amilarinos / Getty Images ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ Stock image. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/2994/chappell-roan-1725536239.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="76">
                <guid>598856</guid>
                <media:thumbnail
                    url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2464892/chappell-roan-targets-scalpers-days-after-oasis-furore.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Chappell Roan Targets Scalpers Days After Oasis Furore ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ Chappell Roan has taken to Instagram to say she is targeting scalpers after tickets went on sale for her Tennessee show. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ @chappellroan/Instagram ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ How to honor Memorial Day: respectful observances, do's and don'ts ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ For many, Memorial Day marks the unofficial start of summer, but the day's purpose is far more significant: honoring those who made the ultimate sacrifice. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>Memorial Day, observed annually on the last Monday of May, serves as a solemn time for Americans to remember and honor military personnel who have died in service to the U.S.</p> <p>While backyard barbecues and family gatherings have become part of the long holiday weekend, organizations and veterans' groups remind citizens that specific traditions and etiquette should be followed during the commemoration.</p> <h2>Why It Matters</h2> <p>For many Americans, Memorial Day marks the unofficial start of summer, but the day's original purpose is far more significant: honoring those who made the ultimate sacrifice.</p> <p>Misunderstandings and misplaced gestures, such as wishing others a "Happy Memorial Day" or conflating the observance with Veterans Day, can undermine the day's gravity.</p> <p>As communities nationwide resume gatherings and traditional celebrations, veterans' groups stress the importance of preserving the integrity of Memorial Day's meaning for current and future generations.</p> <h2>What To Know</h2> <p>Memorial Day, originally called Decoration Day, began after the Civil War in 1868 as a time to honor the fallen by placing flowers on their graves and specifically to commemorate those who died defending the country—a tradition that has since expanded to honor all <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/u.s.-military" data-sys="1">U.S. military</a> members lost in service.</p> <p>When respectfully observing and participating in the commemoration of the day, here are some things to consider.</p> <h3>Do:</h3> <ul> <li>Observe the National Moment of Remembrance, which is usually at 3 p.m. local time on Memorial Day, where Americans are encouraged to pause for a minute of silence to honor the fallen.</li> <li>Visit cemeteries or memorials: individuals may honor service members by laying flowers or flags at cemeteries, especially military resting places, where many graves often go undecorated.</li> <li>Wearing red, white and blue, but not using the American flag as decoration: the flag is not meant to be worn as an accessory, so show your patriotism through a red, white and blue color scheme in your outfit.</li> <li>Support veteran organizations: while the day honors the fallen, donating to groups helping living veterans can extend respect and gratitude beyond the holiday.</li> <li>Educate yourself about the day by learning more about the day's history and sharing stories of those who served and died, to help preserve its significance within families and communities.</li> <li>Tune in to the National Memorial Day Concert on Sunday, May 24 at 8 p.m. ET.</li> </ul> <h3>Don't:</h3> <ul> <li>Do not say "Happy Memorial Day:" veterans and organizations caution that the phrase is inappropriate, as the holiday is for somber remembrance, not celebration.</li> <li>Do not thank current troops for their service as Memorial Day honors the fallen and Veterans Day recognizes all veterans. -While thanking the living on this day is well-intentioned, it may conflate the observances.</li> <li>Do not let commercialization overtake meaning: while sales and barbecues are common, some warn against allowing these to eclipse the day's true intent.</li> <li>Do not let politics detract from tribute: differences in views on war or government policies should not interfere with respecting those who died in service.</li> <li>Do not use the flag as clothing.</li> </ul> <p>While it is customary for Americans to gather for picnics, sports, and barbecues, many groups emphasize blending these celebrations with moments of reflection.</p> <p>For example, families can dedicate a table or moment to honor fallen service members before meals or integrate stories and memory-sharing alongside festivities.</p> <h2>What People Are Saying</h2> <p><strong>VA Secretary Doug Collins</strong> said: "Every day throughout the year, VA plays a vital role in remembering and honoring the brave service members who gave their lives in defense of the freedoms America holds dear. This Memorial Day weekend, we invite Americans to visit VA cemeteries and join us in reflecting upon the important legacies of these fallen heroes."</p> <h2>What Happens Next</h2> <p><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/va-memorial-day-ceremonies-full-list-2075128" target="_blank">More than 130 Memorial Day public ceremonies</a> hosted by the Department of Veterans Affairs at VA National cemeteries will be happening across the U.S. between May 23-26, 2025.</p> <p>Regular updates and related veteran benefits news can be found on the VA's website and communications outlets. Be sure to confirm event dates and timings with the VA before attending as listings published here may have changed for reasons including adverse weather conditions.</p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/va-memorial-day-ceremonies-full-list-2075128">VA Memorial Day Ceremonies: List in Full</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/memorial-day-weekend-weather-forecast-map-2075307">Memorial Day Weekend Forecast Maps Show Conditions Across US</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/drowning-lakes-memorial-day-deaths-1911184">Water Deaths Strike on America's Lakes</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/stephen-king-donald-trump-viral-memorial-day-remark-1905669">Stephen King Calls Out Donald Trump Remark</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>https://www.newsweek.com/how-honor-memorial-day-dos-donts-2075614</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 07:18:15 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075614</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Jasmine Laws ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ News ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T07:18:15-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T07:18:15-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649446/va-memorial-day.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="2500" height="1667">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ VA Memorial Day ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Jacquelyn Martin/AP ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ File photo: a member of the Army visits Section 60 of Arlington National Cemetery, in Arlington, Virginia, in 2024 on Memorial Day. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/2949/is-there-mail-on-memorial-day-post-office-open-hours-today-1716802873.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="56">
                <guid>589859</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2398382/usps.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Is There Mail On Memorial Day? Post Office Open Hours Today ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ Monday, May 27, marks Memorial Day, a federal holiday to honor those who died while serving in the United States armed forces. As a federal holiday, many government offices, buildings and businesses—including mail services—will be closed or have different hours of operation in observance. Newsweek has compiled a list of the different mail delivery services impacted by the Memorial Day holiday. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Various Sources ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Greenland signs lucrative minerals deal with Europe in blow to Trump ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ The Arctic territory has issued a 30-year mining permit to a Danish-French consortium. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>Greenland has allowed a Danish-French consortium to mine a rock which is key to the production of aluminum.</p> <p>The permit granted to Greenland Anorthosite Mining (GAM) to extract anorthosite follows interest in the Arctic territory from U.S. President <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/donald-trump" data-sys="1">Donald Trump</a> in acquiring the island.</p> <p>GAM, which is backed by French company Jean Boulle Group and real estate investment firms bodies from Denmark and Greenland, was granted a 30-year permit, Reuters <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/greenland-gives-danish-french-group-permit-mine-rock-with-green-potential-wake-2025-05-21/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">reported</a>.</p> <p><em><span>This is a developing story to be updated with further information. </span></em></p> <p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/map-us-nuclear-base-cold-war-greenland-2072612">Map Shows US Nuclear Base Hidden Under Greenland's Ice Since Cold War</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/trump-administration-eyes-agreement-greenland-know-2070466">Trump Administration Eyes New Agreement With Greenland: What To Know</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/denmark-warns-trump-white-house-greenland-spying-2070030">Denmark Warns Trump White House on Greenland Spying</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/greenland-denmark-trump-spying-2069495">Denmark Summons US Ambassador Over Greenland Spying Reports</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>https://www.newsweek.com/greenland-trump-permit-extraction-2075673</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 07:17:53 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075673</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Brendan Cole ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ World ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T07:17:53-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T07:17:53-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2450666/breaking-news.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="1200" height="800">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Breaking News ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ There have been multiple arrests made in connection with the death of Matthew Perry, including at least one doctor, per TMZ. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3080/vance-greenland-1743181144.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="47">
                <guid>616125</guid>
                <media:thumbnail
                    url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2616905/jd-usha-vance-visit-greenland-space.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ JD And Usha Vance Visit US Military Base In Greenland ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ Vice President JD Vance and Second Lady Usha Vance visited a U.S. Space Force base in Greenland Friday. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Associated Press ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Walmart responds to Trump's order to "eat the tariffs" ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ Walmart has said it will try to keep prices as "low as possible" after the president criticized the company for blaming price hikes on tariffs. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>Walmart has responded to President <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/donald-trump" data-sys="1">Donald Trump</a>'s suggestion that the company should fully absorb any cost rises that arise because of his tariffs.</p> <p>In a statement to <em>USA Today</em>, <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/walmart" target="_blank">Walmart</a> spokesperson Joe Pennington said: "We have always worked to keep our prices as low as possible and we won't stop. We'll keep prices as low as we can for as long as we can given the reality of small retail margins."</p> <p>The recent exchange between the president and America's largest private sector employer began when Walmart said it would <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/walmart-raise-prices-within-weeks-2072677" target="_blank">need to raise prices</a> in order to cope with the cost increases brought about by Trump's trade policies.</p> <p>Trump criticized the company for "blaming" his trade policies, and said Walmart should be able to "<a href="https://www.newsweek.com/donald-trump-issues-new-warning-message-walmart-2073638" target="_blank">EAT THE TARIFFS</a>," rather than increase prices for customers.</p> <p>Walmart referred <em>Newsweek</em> to its <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/donald-trump-issues-new-warning-message-walmart-2073638" target="_blank">previous comments provided on the issue</a>.</p> <h2><strong>Why It Matters</strong></h2> <p>Despite the recent pause on the tariffs exchanged between the U.S. and China, retailers have warned that the high rates still in place will have a material impact on their operations, resulting in higher costs that they argue will need to be passed onto consumers.</p> <p>However, the administration has maintained that foreign nation's producers will absorb any tariff-related costs, while <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/white-house-slams-amazon-tariffs-move-hostile-political-2065587" target="_blank">criticizing companies</a> for price increases and attributing these to the trade policies.</p> <h2><strong>What To Know</strong></h2> <p>The recent exchange between the president and America's largest private employer began when Walmart said it would <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/walmart-raise-prices-within-weeks-2072677" target="_blank">need to raise prices</a> in order to cope with the administration's trade policies.</p> <p>Upon releasing its first-quarter earnings—which revealed a 2.5-percent year-on-year increase in revenue to $165.6 billion—Walmart warned that its future results could be affected by a number of factors, including foreign currency fluctuations, changes in global economic and geopolitical circumstances, as well as "tariffs and trade policies."</p> <p>In a subsequent earnings call, CEO Doug McMillon thanked the president and treasury secretary for making "progress" on the trade negotiations, referencing the recent announcement by the U.S. and China of a <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/us-china-deal-did-trump-lose-trade-war-2071407" target="_blank">temporary reduction in tariffs</a>. For 90 days as of May 12, tariffs on Chinese imports will drop to 30 percent from 145 percent, with China dropping its rate on American goods to 10 percent from 125 percent.</p> <p>However, McMillon added: "We will do our best to keep our prices as low as possible but given the magnitude of the tariffs, even at the reduced levels announced this week, we aren't able to absorb all the pressure given the reality of narrow retail margins."</p> <p>In an interview with CNBC, Chief Financial Officer John David Rainey similarly said that tariff rates were "still too high" despite the reductions, adding that while Walmart is "wired for everyday low prices...the magnitude of these increases is more than any retailer can absorb."</p> <p>On Saturday, Trump took to Truth Social to respond to Walmart's warnings and criticized the the company for "blaming" tariffs. "Walmart made BILLIONS OF DOLLARS last year, far more than expected," said Trump. "Between Walmart and China they should, as is said, '<a href="https://www.newsweek.com/donald-trump-issues-new-warning-message-walmart-2073638" target="_blank">EAT THE TARIFFS</a>,' and not charge valued customers ANYTHING."</p> <h2><strong>What People Are Saying</strong></h2> <p><strong>White House Press Secretary Karoline Leavitt</strong>, in response to a reporter's question on Walmart's warnings, said: "Well, first of all, the CEO of Walmart made those comments about the tariffs on an earnings call, where CEOs, I believe, are legally obligated to give the most dire warnings and forecasts to their investors and stakeholders. The reality is, as the president has always maintained, Chinese producers will be absorbing the cost of these tariffs, and that is why China was so quick to hustle to the negotiating table with the United States of America. They need our markets. They need our consumers."</p> <p><strong>Republican Senator Bill Hagerty</strong> said that Walmart's anticipation of price increases "assumes that tariffs all go up" during an appearance on CNBC's Squawk Box.</p> <p>"To the extent that there is an increase, you've got the producer, you've got the shipper, you've got the middleman—the retailer—and you've got the consumer. All of them may bear some of that," he said.</p> <p>Hagerty added that Walmart "has the broadest base of American clients there is. And I think they're going to be very careful about how they do this. I know that they've received some criticism from the president—I think they need to think hard."</p> <p><strong>Walmart CFO John David Rainey</strong> told CNBC that retailers would determine price increases based on a product's "elasticity of demand," and an evaluation of the price points at which these can still be sold. However, he said that doing so could lead to price hikes even for items that are not themselves subject to tariffs.</p> <p>"We've not seen a period where you've had prices go up this high this quickly," he added. "We're well equipped and experienced in dealing with elasticities or price increases that are going up two or three percent, but not 30 percent. So understanding, by category and by item, what the demand is going to be is really important to making sure that you have the right amount of inventory in the right places at the right time."</p> <h2><strong>What Happens Next</strong></h2> <p>Despite its concern over the cost impacts of tariffs, Walmart has maintained its full-year outlook, which forecasts net sales of $674.5 billion, up from $643 billion, alongside $29.5 billion in operating income.</p> <p>Walmart CFO Rainey <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/15/walmart-price-increases-trump-tariffs.html" target="_blank">told CNBC</a> that shoppers will likely feel the impact of the tariff-related price hikes toward the end of May and in June.</p> <p><em>Update 05/22/25, 6:48 a.m. ET: This article was updated with a response from Walmart.</em></p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/donald-trump-issues-new-warning-message-walmart-2073638">Donald Trump Issues New Warning Message to Walmart</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/nationwide-walmart-boycott-may-20-2070281">Nationwide Walmart Boycott Planned for May 20: What to Know</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/former-ceo-issues-warning-walmart-raising-prices-2073103">Former CEO Issues Warning Over Walmart Raising Prices</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/walmart-raise-prices-within-weeks-2072677">Walmart to Raise Prices Within Weeks</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>
                https://www.newsweek.com/walmart-responds-donald-trump-eat-tariffs-trade-policy-2075063</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 03:34:16 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075063</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Hugh Cameron ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ News ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-21T03:34:16-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T07:15:55-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2648620/walmart.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="3911" height="2824">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ walmart ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Justin Sullivan/Getty Images ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ Customers enter a Walmart store on April 09, 2025 in San Leandro, California. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3097/walmart-1747667548.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="57">
                <guid>619401</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2647304/picture-video.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ White House Pushes Back On Walmart Plan To Raise Prices Because Of Trump's Tariffs ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ Walmart has warned that it plans to raise prices on some products in the wake of Donald Trump's tariffs. White House Press Secretary Karoline Leavitt instead that Chinese producers "will absorb the cost of these tariffs" instead of American consumers. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ C-SPAN ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Russian 'spy factory' in Brazil exposed: what we know ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ Brazilian counterintelligence agents unmasked at least nine operatives living in the country for years under false identities. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>A Russian "spy factory" operating out of Brazil has been dismantled by counterintelligence agents who unmasked at least nine operatives living in the country for years under false identities&mdash;using it as a launchpad to train novice spies who would then infiltrate the West and elsewhere.</p><p>A team of federal agents from Brazil has been covertly unraveling the Russian spy ring, which used the country as an "assembly line for deep-cover operatives," according to a <em>New York Times</em> investigation published on Wednesday.</p><p><em>Newsweek</em> has contacted the Russian Foreign Ministry for comment by email.</p><h2><strong>Why It Matters</strong></h2><p>Agentstvo, an independent investigative Russian news outlet, described the expos&eacute; on Thursday as "<a href="https://twitter.com/agents_media/status/1925220802976256281" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">one of the biggest failures of the Russian intelligence services</a>" comparable to when a network of 11 spies was exposed in the U.S. 15 years ago.</p><p>Brazilian counterintelligence agents uncovered at least nine Russian officers operating under cover identities over the past three years. Six of them had never been publicly identified until now, the<em> Times</em> reported.</p><h2><strong>What To Know</strong></h2><p>The unmasking began in April 2022, weeks into Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine, when the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/cia" data-sys="1">CIA</a> alerted Brazil's Federal Police to Victor Muller Ferreira, real name, Sergey Cherkasov. He had just landed an internship at the International Criminal Court in The Hague as it was about to start investigating Russia for war crimes in Ukraine.</p><p>Cherkasov, who was admitted to Johns Hopkins University's graduate school in Washington, D.C., in 2018, is currently serving a five-year prison term in Brazil for document forgery. Authorities say that Cherkasov, who spent nearly a decade building a fake identity as his alias Ferreira, is a spy for the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/russian-military">Russian military</a> intelligence agency, GRU.</p><p>He had spent seven to eight years in Brazil building up his cover identity, but when he arrived in the Netherlands, Dutch authorities denied him entry and sent him back to S&atilde;o Paulo.</p><p>His Brazilian passport and other identifying documents checked out, but when police found his birth certificate his story and Russia's operation in Brazil began to fall apart.</p><p>The certificate stated that he was born in 1989 in Rio de Janeiro to a Brazilian mother, a real woman who died in 1993. But when agents tracked down her family, they learned she never had a child. Authorities couldn't find anyone who matched the name listed as his father on the document.</p><p>Intelligence agents then began looking for other so-called "ghosts" in Brazil under an investigation dubbed Operation East.</p><p>"Everything started with Sergey," a senior Brazilian official told the publication.</p><p>Intelligence experts assessed that perhaps Russian authorities ordered many of the suspected spies named in the investigation home as the world shifted its focus on Russia after President <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/vladimir-putin" data-sys="1">Vladimir Putin</a> launched his full-scale invasion of Ukraine.</p><p>Only Cherkasov was prosecuted and sentenced in Brazil.</p><p>Some of the others are thought to have been recalled to Russia<span> before they had perfected their cover identities.</span></p><p><span>Agentstvo reported Thursday that Russian spy Olga Tyutereva, for example, has since returned to Russia and is using her real name and working as a teacher in the Magadan region.</span></p><p>Agentstvo said it found digital traces in Russia of three more spies from the list published in the <em>Times</em>.</p><p>An <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/fbi">FBI</a> affidavit states that in his two years in Washington, Cherkasov filed reports to the GRU on how senior Biden administration officials were responding to the build-up of Russia's military near the Ukrainian border before Putin invaded Ukraine in February 2022.</p><h2><strong>Why Brazil?</strong></h2><p>Jane Bradley, co-author of the <em>Times</em> investigation, told NPR that Brazil has a "very multicultural, diverse population" and so "it's easy for anyone to blend in."</p><p>"The second thing is that Brazilian passports are, you know, one of the most useful and powerful passports in the world. It gets you into a lot of countries without a visa, so it's a very powerful, useful passport to have."</p><p>"And then the other point is more interesting and more complex, which is the Brazilian ID system. How you obtain birth certificates basically has an exemption&mdash;a loophole, if you like&mdash;that makes it easier to apply for a birth certificate than most other countries elsewhere," she added.</p><h2><strong>What Happens Next</strong></h2><p>The spies are unlikely to work abroad again with their covers blown, the<em> Times</em> reported.</p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/russia-gru-ukraine-nscs-2075658">Russian Intelligence Attack on NATO 'Logistics and Technology' Exposed</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/marco-rubio-putin-war-criminal-2075570">Marco Rubio Refuses To Call Putin 'War Criminal', After Grilling Rex Tillerson</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/us-russia-malaysia-news-military-air-navy-show-2075536">US and Russia Flex Military Muscles on Same Stage</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/nato-drills-finland-russia-uk-sweden-donald-trump-2075253">NATO Shows Force on Northern Flank with Russia as US Pulls Back</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>https://www.newsweek.com/russian-spy-factory-brazil-exposed-2075619</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 07:15:21 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075619</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Isabel van Brugen ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ World ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T07:15:21-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T07:15:21-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content
                url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649455/russian-president-vladimir-putin.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="3883" height="2589">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Russian President Vladimir Putin ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ GAVRIIL GRIGOROV/POOL/AFP/Getty Images ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ In this pool photograph distributed by Russia's state agency Sputnik, Russian President Vladimir Putin gives an interview to TV host and Director General of Rossiya Segodnya (RIA Novosti) news agency Dmitry Kiselyov (not pictured) at the Kremlin in Moscow on March 12, 2024. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3098/putin-war-crimes-1-1747857386.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="46">
                <guid>619648</guid>
                <media:thumbnail
                    url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649254/democrat-confronts-rubio-putin-war.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Democrat Confronts Rubio: Is Putin A 'War Criminal?' ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ Democratic Rep. Bill Keating confronted Secretary of State Marco Rubio over the Russia-Ukraine War during a Wednesday hearing. "Vladimir Putin, is he a war criminal?" ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ House of Representatives ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Elon Musk reacts to article about his "decline and fall" ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ Musk called The Atlantic, which published a story about his time with the Trump administration, "a zombie publication." ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>Elon Musk has lashed out at <em>The Atlantic's</em> leadership after the magazine published a piece outlining his <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/05/elon-musk-doge-opponents-dc/682866/" target="_blank">"decline and fall"</a>.</p><p>The tech CEO, who has stepped away from his public-facing role in President <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/donald-trump" data-sys="1">Donald Trump</a>'s administration in recent weeks, branded <em>The Atlantic</em> as a "zombie publication" that was "fading into obscurity."</p><p><em>Newsweek</em> has contacted <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/elon-musk" data-sys="1">Elon Musk</a> through the X press office via email as well as <em>The Atlantic </em>via its press office.</p><h2>Why It Matters</h2><p>Elon Musk has been the defining figure of the second Trump administration, leading the charge on several of the president's policies so far, such as the dismantling of USAID and <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/laid-off-federal-workers-face-challenging-job-prospects-2055695" target="_blank">suspension of federal employees.</a> However, amid mounting public opposition and a disastrous judicial election in Wisconsin, Musk has reprioritized his time away from government work, saying that he has <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/elon-musk-cut-back-political-spending-ive-done-enough-2074715" target="_blank">"done enough"</a> in politics.</p><h2>What To Know</h2><p>On Wednesday, <em>The Atlantic </em>published an article titled "The Decline and Fall of Elon Musk," which detailed a series of clashes between Musk and other members of Trump's inner circle that led to him getting frozen out of cabinet.</p><p>Musk clashed with Treasury Secretary <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/scott-bessent" data-sys="1">Scott Bessent</a> over management of the IRS, Secretary of State <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/marco-rubio" data-sys="1">Marco Rubio</a> over the abolition of USAID, and the president himself over his intervention in Wisconsin's <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/supreme-court" data-sys="1">Supreme Court</a> election in April, according to the report.</p><p>The article says the arguments culminated in an Oval Office meeting in which Musk was "ambushed" by other cabinet members. This coincided with the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/elon-musk-slams-massive-violence-against-tesla-ive-not-harmed-anyone-2074678" target="_blank">height of anti-Tesla protests</a> across the Western world.</p><p>Musk derided the report on social media, writing on his platform X that <em>The Atlantic</em> was "the past, the legacy media fading into obscurity."</p><p>He also branded the outlet as "a zombie publication kept on life support by Laurene," in reference to Laurene Powell Jobs, Steve Jobs' widow as well as founder and president of Emerson Collective, which owns <em>The Atlantic</em>.</p><p>"Steve would be very disappointed," added Musk.</p><h2>What People Are Saying</h2><p><strong>Speaking at a video conference in Qatar, when asked about his political donations and campaigning, Elon Musk said:</strong> "I'm going to do a lot less in the future. I think I've done enough."</p><p>"If I see a reason to do political spending in the future, I will do it. I do not currently see a reason."</p><p><strong>Musk responded to the account named FischerKing, who wrote:</strong> "It was possible 30 years ago to create a narrative with headlines like this. It doesn't work now. Elon is going to be fine, isn't in any sort of decline. But the journalists at places like the Atlantic don't get that this doesn't work any longer. They're stuck in a time warp."</p><p>"They are the past, the legacy media fading into obscurity," replied Musk.</p><h2>What Happens Next</h2><p>Musk has said that he will focusing more on his tech companies, most notably <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/tesla-spacex-elon-musk-popularity-2074639" target="_blank">SpaceX and Tesla</a>, and will participate less in politics in the future.</p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/trump-administration-seeks-supreme-court-shield-doge-2075298">Trump Administration Seeks Supreme Court Shield for DOGE</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/elon-musk-attending-trump-ramaphosa-meeting-white-house-2075234">Elon Musk Attending Trump, Ramaphosa Meeting at White House</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/elon-musk-cut-back-political-spending-ive-done-enough-2074715">Elon Musk to Cut Back Political Spending: 'I've Done Enough'</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/tesla-spacex-elon-musk-popularity-2074639">Tesla and SpaceX Reputations Plummet in Major Poll</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>https://www.newsweek.com/elon-musk-reacts-article-decline-fall-2075577</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 07:10:37 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075577</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Theo Burman ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ News ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T07:10:37-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T07:10:37-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649454/elon-musk.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="2500" height="1666">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Elon Musk ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Getty Images ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ Elon Musk in the Oval Office at the White House on May 21, 2025 in Washington, DC. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3079/cspan-status-1904617345160532395-1-1742935471.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="56">
                <guid>615844</guid>
                <media:thumbnail
                    url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2614601/donald-trump-defends-signal-app-amid-war.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Donald Trump Defends Signal App Amid War Texts Backlash ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ President Donald Trump said that his top national security officials discussing war plans in a Signal text group that included a journalist was "the best technology for the moment." ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ CSPAN ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Ukraine orders evacuations amid Russian troops build-up near border ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ Russian president Vladimir Putin has been briefed on a Moscow move to capture the Ukrainian region of Sumy, next to the frontier. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>Vladimir Putin's forces are massing next to Russia's border with Ukraine's Sumy oblast, it has been reported, following evacuations from the region and a threat that Moscow has identified further territorial targets in its full-scale invasion.</p><p>Sumy governor Oleh Hryhorov said thousands had been evacuated from the region on Ukraine's northeast border and next to the Kharkiv oblast, according to the <em>Kyiv Independent</em>. On the other side of the frontier Russian troops numbers are said to be increasing.</p><p>It comes Putin is trying to justify the renewal of Russian plans to seize Sumy City&mdash;16 miles from the border&mdash;and illegally annex the whole of Sumy Oblast, according to the Institute for the Study of War.</p><p>However, Ukrainian lawmaker Oleksiy Goncharenko told <em>Newsweek</em> that the city of Sumy would be too big for Russian forces to capture.</p><p><em>Newsweek</em> has contacted the Russian defense ministry for comment.</p><h2>Why It Matters</h2><p>An increased Russian troop presence on the other side of Ukraine's north east border signals that Putin is not scaling down his aggression, despite weeks of U.S.-led negotiations.</p><p>Now Ukraine's Sumy and Kharkiv regions have been mentioned as being in Putin's crosshairs, according to reports, and the troop build-up shows intent to occupy more territory regardless of ceasefire demands.</p><h2>What To Know</h2><p>Hryhorov told Ukrainian outlet Suspilne, cited by the Kyiv Independent, that 56,000 residents had been evacuated from their homes in Sumy which has faced a spike in Russian drone attacks and aerial bombs in recent months.</p><p>Last September, children and their parents were evacuated from a six-mile zone bordering Russia and additional evacuations were ordered this week after an attack on a civilian bus in Bilopillia, on May 17, which killed nine people, including all the members of one family.</p><p>Now Russian troops <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.msn.com/en-us/news/world/russia-building-up-troops-near-border-with-kharkiv-oblast-ukrainian-forces-say/ar-AA1FcGID?ocid=BingNewsSerp" target="_blank">are massin</a>g on the other side of the border of the neighboring region of Kharkiv, which may indicate plans for a new assault, according to the 13th Khartiia Brigade of the National Guard of Ukraine.</p><p>It follows reports that, during a meeting with Ukrainian officials in Istanbul last week which Putin refused to attend, a Russian delegation threatened to seize the Kharkiv and Sumy regions.</p><p>Moscow said it would only agree to a ceasefire pushed by the Trump administration if Ukraine withdrew its forces from the four regions Russia claims to have annexed but does not fully control&mdash;Luhansk, Donetsk, Kherson, and Zaporizhzhia.</p><p>Oleksiy Goncharenko wrote on Telegram how Russia has started talking about the Sumy region, seeking the creation of a security zone and threatening to annex the region.</p><p>However, Goncharenko, member of the Ukrainian delegation to the Parliamentary Assembly of the Council of Europe (PACE), told <em>Newsweek</em> on Thursday that the only big city Russia managed to take so far in its full-scale invasion was Mariupol which was surrounded completely and "so it was very specific situation."</p><p>He said he did not believe Russia can take Sumy City itself but they could approach Sumy region and try to seize surrounding territories although the Ukrainian military is developing its plans "and they know what to do."</p><p>During a meeting with Kursk regional officials on Thursday, Putin was asked by a district head to create a buffer zone in Sumy region and claimed Moscow should seize Sumy City and that Russia should be bigger.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/isw" data-sys="1">ISW</a> said this meeting was orchestrated to justify Russia's claims on more territory within Ukraine, although the Washington, D.C. think tank said that Moscow's forces are highly unlikely to be able to seize Sumy City in the short to medium-term given its inability to capture much smaller settlements over the last three years.</p><h2>What People Are Saying</h2><p><strong>Andrii Pomahaibus, chief of staff of the 13th Khartiia Brigade of the National Guard of Ukraine to Ukrainian media:</strong> "The enemy is trying to pull its personnel closer to the front line and conduct at least some assault operations (toward Kharkiv)."</p><p><strong>Institute for the Study of War, Thursday:</strong> "Putin likely orchestrated a meeting with Kursk Oblast officials on May 20 to set conditions to justify the renewal of Russian plans to seize Sumy City and illegally annex Sumy Oblast."</p><h2>What Happens Next</h2><p>Russia's troop build-up by Ukraine is likely to continue with Moscow's territorial aims beyond the oblasts that Russia has already illegally occupied or annexed, the ISW said. It added that Putin may try to leverage further advances in Sumy Oblast to demand that Ukraine cede part of it to Moscow during future peace negotiations.</p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/russia-gru-ukraine-nscs-2075658">Russian Intelligence Attack on NATO 'Logistics and Technology' Exposed</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/russia-ukraine-trump-putin-zelensky-promises-2075085">Donald Trump Gives Up on One of His Major Promises</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/trump-russia-invasion-ukraine-illegal-g7-2075113">Trump Admin Resists Branding Russia's Invasion of Ukraine 'Illegal': Report</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/putin-aide-trump-putin-call-2074702">Putin's Aide Reveals New Details About Donald Trump Call</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>https://www.newsweek.com/russia-ukraine-sumy-evacuations-2075563</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 07:05:04 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075563</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Brendan Cole ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ World ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T07:05:04-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T07:05:04-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649395/sumy-ukraine.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="2500" height="1667">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Sumy, Ukraine ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ ROMAN PILIPEY/Getty Images ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ This image from April 13, 2025 shows a Ukrainian rescuer at the site of a missile attack in Sumy, northeastern Ukraine. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3097/putin-kursk-1747820220.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="42">
                <guid>619565</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2648715/vladimir-putin.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Vladimir Putin Seen Making Rare Visit To Kursk Region ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ Russian President Vladimir Putin has visited the Kursk region for the first time since Russia said it expelled Ukrainian forces from the area in April. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ AP ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Plane passenger's 7-hour "particularly stinky" revenge on woman who demanded aisle seat applauded ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ Passenger weaponizes gas in petty revenge after being denied aisle seat access. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>A plane passenger's "particularly stinky" revenge on a fellow traveler who stole their aisle seat has sparked laughter across the internet.</p> <p>The 33-year-old passenger and original poster (OP), user littleredbird1991, took to <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/pettyrevenge/comments/1krhl8v/steal_my_seat_how_about_a_crop_dusting/?share_id=9s1YFJruu1NuBisY9GAAK&amp;utm_content=1&amp;utm_medium=ios_app&amp;utm_name=ioscss&amp;utm_source=share&amp;utm_term=1" target="_blank">Reddit</a> to recount the incident, which took place on a seven-hour cross-country <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/southwest-airlines">Southwest Airlines</a> flight.</p> <p>After boarding as part of group B, the OP headed towards the back of the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/plane">plane</a> to secure an aisle seat.</p> <p>However, trouble began when a late-boarding passenger, referred to as "Entitled Karen" or EK, arrived and demanded the aisle seat, claiming she had paid for it despite Southwest's open seating policy.</p> <p>EK's aggressive <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/behavior">behavior</a> escalated quickly. She insisted the OP was in her rightful seat and began shouting, and although the OP tried to explain the seating rules, the woman refused to listen and then took the aisle seat without permission.</p> <p>"Now, I may be passive, but I also am petty," the OP wrote. "I am also really gassy on <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/airplanes">airplanes</a>.</p> <p>"Normally, I try to contain it and go to the restroom when it gets bad enough and just let it rip there. But I was p***** at EK and, frankly, p***** at everyone else on the plane for letting her get away with it.</p> <p>"So I decided that I was just going to let 'er rip all 7 hours of the flight. I put on my headphones (over the ear) and started passing gas about 1 hour into the flight. And lucky for me (and unlucky for everyone else), they were particularly stinky."</p> <p>She continued, "Every time I would toot, she would sniff, smell it, then shoot dirty looks at me. I just ignored her and just kept listening to my <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/music">music</a> and <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/reading">reading</a> my Kindle.</p> <p>"At about hour 5, she had had enough and hit the call button to ask to move. The <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/flight-attendant">flight attendant</a> told her we were fully booked and there was nowhere to move her to.</p> <p>"EK looked even more pissed but I guess she had seen enough of the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/internet">internet</a> to know if she threw a fit she would get arrested when we landed.</p> <p>"When we did land (since we were near the back), I gave it one more silent but deadly toot to seal the deal and let her bathe in my stink for a couple more minutes."</p> <h3>'You are my absolute hero'</h3> <p>Redditors flocked to the comments to applaud the OP, though one admitted, "I was REALLY hoping to read that you passed the gas in her face when you went to take your seat!"</p> <p>Another quipped, "Give Karen a touch of pinkeye to remember you by."</p> <p>"Honestly, I'd admit it. 'Told you I needed the aisle seat, I go to the restroom all the time when on a flight'," one Redditor wrote.</p> <p>"You are my absolute hero. Well done!!" added another. "Not only did you give the nasty Karen her due, you reminded others nearby of the importance of speaking up when it matters."</p> <h3>Frequent Flyer Frustrations</h3> <p>Airline seat disputes have become a common subject online, and platforms like <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/reddit" target="_blank">Reddit</a> and <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/tiktok" data-sys="1">TikTok</a> regularly feature complaints from passengers caught in awkward swap requests or facing pressure from flight attendants or fellow travelers.</p> <p>A June 2023 study from Kayak found that passengers believe "you are allowed to ask to switch seats if you ask politely" because 54% of travelers "have a soft spot for common courtesy".</p> <p>A previous article in <em><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/passenger-refusing-seat-swap-plane-etiquette-viral-reddit-2047991" target="_blank">Newsweek</a></em> covered a similar dispute in which a plane passenger "finally said no" and refused to switch seats to help a couple sit together.</p> <p>Another <em><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/passenger-switches-seats-child-tantrum-flight-2075310" target="_blank">Newsweek</a></em> story detailed an incident where a plane passenger was backed for requesting to change their seat mid-flight after being seated next to a special needs child who threw an hours-long tantrum.</p> <p><em>Newsweek</em> has contacted littleredbird1991 for comment via <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/reddit" target="_blank">Reddit</a>.</p> <p><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/wsid" target="_blank"><em>Newsweek</em>'s "What Should I Do?"</a> offers expert advice to readers. If you have a personal dilemma, let us know via <a href="mailto:life@newsweek.com" target="_blank">life@newsweek.com</a>. We can ask experts for advice on relationships, family, friends, money and work, and your story could be featured on WSID at <em>Newsweek.</em></p> <p>To read how <em>Newsweek</em> uses AI as a newsroom tool, click <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/editorial-guidelines" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><p> <strong>Related Articles</strong> <ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/passenger-horrified-flight-attendant-reaction-2074761">Woman Tries To Order Drink on Flight—Makes Horrifying Error: 'Humiliation'</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/gen-z-plane-passenger-refusing-give-window-seat-kid-2074651">Gen Z Woman Refusing To Give Up Window Seat on Plane for Kid Backed</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/passenger-switches-seats-child-tantrum-flight-2075310">Passenger Seated Near Screaming Kid on Flight—Makes Controversial Choice</a></li></ul> </p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>https://www.newsweek.com/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 07:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075348</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Matthew Impelli ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ Life ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T07:05:00-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T07:05:00-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content
                url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649016/plane-passenger-hands-covering-face.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="2500" height="1662">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Plane passenger with hands covering face. ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Getty ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ Stock image: Passenger on a plane appearing frustrated with hands over his face. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3097/passenger-mortified-by-unexpected-interaction-on-plane-1747761613.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="14">
                <guid>619511</guid>
                <media:thumbnail
                    url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2648193/passenger-mortified-unexpected-interaction-plane.png" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Passenger Mortified By Unexpected Interaction On Plane ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ “I knew immediately after this happened that this situation would be relatable to others,” the passenger told Newsweek. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ @luciebfink/TikTok ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Panama puts focus on nature's role in solving the climate crisis ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ Forests, oceans and other ecosystems play a vital part in pulling CO2 from the air. But new research shows climate change is threatening those natural systems. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>Panama's Environment Minister Juan Carlos Navarro describes himself as "a retired politician." But after a long political career, including two terms as mayor of Panama City, old habits die hard. When describing his country's economics, Navarro drew on a political adage coined by campaign strategist James Carville.</p> <p>"To paraphrase Carville, it's about nature, stupid," Navarro told <em>Newsweek</em>.</p> <p>Carville's catchphrase was about the central importance of the economy, of course, but Navarro's twist emphasizes that economic activity, in turn, depends on nature.</p> <p>As evidence, Navarro pointed to the Panama Canal, not far from the summit's venue, and the many rivers and streams that feed into it.</p> <p>"From that same watershed comes all of the water to drive the canal that permits safe passage for 6 percent of global commerce," he said. "And this is the backbone of the Panamanian economy."</p> <p>Panama is hosting a four-day <a rel="nofollow" href="https://naturesummit.org/" target="_blank">Nature Summit </a>this week to highlight those connections between the environment, economy and climate change. The summit takes place in concert with a Global Climate Week in Panama, organized by the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/united-nations" data-sys="1">United Nations</a>.</p> <p>In November, the 30th annual U.N. conference of the parties (COP30) climate talks will take place in Belem, Brazil. That will be the first U.N. climate talks held in the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/amazon" data-sys="1">Amazon</a>, a natural venue to highlight <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/razan-al-mubarak-thinks-key-climate-solution-right-front-usits-nature-1838221" target="_blank">nature-based solutions to climate change</a>, and Navarro said the Panamanian summit is meant to set the stage.</p> <p>"We're holding the nature summit precisely to be able to come up with ideas that can be used as input in the upcoming COP30 in Belem," Navarro said.</p> <p>The summit brought together leaders from businesses, governments, philanthropies and indigenous communities to come up with specific ways to support and pay for conservation programs that help to capture carbon.</p> <p>Oceans, forests and other ecosystems draw down carbon dioxide from the atmosphere, making <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/cop28-looks-nature-help-against-climate-change-1851865" target="_blank">nature conservation a vital part </a>of meeting international climate targets. But the connection between climate change and nature works in the other direction as well. Climate change stresses ecosystems in ways that threaten wildlife and the wide range of services we depend on from nature, including fisheries, forest products and clean water.</p> <p>In his remarks Tuesday at the Nature Summit, U.N. Climate Change Executive Secretary Simon Stiell linked climate change to the prolonged drought affecting the Panama Canal.</p> <p>"Climate change has already driven water levels lower, slowing shipping and disrupting trade routes," Stiell said. "The same droughts that plague the canal are affecting essential commodities worldwide, reducing harvests, emptying shelves, and pushing families into hunger."</p> <p>Two reports just out this week show the profound threat climate change poses to natural systems and the urgent need to conserve them. - want to make sure you're OK with that.</p> <p>A study <a rel="nofollow" href="https://academic.oup.com/bioscience/advance-article/doi/10.1093/biosci/biaf059/8127685?login=false" target="_blank">published Tuesday in the journal <em>BioScience</em></a> found that more than 3,500 animal species are threatened by impacts from climate change. Until recently, the study's authors said, the main causes of biodiversity loss have been habitat loss and overexploitation by people.</p> <p>"But as climate change intensifies, we expect it to become a third major threat to the Earth's animals," lead author William Ripple, a professor of ecology at Oregon State University, wrote. "Rapid and effective climate mitigation is crucial now more than ever for saving the world's biodiversity."</p> <p>A <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.wri.org/news/release-global-forest-loss-shatters-records-2024-fueled-massive-fires" target="_blank">report released on Wednesday</a> by researchers at the University of Maryland and the nonprofit group World Resources Institute found that the global loss of forests has reached a record high.</p> <p>About 17 million acres of tropical primary forests were lost in 2024, according to the report, nearly double the amount lost in 2023. And the researchers said that for the first time in their records the primary cause of forest loss is not deforestation due to agriculture, but rather, loss from wildfires.</p> <p>Heat and drought due to climate change can make conditions ripe for large and intense wildfires and, in turn, the fires release much of the carbon stored in forests into the atmosphere.</p> <p>"If this trend continues, it could permanently transform critical natural areas and unleash large amounts of carbon — intensifying climate change and fueling even more extreme fires," Peter Potapov, co-director of the Global Land Analysis and Discovery Lab at the University of Maryland, said in a statement. "This is a dangerous feedback loop we cannot afford to trigger further."</p> <p>The report's authors say that in order to meet global goals for forest protection the world must reduce deforestation by 20 percent every year through stronger fire prevention, better enforcement of trade regulations and more funding for forest protection.</p> <p>In an ironic twist for the nature summit, the total area of tropical forests lost last year roughly equals the size of Panama.</p> <figure><img src="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649309/juan-carlos-navarro-panama.jpg" /><figcaption>Juan Carlos Navarro during his Panamanian presidential campaign in 2014. Now Panama's Environment Minister, Navarro emphasizes the importance of nature to the country's economy and the effort to rein in climate change.<span class="copyright">Rodrigo Arangua/AFP via Getty Images</span></figcaption></figure> <p>Environment Minister Navarro said it is critical to ensure that protected areas are actually protected on the ground.</p> <p>"Panama is leading the charge globally to demonstrate that we can turn paper national parks and reserves into real protected areas and national parks," he said, and he described an increase in staffing at parks, better equipment for rangers and new technology to detect forest encroachment or poaching. "We're getting it done, we get it, and now we're helping to lead efforts globally in this same direction."</p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/human-evolution-rainforests-archaeology-west-africa-ivory-coast-2036488">Evolution: 150,000-Year-Old Rainforest Discovery Shakes Up Human History</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sloths-brink-extinction-struggle-adapt-climate-change-1959837">Sloths on Brink of Extinction As They Struggle To Adapt to Changing World</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/brazil-president-amazon-road-deforestation-1952640">'Historic Deforestation' Fears as Amazon Road Paving Gets Go Ahead</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/mass-extinction-prevention-protected-areas-species-1916991">Areas To Save To Halt 'Extinction Crisis' Revealed</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>
                https://www.newsweek.com/panama-puts-focus-natures-role-solving-climate-crisis-2075493</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 07:00:02 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075493</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Jeff Young ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ World ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T07:00:02-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T07:00:02-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content
                url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649301/forest-nature-preservation-panama.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="2500" height="1664">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Forest Nature Preservation Panama ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Rodrigo Arangua/AFP via Getty Images ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ View of an over 400-year-old tree in Barro Colorado island, in the artificial Gatun Lake of the Panama Canal. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/2898/nature-based-solutions-1-1706737729.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="137">
                <guid>579645</guid>
                <media:thumbnail
                    url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2343247/nature-based-solutions.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Harnessing the Power of Nature is Helping Us Fight Climate Change ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ Solutions to some of climate change's most pressing challenges already exist. Nature-based solutions harness the power of the natural world to combat the climate crisis, and can be as simple as protecting forests and coastal wetlands. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Various Sources ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ The Right-Wing Culture War Scam Comes Full Circle | Opinion ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ The new campus censors are almost entirely on the MAGA far right. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>Last week, a New York University (NYU) student named Logan Rozos <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/05/16/us/nyu-withholds-diploma-student-gaza-speech-hnk" rel="nofollow">delivered</a> a short commencement address condemning Israel's brutalization of Gaza. The beliefs expressed in the address—which (<em>quelle horror</em>!) apparently departed from university guidelines—were unremarkable and at this point <a href="https://circle.tufts.edu/latest-research/young-voters-and-israel-palestine-conflict" rel="nofollow">widely shared</a> among younger Americans. Instead of quietly moving along from a speech that was received quite well by its audience, NYU has taken the unprecedented (and cowardly) step of withholding the student's diploma altogether.</p> <p>The imbroglio is a perfect encapsulation of where the GOP's "cancel culture" scam has been headed all along, which is not to the mythical "viewpoint diversity" disingenuously demanded by the kinds of people who have spent the past decade bizarrely obsessing over minor <a href="https://www.vox.com/identities/2019/11/5/20944138/oberlin-banh-mi-college-campus-diversity" rel="nofollow">dining hall controversies</a> at Oberlin College or parsing <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2015/12/08/us/yale-lecturer-resigns-after-email-on-halloween-costumes.html" rel="nofollow">silly Halloween emails</a> from Yale administrators but rather to a different, more open and unapologetic censorship regime, one designed and policed by the far right rather than the far left.</p> <p>Left-wing ideological excesses at American colleges and universities were always massively overblown. College campuses, after all, cannot and should not be anarchic free speech zones where any maniacal provocateur like <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/politics-news/milo-yiannopoulos-career-new-ventures-1236059885/" rel="nofollow">Milo Yiannopoulos</a> can come and deliver an outrageous address designed to do nothing other than generate controversy without any pushback. You don't actually have a constitutional right not to be protested, and when you visit a college, you are also setting foot in a place where other human beings live and work. You should not always expect your opinions to be received calmly or warmly.</p> <p>But yes, occasionally the anti-speaker fervor of left-wing student groups went overboard and in general some academics and writers on the left should have been more outspoken about maintaining climates of open discourse on campus. I'm thinking in particular of former International Monetary Fund (IMF) honcho Christine Lagarde <a href="https://www.insidehighered.com/news/2014/05/13/head-imf-facing-protests-withdraws-smith-college-commencement-address" rel="nofollow">pulling out</a> of her Smith College commencement address in 2014 because of protests. At the same time, conservatives in the 21st century have consistently claimed speech rights for incendiary campus speakers that they do not believe <a href="https://www.juancole.com/2017/05/coultergate-campus-speech.html" rel="nofollow">should be enjoyed</a> by professors with unfashionable views about Israel and Palestine.</p> <p>And it's worth noting that <a href="https://www.thefire.org/sites/default/files/2025/05/Students-Under-Fire-Report-2020-2024_final.pdf" rel="nofollow">according to</a> the Foundation for Individual Rights in Education, since 2023 "students and student groups were mostly targeted by administrators, for expression about the Israeli-Palestinian conflict" and that "government officials and politicians led more attempts to punish student speech than in any other period" that the organization has studied. So, to the extent that cancel culture is running amok on college campuses today, it is almost entirely perpetrated by those on the political right.</p> <p>It's also telling that nearly all of the prominent public figures who made their careers warning about the dangers of woke "cancel culture" on college campuses have been completely silent as students are not just attacked but in some cases <a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/world/tufts-student-immigration-1.7531299" rel="nofollow">disappeared into</a> America's immigration gulag for the crime of leading protests or writing op-eds. With a few prominent exceptions like <em>The Atlantic</em>'s Connor Friedersdorf, who to his credit has <a href="https://x.com/conor64/status/1906500805366259955" rel="nofollow">condemned</a> the new witch hunts against Palestinian activists, their commitment to campus free speech has turned out to be nothing but empty clout-chasing and bad faith.</p> <p>And it should be no surprise that Israel is the leading edge of the new right-wing censorship regime. For more than 20 years, apologists for Israel have sought to shame, blackball, and fire professors who criticize Israeli policy. Today's incarnation of silencing Palestinian voices is called "<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/05/18/us/project-esther-heritage-foundation-palestine.html" rel="nofollow">Project Esther</a>" but 20 years ago it was called Campus Watch, which still hosts a web page that <a href="https://www.meforum.org/campus-watch/students-study-unrest-in-the-middle-east-incl" rel="nofollow">re-runs</a> in its entirety an utterly innocuous 14-year-old article from my university's student newspaper about students studying the Arab Spring.</p> <p>It's all the same thing. Something—in this case it is the accusation that Israel is committing war crimes or genocide in Gaza—is declared beyond the scope of criticism and free speech and then a million little busybodies start sifting through syllabi, social media, and research to find thoughtcrimes. Academics who study the Middle East are more than accustomed to dealing with this kind of blowback, and many have <a href="https://www.thefire.org/news/major-hit-tenure-muhlenberg-fires-pro-palestinian-professor" rel="nofollow">paid</a> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/oct/24/university-professors-discipline-palestine-support" rel="nofollow">for</a> <a href="https://ccrjustice.org/files/Salaita_Factsheet_1-29-15_0.pdf" rel="nofollow">their views</a> <a href="https://depauliaonline.com/54141/news/campusnews/exclusive-norman-finkelstein-requests-apology-from-depaul/" rel="nofollow">with</a> <a href="https://www.masslive.com/news/2023/11/smith-college-lecturer-says-she-was-fired-after-speaking-about-israel-hamas-war-in-class.html" rel="nofollow">their careers</a>, without any support from the <em>Free Press</em> crowd.</p> <p>But what's new is both the effort to silence and harm the career prospects of student dissidents as well as the coordinated effort to force universities to shutter entire programs of study for fear that criticism of Israel's policies—and America's complicity with them—might escape containment. What's also new is the effort to strip entire institutions of completely unrelated funding if they do not do the bidding of people whose fragile outlooks cannot bear a moment's criticism of Israel.</p> <p>Administrators must either resist this new, MAGA-led witch hunt, or watch the independence and freedom of universities disappear along with their integrity.</p> <p><em>David Faris is an associate professor of political science at Roosevelt University and the author of </em>It's Time to Fight Dirty: How <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/democrats" target="_blank">Democrats</a> Can Build a Lasting Majority in American Politics<em>. His writing has appeared in </em>Slate<em>, </em>The Week<em>, </em>The Washington Post<em>, </em>The New Republic<em>, </em>Washington Monthly<em> and more. You can find him on Twitter @davidmfaris.</em></p> <p><em>The views expressed in this article are the writer's own.</em></p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/gen-z-celebrates-donald-trump-victory-college-campuses-1981882">Gen Z Celebrates Donald Trump's Victory Across College Campuses</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/columbia-university-hatred-israel-part-curriculum-1895696">At Columbia University Hatred of Israel Is Part of the Curriculum</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/look-liberal-arts-lower-temperature-campus-culture-wars-opinion-1859231">Look to the Liberal Arts to Lower the Temperature of Campus Culture Wars | Opinion</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/river-sea-call-genocide-heard-america-opinion-1838595">'From the River to the Sea': A Call to Genocide Heard in America | Opinion</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>
                https://www.newsweek.com/right-wing-culture-war-scam-comes-full-circle-opinion-2075404</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 07:00:01 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075404</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ David Faris ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ Opinion ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T07:00:01-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T07:00:01-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content
                url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649202/group-faculty-staff-students.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="2500" height="1667">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ A group of faculty, staff, and students ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ AANDREW THOMAS/Middle East Images/AFP via Getty Images ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ A group of faculty, staff, and students of George Washington University meet in the yard where there was a pro-Palestine encampment last year, on May 8, 2025, in Washington D.C. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3097/bring-your-kids-2-1747766352.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="22">
                <guid>619515</guid>
                <media:thumbnail
                    url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2648246/trumps-favorite-wh-room-has-maga-gold.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Trump's Oval Office Is 'Decked Out' In 'MAGA Gold' ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ White House Press Secretary Karoline Leavitt held a briefing with kid journalists. She was asked what President Donald Trump's favorite room in the White House is. She answered, "I think his favorite room in the white House is definitely the Oval Office, because it's so beautiful. And he has decked it out in gold. It's now MAGA gold in there." ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ CSPAN ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Russian intelligence attack on NATO "logistics and technology" exposed ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ London says Russia's GRU military intelligence is trying to penetrate Ukraine allies' networks. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>Russia's military intelligence is targeting logistics operations in <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/nato" data-sys="1">NATO</a> countries which help Ukraine, according to the UK's National Cyber Security Centre (NSCS).</p><p>The NSCS, part of the U.K's GCHQ (Government Communications Headquarters) <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/news/uk-partners-expose-russian-intelligence-campaign" target="_blank">said </a>that Russia's GRU Unit 26165 is trying to penetrate networks across defense and transport systems both in Ukraine and in several of its allies.</p><p><em>Newsweek</em> has contacted the Russian defense ministry for comment.</p><h2>Why It Matters</h2><p>Western leaders have raised the alarm over the cyber warfare that Russian hacker groups have engaged in since the start of Moscow' full-scale invasion of Ukraine.</p><p>These include accusations that Russia has conducted cyberattacks against Ukraine and on civilian infrastructure in Europe, and interfered in foreign elections. The NSCS report will reinforce these concerns.</p><h2>What To Know</h2><p>The NSCS said the U.K. government and its allies had exposed a campaign of "malicious cyber activity" carried out by Russia's GRU military intelligence unit 26165, also known as APT 28, against western logistics entities and technology companies.</p><p>The unit, also known as '<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.crowdstrike.com/en-us/blog/who-is-fancy-bear/" target="_blank">Fancy Bear</a>,' has raise the alarm among NATO allies with France accusing the unit in April of carrying out cyberattacks against its government ministries.</p><p>The U.K. and partners from ten countries found that it had conducted the operations against both public and private organizations since 2022, the NSCS said in its press release.</p><p>These included organizations across the defense sector, IT services, maritime, airports, ports and air traffic management systems and other sectors which help deliver support to Ukraine.</p><p>The GRU unit's activity included credential guessing, spear-phishing and exploiting <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/microsoft" data-sys="1">Microsoft</a> Exchange mailbox permissions. Russian intelligence also targeted internet-connected cameras at Ukrainian border crossings and near military installations.</p><p>The countries apart from Ukraine which were targeted were Bulgaria, the Czech Republic, France, Germany, Greece, Italy, Moldova, the Netherlands, Poland, Romania, Slovakia and the U.S.</p><p>No specific organizations were named and there was no information about whether the unit managed to obtain classified information.</p><p>The NCSC called on leaders at technology and logistics firms to recognize the elevated cyber threat and take immediate action to protect themselves.</p><h2>What People Are Saying</h2><p><strong>Paul Chichester, NCSC Director of Operations:</strong> "This malicious campaign by Russia's military intelligence service presents a serious risk to targeted organizations, including those involved in the delivery of assistance to Ukraine."</p><p><strong>Atlantic Council report <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/content-series/russia-tomorrow/unpacking-russias-cyber-nesting-doll/#conclusion" target="_blank">released May 20</a>:</strong> "American and Western policymakers must size up the threat, unpack the complexity of Russia's cyber web, and invest in the right proactive measures to enhance their security and resilience."</p><h2>What Happens Next</h2><p>A report by the Atlantic Council r<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/content-series/russia-tomorrow/unpacking-russias-cyber-nesting-doll/#conclusion" target="_blank">eleased Tuesday</a> concluded that Russia is a persistent and well-resourced cyber threat to the United States and its allies and partners, and the threat Moscow poses will continue to emerge in future.</p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/marco-rubio-putin-war-criminal-2075570">Marco Rubio Refuses To Call Putin 'War Criminal', After Grilling Rex Tillerson</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/us-russia-malaysia-news-military-air-navy-show-2075536">US and Russia Flex Military Muscles on Same Stage</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/nato-drills-finland-russia-uk-sweden-donald-trump-2075253">NATO Shows Force on Northern Flank with Russia as US Pulls Back</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/us-news-minuteman-iii-intercontinental-ballstic-missile-test-pacific-russia-china-2075137">US Launches Nuclear-Capable Missile in Arms Race With Russia and China</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>https://www.newsweek.com/russia-gru-ukraine-nscs-2075658</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 06:59:22 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075658</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Brendan Cole ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ World ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T06:59:22-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T06:59:22-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content
                url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649541/generic-computer-hacking-image.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="2500" height="1871">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Generic computer hacking image ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Getty Images ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ This generic image from 2017 shows a computer exploited by computer hackers. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/2807/587bb9ddb6f8ea0598adaaf54b8e7a3406dbbc60-1690372743.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="41">
                <guid>561417</guid>
                <media:thumbnail
                    url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2262141/group-ib-cybersecurity-firm-co-founder-ilya-sachkov.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Russian Cyber Expert Accused of Spying for U.S. Gets 14 Years Behind Bars ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ Ilya Sachkov, a Russian cyber expert accused of spying for the U.S., was handed a 14-year prison sentence on treason charges by a Russian court on Wednesday. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Various Sources ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Marco Rubio refuses to call Putin 'war criminal', after grilling Rex Tillerson ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ The secretary of state appeared at a foreign affairs committee. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>Marco Rubio refused to call <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/vladimir-putin" data-sys="1">Vladimir Putin</a> a "war criminal," despite grilling former secretary of state <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/rex-tillerson" data-sys="1">Rex Tillerson</a> over the same issue in 2017.</p><p>At a House Committee on foreign affairs session on Wednesday, the current secretary of state dodged questions on Putin, though admitted there had been "war crimes" in the war.</p><p><em>Newsweek</em> contacted the Department of State by website form to comment on this story.</p><h2><strong>Why It Matters</strong></h2><p>Putin invaded Ukraine in February 2022. One of President <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/donald-trump" data-sys="1">Donald Trump</a>'s pledges during his campaign to office was to <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/trump-tariffs-russia-marco-rubio-2064753" target="_blank">end the war in Ukraine</a> within 24 hours of taking office but the administration has struggled to do so and on Tuesday, Trump and Putin had a two-hour phone conversation that did not result in a peace deal.</p><figure><img src="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649427/marco-rubio.jpg" /><figcaption>Secretary of State Marco Rubio testifies before House Committee on Appropriations subcommittee budget hearing for the Department of State and related programs on Capitol Hill in Washington, Wednesday, May 21, 2025. <span class="copyright">AP Photo/Jose Luis Magana</span></figcaption></figure><p>On Wednesday, it was reported that Trump told his Ukrainian counterpart <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/volodymyr-zelensky" data-sys="1">Volodymyr Zelensky</a> that Russia and Ukraine must <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/russia-ukraine-trump-putin-zelensky-promises-2075085" target="_blank">independently end the war.</a></p><h2><strong>What To Know</strong></h2><p>During the hearing, Democratic Representative Bill Keating asked Rubio if he thought Putin was a war criminal.</p><p>"I think you can look at instances that have happened there and certainly characterize them as war crimes but our intent is to end the war," Rubio responded.</p><p>Keating asked again: "Is he a war criminal?"</p><p>Rubio said: "We can't end the war without talking to Mr. Putin."</p><p>When Keating pressed him again and accused Rubio of "equivocating," Rubio said: "I'm answering your question and the answer is war crimes have been committed no doubt and who is responsible for that, there will be a time and place for that accountability."</p><p>As a Florida Senator in 2017, Rubio grilled Tillerson during his confirmation hearing for secretary of state on the same issue.</p><p>When Tillerson said he would "not use that term," Rubio spoke about Syria and said: "It should not be hard to say that Vladimir Putin's military has conducted war crimes in Aleppo because it is never acceptable, you would agree, for a military to specifically target civilians, which is what's happened there through the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/russian-military" data-sys="1">Russian military</a>."</p><h2><strong>What People Are Saying</strong></h2><p><strong>The group Republicans against Trump said on X </strong>that Rubio refusing to call Putin a war criminal was "shameful."</p><p><strong>During the hearing, Democratic Senator Jeanne Shaheen said:</strong> "What Vladimir Putin is doing now is playing for time and he's playing the president like a fiddle."</p><h2><strong>What Happens Next</strong></h2><p>Rubio said on Sunday that the Trump administration expects to figure out "pretty soon" if Russia is <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/marco-rubio-addresses-russia-tapping-us-ukraine-talks-2073831" target="_blank">"tapping us along"</a> when it comes to peace talks.</p><p>During the hearing, he said the U.S. will impose more sanctions on Russia if efforts to reach a peace deal stall."</p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/iran-uranium-enrichment-nuclear-weapon-us-trump-israel-2075145">How to Build a Nuclear Weapon - What is Uranium Enrichment For?</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/are-us-iran-nuclear-talks-dead-end-opinion-2074956">Are US-Iran Nuclear Talks at a Dead-End? | Opinion</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/us-doubles-down-iran-nuclear-threat-2075047">U.S. Doubles Down on Iran Nuclear Threat</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/marco-rubio-addresses-russia-tapping-us-ukraine-talks-2073831">Marco Rubio Addresses if Russia Is 'Tapping Us Along' in Ukraine Talks</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>https://www.newsweek.com/marco-rubio-putin-war-criminal-2075570</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 06:54:20 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075570</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Kate Plummer ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ News ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T06:54:20-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T06:54:20-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649427/marco-rubio.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="2500" height="1667">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Marco Rubio ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ AP Photo/Jose Luis Magana ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ Secretary of State Marco Rubio testifies before House Committee on Appropriations subcommittee budget hearing for the Department of State and related programs on Capitol Hill in Washington, Wednesday, May 21, 2025. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3098/putin-war-crimes-1-1747857386.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="46">
                <guid>619648</guid>
                <media:thumbnail
                    url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649254/democrat-confronts-rubio-putin-war.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Democrat Confronts Rubio: Is Putin A 'War Criminal?' ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ Democratic Rep. Bill Keating confronted Secretary of State Marco Rubio over the Russia-Ukraine War during a Wednesday hearing. "Vladimir Putin, is he a war criminal?" ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ House of Representatives ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Who is Elias Rodriguez? Suspect named in Israeli embassy staff killings ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ Two Israeli embassy employees, Yaron Lischinsky and Sarah Milgrim, were shot and killed in Washington D.C. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>Authorities have identified a suspect in the fatal <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/fatal-shooting-near-capital-jewish-museum-dc-what-we-know-2075539" target="_blank">shooting of two Israeli embassy workers</a> near a Jewish museum in Washington, D.C. on Wednesday night as 30-year-old Elias Rodriguez from Chicago.</p><h2>The Context</h2><p>Video footage on social media showed a man chanting "free, free Palestine" being led away by officers inside what appeared to be the Capital Jewish Museum in Washington, D.C. on Wednesday night, following the shooting. Washington Metropolitan Police Chief Pamela Smith told reporters the suspect made the same chant while in custody.</p><p>Smith said a man had been seen pacing outside the museum before the incident.</p><p>Protests in the United States have remained ongoing following the October 7, 2023, <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/hamas">Hamas</a> attack on southern Israel, which killed some 1,200 people and saw about 250 taken hostage. Israel has resumed its offensive after <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/gaza-heads-deepening-war-month-after-ceasefire-collapse-2060811" target="_blank">a temporary ceasefire</a> earlier this year and has so far <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/israel-gaza-nato-ultimatum-2074572" target="_blank">killed more than 52,000 people</a> in Gaza, both civilians and militants, the Associated Press reported, citing Palestinian health officials.</p><h2><span>What To Know</span></h2><p>The Israeli foreign ministry said the victims were Yaron Lischinsky and Sarah Milgrim. "No words can express the depth of our grief and horror at this devastating loss," it said.</p><p>One witness inside the museum told WAGA-TV a man ran into the building after the shooting and was initially offered help.</p><p>"The security guard happened to let this guy in. I guess they were thinking, and he was covered in rain, he was clearly in trauma, he was in shock, and some of the people in the event brought him water, they sat him down. 'Are you OK? Were you shot? What happened?' He's like, 'Somebody call the cops.'</p><p>"So about 10 minutes later when the cops actually came in he said, 'I did this,' he said, 'Sir I'm unarmed,' he put his hands up he grabbed a red kaffiyeh out of his pocket and started the free Palestine chants. You know, 'there's only one solution, intifada revolution' and he was being dragged out of the building as he was yelling 'free Palestine.'"</p><h2>Who Is Elias Rodriguez?</h2><p>A <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/elias-rodriguez-2132a4164/" target="_blank">LinkedIn profile</a> under the name of a Chicago-based Elias Rodriguez, whose profile photograph appears to match those of the suspect, says he worked as a "profiles administrative specialist" at the American Osteopathic Information Association (AOIA), a body which represents osteopathic medical doctors. The AOIA also <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.aoiassn.org/staff" target="_blank">lists an "Elias Rodriguez</a>" as an employee in this role on its official website.</p><p>According to the LinkedIn page, Rodriguez previously worked as a "production and logistics coordinator and oral history researcher" at the HistoryMakers, a nonprofit that says it is committed to "preserving and making widely accessible the untold personal stories of both well-known and unsung African Americans."</p><p>The <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.thehistorymakers.org/our-people/Elias--Rodriguez" target="_blank">HistoryMakers says</a> Rodriguez has a B.A. degree in English from the University of Illinois at Chicago, lived in the city's Avondale neighborhood and previously worked as a content writer "for commercial and noncommercial firms in the technology space."</p><p><em>Newsweek</em> has not independently verified that the Elias Rodriguez listed by the HistoryMakers is the same person police arrested over the Washington, D.C. shooting.</p><p><em>Newsweek</em> has contacted Washington D.C. Metropolitan Police, the Chicago Police Department, the AOIA and the HistoryMakers for comment on Thursday outside of regular office hours via telephone, email and online inquiry form.</p><p>In October 2017, an <a rel="nofollow" href="https://liberationnews.org/chicago-demands-justice-laquan-not-money-amazon/" target="_blank">article by <em>Liberation</em></a>, the newspaper of the left-wing Party for Socialism and Liberation (PSL), listed an "Elias Rodriguez" as one of its activists in an article about the police shooting of 17-year-old Black youth Laquan McDonald in Chicago in 2014. The article appears to have since been removed.</p><p>Speaking to the publication, Rodriguez said that "[Amazon's] whitening of Seattle is structurally racist and a direct danger to all workers who live in that city. So do we in Chicago and all across the country want a nation of cities dominated and occupied by massive corporations where only the rich and white can live and the vast majority of us must live on edges of the city and society living in deeper and deeper poverty?"</p><p>The PSL <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/elias-rodriguez-not-member-says-socialist-party-linked-dc-suspect-2075632" target="_blank">denied Rodriguez is a party member</a> in a post on X, formerly <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/twitter" data-sys="1">Twitter</a>.</p><p>They added: "We reject any attempt to associate the PSL with the DC shooting."</p><p>Independent journalist Ken Klippenstein shared what he said was the shooter's <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.kenklippenstein.com/p/the-israel-embassy-shooter-manifesto" target="_blank">980-word manifesto</a> on his website, though he didn't say how he obtained the document and its authenticity has not been independently verified.</p><p>"I believe the document to be authentic for several reasons, including the fact that it is signed by Rodriguez and timestamped well before he was named by law enforcement or any media," Klippenstein wrote.</p><p>The document advocates for what its author calls "armed demonstration" as a response to "genocide," a term they use to describe the Israeli military operation in Gaza.</p><p>The author writes: "Israelis themselves boast about their own shock at the free hand the Americans have given them to exterminate the Palestinians. Public opinion has shifted against the genocidal apartheid state, and the American government has simply shrugged, they'll do without public opinion then, criminalize it where they can, suffocate it with bland reassurances that they're doing all they can to restrain Israel where it cannot criminalize protest outright."</p><p>Referring to Operation Protective Edge, a 2014 Israeli military operation against Hamas in Gaza, the author added: "The action would have been morally justified taken 11 years ago during Protective Edge, around the time I personally became acutely aware of our brutal conduct in Palestine.</p><p>"But I think to most Americans such an action would have been illegible, would seem insane. I am glad that today at least there are many Americans for which the action will be highly legible and, in some funny way, the only sane thing to do."</p><h2>What People Are Saying</h2><p><strong>Speaking to the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/bbc" data-sys="1">BBC</a>, Washington, D.C.-based Rabbi Levi Shemtov</strong> described the couple shot as "nice people, popular," adding this is "brutal news."</p><p><strong>The Israeli Embassy to the U.S.A. said in a statement:</strong> "Yaron and Sarah were our friends and colleagues. They were in the prime of their lives.</p><p>"This evening, a terrorist shot and killed them as they exited an event at the Capital Jewish Museum in DC.</p><p>"The entire embassy staff is heartbroken and devastated by their murder. No words can express the depth of our grief and horror at this devastating loss."</p><p><strong><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/donald-trump-responds-isreali-embassy-shooting-washington-dc-2075553" target="_blank">President Donald Trump wrote</a> in a post on his Truth Social website:</strong> "These horrible D.C. killings, based obviously on antisemitism, must end, NOW!"</p><p><em>Updates 5/22/25, 5:33 a.m and 6:30 a.m. ET: This article was updated with additional information and</em><em> to note the Party for Socialism and Liberation has denied Rodriguez is a party member.</em></p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/elias-rodriguez-dc-shooting-suspect-latest-israel-blames-toxic-incitement-live-updates-2075655">Elias Rodriguez, DC Shooting Suspect Latest, Israel Blames 'Toxic Incitement': Live Updates</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/elias-rodriguez-not-member-says-socialist-party-linked-dc-suspect-2075632">Elias Rodriguez 'Not a Member' Says Socialist Party Linked to DC Suspect</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>
                https://www.newsweek.com/who-elias-rodriguez-suspect-named-israeli-embassy-staff-killings-2075558</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 03:50:19 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075558</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ James Bickerton ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ U.S. ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T03:50:19-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T06:46:20-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649390/washington-dc.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="2500" height="1597">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Washington DC ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ ALEX WROBLEWSKI/AFP/GETTY ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ A man draped in the Israeli flag, bearing a cross and the name 'Jesus' at its center, gestures as Metropolitan Police officers secure the area outside the Capital Jewish Museum following a shooting that left two people dead in Washington, DC, in the early hours of May 22, 2025. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3098/eu-israel-shots-1747839238.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="50">
                <guid>619612</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2648982/eu.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ EU Rebukes Israel Over Warning Shots Near Gaza-Bound Diplomats ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ The European Union's top diplomat on Wednesday said any threat to diplomats' lives was "unacceptable," as a delegation came under fire while visiting Jenin in the Israel-occupied West Bank. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ AP ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Tiger Woods drops cryptic 'to be continued' post looking for length ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ Tiger Woods is involved in numerous projects outside of competitive golf, including the design of several golf courses in various locations around the country. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>The Achilles injury has not stopped <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/tiger-woods-design-par-3-augusta-national-home-masters-2056869">Tiger Woods from continuing to work on his other ventures</a> outside of competitive golf. These include golf course design, an activity that Woods and his company, TGR Design, have recently revived.</p> <p>The 15-time major champion <a href="https://twitter.com/TigerWoods/status/1925191067403501765" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">recently released a promotional video</a> showing him at the construction site of his latest project, the Bluejack Ranch golf course in Aledo, Texas. It is a private residential club that will include a golf course among other amenities.</p> <p>Woods already designed a course for Bluejack in Montgomery, Texas (Bluejack National), which was built between 2014 and 2016. The start of construction of the new course in Aledo was reported in January this year.</p> <p>In the video posted by <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/tgl-rumors-tiger-woods-launch-womens-league-2063982">Tiger Woods</a>, it is heard that the new course is designed over 7,500 yards. However, the legendary player predicts that "more length" will continue to be sought as the project progresses.</p> <p>This video is the third in a series that has been released since last April. However, it ends with the cryptic message "To be continued", suggesting that there are still new revelations coming.</p> <p>The project description on TGR Design's official website highlights the fusion between the surrounding natural beauty and the strategic difficulties that will characterize the course:</p> <p>"The course will play alongside stunning terrain dotted with rock outcroppings as well as mature oaks and hardwoods that line the numerous creeks running throughout the property that will contrast the open, rolling pastureland for a truly unique and varied experience throughout the round."</p> <p><em>"Wide playing corridors flanked by native grasses and prairie will offer playability throughout the round while also emphasizing shot-making and strategy as multiple routes will be offered from tee to green."</em></p> <p><em>"The highly strategic nature of the course will be particularly evident in the interesting and bold green contouring that will place a premium on accuracy and precision to score well but maintain playability with low-cut green surrounds that promote creative shot-making and recoveries."</em></p> <p>In addition to Bluejack Ranch, Woods and TGR Design are currently working on three other golf course projects. They are the Marcella Club in Utah, the Trout National - The Reserve in New Jersey, and a nine-hole par-3 in Augusta, Georgia.</p> <p>To date, the 82-time PGA Tour winner and his design firm <a rel="nofollow" href="https://tgrdesign.tigerwoods.com/courses/">have signed the blueprints of 17 golf-related facilities</a>, including golf courses, practice facilities and even eight PopStroke putting courses in Florida, Arizona and Texas.</p> <p><em><strong>More Golf: </strong></em><em><strong><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/tiger-woods-tgl-officially-lands-new-team-catch-2075099">Tiger Woods' TGL Officially Lands New Team with a Catch</a></strong></em></p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/john-daly-inks-deal-hooters-keep-company-alive-2074508">John Daly Inks Deal with Hooters Trying to Keep Company Alive</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/paige-spiranac-golf-story-chris-pratt-chuckling-2075442">Paige Spiranac's Chris Pratt Golf Story Will Leave You Chuckling</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/rory-mcilroy-follows-bryson-dechambeau-footsteps-dp-world-tour-history-2075464">Rory McIlroy Follows Bryson DeCambeau's Footsteps Making History</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/pga-tour-news-scottie-scheffler-odds-charles-schwab-challenge-2075418">Scottie Scheffler's Odds to Win Charles Schwab are Ludicrous</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>
                https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/tiger-woods-cryptic-post-continued-length-2075544</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 06:45:01 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075544</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Julio Cesar Valdera Morales ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ Golf ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T06:45:01-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T06:45:01-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649378/tiger-woods.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="2825" height="1883">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ tiger woods ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Douglas P. DeFelice/Getty Images ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ Tiger Woods of the United States plays his shot from the 15th tee during the second round of the PNC Championship at Ritz-Carlton Golf Club on December 22, 2024 in Orlando, Florida. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3073/0340fec71f9e3df7f308b58baf6a8a6cb35247fe-1741746999.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="55">
                <guid>614759</guid>
                <media:thumbnail
                    url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2602779/tiger-woods-genesis-invitational-pga-tour.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Tiger Woods Ruptures Achilles, Undergoes Surgery Before The PLAYERS ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ The golfing world is in shock. On Tuesday, the legendary Tiger Woods announced on social media that he suffered a ruptured Achilles tendon while practicing at home. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Various Sources ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Dog owners say their pets have better social lives than they do ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ A new survey has found that dog owners believe their pets have better social lives than they do. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>Wagging tails, smiley faces and adorable eyes—it is little surprise that dogs find it easy to make friends. But a new survey has revealed that American dog owners believe their pets have better social lives than they do.</p> <p>A survey by Talker Research on behalf of Camp Bow Wow asked 2,000 dog owners aged 25 and over about their pets' lives.</p> <p>When asked whether they agree with the statement, "My dog hangs out with their dog friends more than I hang out with my friends," more than six in 10 (63 percent) U.S. dog owners said they agreed, including 34 percent who strongly agree and 29 percent who somewhat agree.</p> <p>According to the same survey, most dogs aren't just social—they have full-on friend groups. Nearly three in four dog owners (73 percent) said their dog has at least <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/friendliest-dog-breeds-1844015" target="_blank">one dog friend</a>, with 27 percent saying their pet has three or more.</p> <p>These aren't occasional encounters either, 37 percent of owners say their dog hangs out with their canine companions at least once a week, and 14 percent report multiple weekly meetups. Whether it's at the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/tiny-pup-excited-about-park-suddenly-becomes-scares-after-seeing-big-dogs-2008031" target="_blank">dog park</a>, on walks, or at pet-friendly events, it seems our four-legged friends are living active, connected social lives.</p> <p>"Dogs are just like us, being able to see other dogs and interact with them on a regular basis does so much good for their mental and emotional wellbeing, and it makes their parents happier, too," said Camp Bow Wow's animal health and behavioral expert Erin Askeland.</p> <h3>How Many Americans Are Lonely?</h3> <p>For the humans though, there is a serious undertone. According to the U.S. Surgeon General's Advisory on Social Connection, nearly half of U.S. adults report <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/gen-z-loneliest-generation-1996926" target="_blank">experiencing loneliness</a>, with particularly high rates among young and older populations. The advisory highlights that social disconnection increases the risk of premature death by 26 percent to 29 percent, a health impact comparable to smoking 15 cigarettes a day.</p> <p>This so-called epidemic of loneliness is fueled by long-term trends such as shrinking social networks, declining in-person interactions, and the rise of single-person households, which now make up nearly 30 percent of U.S. households, up from just 13 percent in 1960. Time spent with friends has dropped dramatically—down 20 hours per month since 2003—while time spent alone has climbed steadily.</p> <p>The survey also revealed a clear generational divide in how dog owner's rated their own social lives. Younger generations were far more likely to agree that their dogs are the more socially active ones in the household. Among Gen Z dog owners, a striking 81 percent said their dogs spend more time with friends than they do. Millennials weren't far behind, with 71 percent agreeing with the statement.</p> <p>By contrast, only 45 percent of Baby Boomers and just 23 percent of the Silent Generation felt the same way.</p> <p><em>Talker Research surveyed 2,000 American dog owners aged 25 and older who own fewer than four dogs; the survey was commissioned by Camp Bow Wow and administered and conducted online by Talker Research between Apr. 21 and Apr. 28, 2025.</em></p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/cat-turns-24-thats-not-only-reason-theyre-celebrating-2075188">Cat Turns 24—and That's Not the Only Reason They're Celebrating</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/kitten-thief-caught-womans-barn-2075319">'Kitten Thief' Caught in Woman's Barn, Internet Obsessed With Culprit</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/woman-finds-reason-mysterious-holes-clothes-2075318">Woman's Clothes Kept Getting Mysterious Holes—Then She Grabbed a Flashlight</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/gen-x-mom-films-daughters-reaction-90s-songs-2075243">Gen X Mom Films Teen Daughter's Priceless Reaction to 90s Songs—'Mortified'</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>https://www.newsweek.com/dog-owners-say-pets-better-social-lives-2075153</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 06:39:54 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075153</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Alice Gibbs ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ Life ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T06:39:54-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T06:39:54-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2648782/french-bulldog-owner.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="1500" height="1000">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ French bulldog and owner ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Anastasia Efimova/Getty Images ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ A file photo of a dog owner and her French Bulldog. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3068/tiktik-1740647867.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="36">
                <guid>613620</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2596620/picture-video.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Awkward Corgi's Reaction During Puppy Social Event ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ Cannoli's reaction to the dogs running around her has delighted social media, as one person joked that she looked "appalled by all this roughness." ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ @rollinwithcannoli / TikTok ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Trump's "gold card" tied to surge in US visa inquires ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ The director of an EB-5 visa advisory firm saw "a sharp rise in inquiries since President Trump announced the gold card program." ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>President <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/donald-trump" data-sys="1">Donald Trump</a>'s $5 million "gold card" visa has led to an increase in interest in U.S. residency programs for wealthy individuals looking for fast-track pathways to American citizenship.</p><h2>Why It Matters</h2><p>In February, the president <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/donald-trump-gold-card-visa-applicants-2036982" target="_blank">proposed a gold card program</a> that would offer U.S. residency to individuals who invest $5 million in the country. Since returning to office on January 20, Trump has proposed sweeping changes to U.S. immigration policy and has moved to limit other immigration pathways, with his administration pausing the processing of <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/trump-administration-pauses-green-card-applications-refugees-asylum-seekers-2050388" target="_blank">some green card applications</a> and <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/supreme-court-lets-donald-trump-end-protections-350000-venezuelans-2074243" target="_blank">ending the temporary legal status</a> of certain migrant groups.</p><figure><img src="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649437/trump.jpg" /><figcaption>President Donald Trump holds up the $5 million gold card as he speaks to reporters while in flight on board Air Force One, en route to Miami, Thursday, April 3, 2025. <span class="copyright">Pool/AP</span></figcaption></figure><h2>What To Know</h2><p>The U.S. is experiencing a surge in interest from wealthy individuals, largely driven by programs such as the EB-5 Immigrant Investor Program, according to the global investment migration firm Henley &amp; Partners.</p><p>The EB-5 program, established in 1990, requires applicants to pay between $100,000 and $200,000 in fees to the United States Citizenship and Immigration Service. Additionally, investors must commit between $800,000 and $1 million and create at least 10 jobs for American workers.</p><p>In a news release issued on Tuesday, Henley &amp; Partners reported a 325 percent increase in EB-5 inquiries between 2019 and 2024. In Q1 2025 alone, inquiries rose 57 percent compared to the same period last year and 168 percent compared to Q4 2024. The EB-5 is now the fourth most inquired-about residence program globally.</p><p>"I've seen a sharp rise in inquiries since President Trump announced the gold card program. Many clients have fast-tracked their EB-5 filings out of concern the program might be replaced," Ashok Kumar Adusumilli, the director of EB5Resources.com, told <em>Newsweek</em>.</p><p>Since its creation, the EB-5 has attracted more than $55 billion in foreign direct investment, according to Henley &amp; Partners.</p><p>Experts argue that the gold card won't affect foreign investment in the U.S.</p><p>"It won't affect it hardly at all because there are far better investment opportunities than just giving $5 million to the federal government," David Bier, the director of immigration studies at the Cato Institute, told <em>Newsweek</em>.</p><p>"President Trump is a businessman and innovator who is always looking for new ways to bring investment back to the United States and encourage legal immigration," Abigail Jackson, a White House spokesperson, told <em>Newsweek</em>.</p><p>While the White House did not confirm the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/donald-trump-gold-card-visa-elon-musk-update-2070705" target="_blank">date of the program's rollout</a>, Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick said on Wednesday that the website for the gold card program <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/trump-gold-card-update-us-residency-five-million-2075509" target="_blank">would launch within a week</a>.</p><p>Lutnick said at the Axios Building the Future event in Washington, D.C., that the website trumpcard.gov would first allow users to register their interest in purchasing a card. Lutnick previously said 1,000 gold cards had been sold, despite no website existing.</p><p>One of the key features being promoted with the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/donald-trump-reveals-5m-visa-gold-card-his-face-2055171" target="_blank">proposed "Trump Card"</a> visa is that recipients would be subject only to U.S. territorial taxation, meaning they would be taxed solely on income earned within the U.S., rather than on their worldwide income.</p><p>This proposed shift could make U.S. residency appealing to foreign investors.</p><p>"In my experience, many foreign investors have hesitated to establish U.S. residency specifically due to global taxation concerns. If the gold card allows them to live in the United States without being subject to such tax burdens, it could lead to a tangible increase in domestic investment," Adusumilli said.</p><p>However, implementing such a policy would require a significant change to the Internal Revenue Code. Specifically, it would necessitate the creation of a new category of U.S. taxpayers distinct from current classifications, such as citizens, lawful permanent residents (green card holders) and individuals who meet the substantial presence test&mdash;all of whom are subject to worldwide taxation.</p><p>Such a change cannot be enacted through executive order and would require formal legislation passed by both houses of <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/congress" data-sys="1">Congress</a>. However, no such provision appears in <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/donald-trump-bill-hearing-timing-2075051" target="_blank">Trump's "big, beautiful bill,"</a> which is under debate in Congress.</p><p>"It is noteworthy that the GOP reconciliation bill provides none of the necessary changes to make this proposal a reality," Bier said.</p><p>Even if such language were added through the budget reconciliation process, the Byrd Rule would likely limit the tax benefits to 10 years. If the proposal were instead introduced through regular legislative channels, it would be subject to the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/senate" data-sys="1">Senate</a> filibuster, making passage significantly more difficult.</p><p>One expert lambasted the policy, saying it would be "dead on arrival."</p><p>"The Trump Card is DOA because there is no viable market," David Lesperance, the managing partner at Lesperance &amp; Associates, told <em>Newsweek</em>. "Yet another nail in the coffin of viability is the fact that the most attractive promoted feature, territorial taxation, has not even been included in the current tax reconciliation proposals."</p><h2>What People Are Saying</h2><p><strong>David Bier, the director of immigration studies at the Cato Institute, told <em>Newsweek</em></strong>: "The Trump administration says that it wants to end the existing program, but it has no power to do that, so I doubt that will happen."</p><p><strong>David Lesperance, the managing partner at Lesperance &amp; Associates, told <em>Newsweek</em></strong>: "No one will spend their entire fortune on a donation to the U.S. government for the honor of becoming a U.S. taxpayer."</p><p><strong>Ashok Kumar Adusumilli, the director of EB5Resources.com, told <em>Newsweek</em></strong>: "EB-5 and the gold card can coexist as distinct pathways targeting different investor profiles."</p><p><strong>Commenting on the gold card website, Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick said on Wednesday</strong>: "All that will come over a matter of the next weeks&mdash;not month, weeks."</p><p><strong>Jean Paul Fabri, the chief economist at Henley &amp; Partners,</strong> <strong>said in a news release</strong>: "The apparent paradox of wealthy U.S.-Americans considering moves abroad, while non-Americans invest in the USA, reflects a broader global dynamic and an economic truth. The USA remains the world's best place to create and grow wealth, even if some opt to move elsewhere. For global investors, the American market represents opportunity, scale, security, and innovation."</p><h2>What Happens Next</h2><p>The website is expected to launch in the coming weeks. However, the program, which requires congressional action to move forward, faces major legislative hurdles.</p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/donald-trump-admin-h-1b-visa-applications-2072626">Trump Admin Selects 120,000 H-1B Visa Applications: What to Know</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/green-car-revoked-white-house-immigration-2072578">Green Cards Could Be Revoked At Any Time Under White House Proposal</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/donald-trump-gold-card-visa-elon-musk-update-2070705">Donald Trump's Gold Card Visa: Elon Musk Gives New Update</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/ice-maryland-visa-fraud-sham-marriage-2065612">ICE Thwarts Major Nationwide Marriage Fraud Operation</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>https://www.newsweek.com/donald-trump-gold-card-visa-immigration-2075603</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 06:32:34 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075603</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Billal Rahman ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ Politics ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T06:32:34-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T06:32:34-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649437/trump.jpg" type="image/jpeg"
                medium="image" expression="full" width="2500" height="1667">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Trump ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Pool/AP ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ President Donald Trump holds up the $5 million gold card as he speaks to reporters while in flight on board Air Force One, en route to Miami, Thursday, April 3, 2025. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3082/gold-card-1743753077.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="29">
                <guid>616573</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2620724/trump-gold-card.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Donald Trump Reveals $5m Visa Gold Card With His Face On It ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ President Donald Trump has unveiled his $5 million 'gold card' visa, featuring his own likeness. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ AP ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Woman "confused" by how cat gets into home, then she catches it on camera ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ "To be fair, he's not sneaking if he doesn't seem to care about being caught," one user said in the comments. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>A family was baffled after discovering a random cat in the home in the middle of the night and couldn't understand how he got in&mdash;until they managed to catch him sneaking inside on camera the next day.</p><p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@ayelookidgaf/video/7504941296641953067?is_from_webapp=1&amp;sender_device=pc" target="_blank">The clip</a>, shared on <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/tiktok" data-sys="1">TikTok</a> by @ayelookidgaf, shows the orange kitten kicking out a vent with his paws, as he makes his way up into the poster's living room while she's recording him on her phone.</p><p>"Throwback to when we were all confused about how this random cat ended up in our house in the middle of the night - only to catch him sneaking in through the vent the next day," she says in the caption.</p><p>The video quickly went viral on social media, and it has received over 533,900 views and 131,500 likes on the platform so far.</p><p>User @theynotlikeus757 commented: "He's very smart , luckily it's just the cat and not a raccoon or snake lol."</p><p>Another TikToker, Moxuri, wrote: "To be fair, he's not sneaking if he doesn't seem to care about being caught."</p><p>Thatfuckingnurserandy commented: "He's so casual about it. 'Oh hey guys! That was a long day, am I right? Thank god we're home!"</p><p>Cats are known for their <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/feline-parkour-cat-turns-train-obstacle-course-because-she-can-1843497" target="_blank">ability to twist and bend</a> their bodies and sneak into places that most other animals would never try. What makes them so flexible?</p><p>Felines have a <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/why-does-my-cat-squeeze-small-spaces-liquid-uri-burstyn-1711590" target="_blank">much more elastic spinal column</a> than humans and many other animals. They have 30 vertebrae, or 53 up to the tail, and specialized intervertebral discs, loosely connected, that allow them to rotate their bodies to 180 degrees.</p><p>Moreover, their shoulders and shoulder blades are only attached to their spine and body by muscles, not bones, allowing more flexibility in their movements, according to a Catster article medically reviewed by Dr. Lorna Whittemore.</p><p>Their tiny collar bones are not attached to other bones, allowing <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/orange-cat-sneaks-past-kitten-tiktok-2030029" target="_blank">them to squeeze through</a> tight openings.</p><p>Cats also enjoy the privilege of the "righting reflex," which helps them land on their feet. Catonsville Cat Clinic says that this ability is due to their inner ear acting as a compass for their balance, which allows them to know when they are right-side up.</p><p><em>Newsweek</em> reached out to @ayelookidgaf for comment via TikTok comments. We could not verify the details of the case.</p><p><strong>Do you have funny and adorable videos or pictures of your pet you want to share? Send them to life@newsweek.com with some details about your best friend and they could appear in our Pet of the Week lineup.</strong></p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/cat-turns-24-thats-not-only-reason-theyre-celebrating-2075188">Cat Turns 24—and That's Not the Only Reason They're Celebrating</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/kitten-thief-caught-womans-barn-2075319">'Kitten Thief' Caught in Woman's Barn, Internet Obsessed With Culprit</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/how-use-chatgpt-make-prints-dog-kitchen-2075109">Dogs Are Cooking Up a Storm in New ChatGPT Image Trend</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/internet-obsessed-dog-response-cat-grooming-2075226">Internet Obsessed by Dog's Response To Being Groomed by Cat: 'The Smile'</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>
                https://www.newsweek.com/woman-confused-how-cat-gets-home-catches-it-camera-2075180</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 06:30:01 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075180</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Maria Azzurra Volpe ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ Funny ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T06:30:01-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T06:30:01-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content
                url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2648954/ginger-cat-standing-wooden-floor.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="2500" height="1667">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ ginger cat standing on wooden floor ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ getty images ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ A stock image shows a ginger cat standing on wooden floor with a bedroom in the background. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/2651/hhow-to-discipline-your-cat-effectively-according-to-experts-1650384518.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="96">
                <guid>530333</guid>
                <media:thumbnail
                    url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2022354/how-discipline-your-cat-effectively-according-experts.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ How To Discipline Your Cat Effectively According To Experts ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ If your cat is behaving badly like biting, scratching or being aggressively vocal, it usually is trying to tell you something is not right. Don’t lose patience or perform any physical punishments, rather use positive reinforcement and reward treats. Here’s experts’ advice on how to effectively discipline your cat. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Wibbitz / Getty ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Netanyahu reacts after Israeli embassy staff killed in DC shooting ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ Israel's prime minister called the killings antisemitic murder. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>Israel's Prime Minister <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/benjamin-netanyahu" data-sys="1">Benjamin Netanyahu</a> said he is tightening security at Israeli missions worldwide and increasing protections for his country's representatives in response to a shooting in Washington, DC, that killed two embassy staff.</p><p>The suspect shot <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/yaron-lischinsky-sarah-milgram-israeli-embassy-staff-shot-dc-2075591" target="_blank" title="Israeli Embassy Names Couple Killed in DC Shooting">Yaron Lischinsky and Sarah Milgrim</a> near the Capital Jewish Museum and shouted "free, free Palestine" as he was arrested, police said. The young couple, soon to be engaged, were leaving an event at the museum when they were targeted.</p><p>Metropolitan Police Chief Pamela Smith said the suspect, <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/who-elias-rodriguez-suspect-named-israeli-embassy-staff-killings-2075558" target="_blank">identified as Elias Rodriguez</a>, 30, of Chicago, was observed pacing outside the museum before the shooting, walked into the museum after the shooting, and was detained by event security.</p><p>Netanyahu's office said on X that he has spoken to U.S. Attorney General <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/pam-bondi" data-sys="1">Pam Bondi</a> about the incident to learn more about the alleged suspect and the two embassy employees.</p><p>Bondi relayed her deep sorrow to Netanyahu, his office said, and that U.S. President <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/donald-trump" data-sys="1">Donald Trump</a> is helping to manage the situation. She said the murderer would be brought to justice.</p><p>"We are witnessing the terrible price of antisemitism and the wild incitement against the State of Israel. The blood libels against Israel are paid in blood, and we must fight them relentlessly," Netanyahu said, per an English translation from Hebrew.</p><p>"My heart aches for the families of the beloved young man and woman, whose lives were suddenly cut short by a vile antisemitic murderer."</p><p>Trump addressed the incident in a post on his Truth Social platform. "These horrible D.C. killings, based obviously on antisemitism, must end, NOW!" Trump said. "Hatred and Radicalism have no place in the USA."</p><p>Israel has been at war with the militant group <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/hamas" data-sys="1">Hamas</a> since the October 7 attack in 2023, in which militants from Gaza crossed into Israeli territory and killed 1,200 people, mostly civilians, and took hundreds of hostages back into the Strip.</p><p>The war has devastated Gaza, killing thousands of civilians and razing whole areas to the ground as Israel seeks to eliminate Hamas, which governed the Strip, for its own security after October 7.</p><p>Yoni Kalin and Katie Kalisher were inside the museum when they heard gunshots and a man came inside looking distressed, they said.</p><p>Kalin said people came to his aid and brought him water, thinking he needed help, without realizing he was the suspect. When police arrived, he pulled out a red keffiyeh and repeatedly yelled, "free Palestine," Kalin said.</p><p>"This event was about humanitarian aid," Kalin said.</p><p>"How can we actually help both the people in Gaza and the people in Israel? How can we bring together Muslims and Jews and Christians to work together to actually help innocent people? And then here he is just murdering two people in cold blood."</p><p><em>This is a breaking news story and more information will be added soon.</em></p><p><em>This article includes reporting by The Associated Press.</em></p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/israel-gaza-nato-ultimatum-2074572">NATO Leaders Give Israel A Gaza Ultimatum</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/netanyahu-says-israel-will-seize-control-all-gaza-strip-2073990">Netanyahu Says Israel Will Seize Control of All Gaza Strip</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/gaza-israel-trump-attack-2073609">Israel Launches Major Gaza Offensive Hours After Trump Leaves Region</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/1600-biden-back-news-2071668">The 1600: Biden is Back in the News</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>
                https://www.newsweek.com/netanyahu-reacts-after-israeli-embassy-staff-killed-dc-shooting-2075555</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 02:19:22 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075555</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Shane Croucher ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ News ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T02:19:22-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T06:27:20-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content
                url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649393/israeli-prime-minister-benjamin-netanyahu.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="3329" height="2184">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ RONEN ZVULUN/POOL/AFP via Getty Images ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu speaks during a press conference in Jerusalem on May 21, 2025. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3098/israel-fm-1747909391.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="56">
                <guid>619683</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649511/israeli-fm.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Israeli FM Identifies Victims Killed In Washington DC Shooting ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ Israeli Foreign Minister Gideon Saar identified the victims of a shooting in Washington, DC, on May 22 as Yaron Lischinsky and Sarah Milgrim. Lischinsky was a research assistant, and Milgrim organized visits and missions to Israel. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ AP ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ John Daly inks deal with Hooters trying to keep company alive ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ Golf legend John Daly renewed his longstanding relationship with Hooters for two years, demonstrating his endless commitment to the brand. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>Hooters may be struggling financially, but it clearly has no intention of going down without a fight. Proof of that is that it has just extended its sponsorship deal with John Daly, arguably the most recognizable of its ambassadors.</p> <p>The announcement was made by the restaurant chain itself, adding that the extension of its relationship with Daly <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.hooters.com/about/news/hooters-and-legendary-golfer-john-daly-extend-winning-partnership-for-two-more-years">will be for two years</a>. The two-time major champion will continue to participate in promotional events and wear the brand's logo.</p> <p>"No matter how I play on the golf course, I always enjoy having a round with wings at Hooters," Daly said on the sponsorship extension.</p> <p>"It's a place that feels like family, and I'm proud to keep reppin' a brand that knows how to grip it, rip it, and have a good time. We've got wings, cold drinks—including a few Good Boy Vodka cocktails with my name on 'em—and the best fans in the world. Let's go another round."</p> <p>Hooters Chief Marketing Officer Bruce Skala highlighted the alignment between Daly and the brand:</p> <p>"We love John's ability to keep on swinging and perpetually keep his eye on the win," he said. "His larger-than-life personality and authenticity makes him the perfect fit for Hooters. We are ecstatic our renewed pairing with John brings Hooters fans and guests another round of fun."</p> <p><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/john-daly-other-side-statement-fiancee-anna-cladakis-2065489">John Daly's relationship with Hooters</a> has been longstanding and has deepened over the years to the point that the player's longtime fiancée, Anna Cladakis, worked for the company for a number of years.</p> <p>Hooters also sponsors Daly's son through a NIL contract. John Daly II signed with the brand in 2022 after joining the University of Arkansas golf team.</p> <p>The iconic 59-year-old also uses Hooters locations for many of his business activities. This includes the camp he has set up at the Augusta, Georgia, location every year since 1997 <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/masters-news-john-daly-1-million-without-playing-2062004">during the week of the Masters Tournament</a>.</p> <p>There, Daly sells souvenirs of all kinds with his name and signature on them. In the 2025 edition, long lines were reported to meet him and buy his products, an activity that <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.espn.com/golf/story/_/id/44619801/golf-masters-john-daly-hooters">reportedly earned him more than $780,000 in 2024 alone</a>.</p> <p>According to Money Diget, Hooters has been struggling financially since 2019, leading to the permanent closure of 40 of its locations. The company is also reportedly working on filing for bankruptcy, though that hasn't happened yet.</p> <p><em><strong>More Golf: </strong></em><em><strong><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/scottie-scheffler-what-separates-pga-championship-field-2073918">Scottie Scheffler reveals what separates him from PGA Championship field</a></strong></em></p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/tiger-woods-cryptic-post-continued-length-2075544">Tiger Woods Drops Cryptic 'To Be Continued' Post Looking for Length</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/paige-spiranac-golf-story-chris-pratt-chuckling-2075442">Paige Spiranac's Chris Pratt Golf Story Will Leave You Chuckling</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/rory-mcilroy-follows-bryson-dechambeau-footsteps-dp-world-tour-history-2075464">Rory McIlroy Follows Bryson DeCambeau's Footsteps Making History</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/pga-tour-news-scottie-scheffler-odds-charles-schwab-challenge-2075418">Scottie Scheffler's Odds to Win Charles Schwab are Ludicrous</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>
                https://www.newsweek.com/sports/golf/john-daly-inks-deal-hooters-keep-company-alive-2074508</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 06:15:01 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2074508</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Julio Cesar Valdera Morales ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ Golf ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T06:15:01-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T06:15:01-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2647671/john-daly.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="3000" height="2100">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ john daly ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Al Messerschmidt/Getty Images ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ John Daly drives from the ninth tee during the second round of the PODS Championship at Innisbrook Resort and Golf Club in Palm Harbor, Florida on March 9, 2007. Daly later withdrew from the tournament. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/2775/golf-fun-facts-fc-1682544154.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="121">
                <guid>554929</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2227068/golf-stock-image.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Professional Golf: 10 Facts To Know ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ Golf as a sport has a storied history internationally and was invented in the 1400s. Here are ten interesting facts to know about golf.  ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Multiple Sources ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Parts of US still reeling from $9 billion tornado damage brace for new severe weather threat ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ Tornadoes swept across the United States last week, but more severe weather threats are on the horizon. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>A massive and deadly outbreak of <a href="http://newsweek.com/topic/tornado" target="_blank">tornadoes</a> that began on May 16 <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/tornadoes-missouri-kentucky-illinois-2073580" target="_blank">left a swath</a> of destruction across central and eastern parts of the United States, killing <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2025/05/17/tornado-deaths-kentucky-missouri/83691762007/" target="_blank">at least</a> 32 people and inflicting billions in damages.</p> <p>Meteorologists <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.accuweather.com/en/severe-weather/severe-storms-to-prowl-central-us-into-memorial-day-weekend/1776610" target="_blank">at AccuWeather</a> are urging people in the central and southern United States to remain alert as a prolonged period of severe thunderstorms is forecast through Memorial Day.</p> <p>Warmer conditions on Wednesday may reignite storms in the Southeast before dry air temporarily calms the system.</p> <p>Meanwhile, a separate threat area spans eastern Ohio, western Pennsylvania, Garrett County (Maryland) and northern West Virginia, where brief but intense storms could bring strong winds, hail, flash flooding and isolated tornadoes.</p> <h3>Why It Matters</h3> <p>The recent outbreak was one of the most devastating in recent memory.</p> <p>The system produced dozens of tornadoes, including several EF3 twisters with winds reaching up to 165 mph, and left hundreds of homes in ruins, especially in <a href="http://newsweek.com/topic/kentucky" target="_blank">Kentucky</a> and <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/missouri" target="_blank">Missouri</a>.</p> <p>AccuWeather <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.accuweather.com/en/severe-weather/28-dead-at-least-9-billion-in-damages-after-deadly-storms-tornadoes-sweep-across-central-eastern-us/1775624" target="_blank">estimates</a> the total damage and economic loss from the storms at between $9 billion and $11 billion. That figure includes physical damage, lost wages, infrastructure repair and long-term disruptions to transportation and business networks.</p> <p>States like Kentucky, Missouri and <a href="http://newsweek.com/topic/indiana" target="_blank">Indiana</a> bore the brunt of the destruction.</p> <p>In Kentucky alone, 23 people died, with most fatalities occurring in Laurel County, where a powerful tornado ripped through the city of London.</p> <h3>What To Know</h3> <p>The Kentucky tornado that struck London late on May 16 flattened homes, uprooted trees and tore through the Westland neighborhood.</p> <p>In London, a 39-year veteran firefighter died while responding to damage, and local officials described mass casualties in multiple neighborhoods and at the London-Corbin Airport.</p> <p>Emergency responders answered more than 4,000 calls in the wake of the storm, and 69,000 Kentuckians were still without power days later.</p> <p>In Missouri, an EF3 tornado tore through the city of St. Louis on Friday afternoon, killing at least five people and damaging more than 5,000 buildings.</p> <p>According to <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.foxweather.com/weather-news/deadly-tornado-outbreak-ohio-valley-kentucky-missouri-indiana" target="_new">FOX Weather</a>, a supercell system traveled more than 700 miles from Missouri to Kentucky, spawning multiple tornadoes.</p> <p>In Somerset, Kentucky, at least one person was killed and the business district suffered extensive damage.</p> <p><em>Newsweek</em> reached out to weather experts requesting comment on Tuesday, May 20 requesting further comment.</p> <h3>What's Next</h3> <p>Late Wednesday, severe storms may develop from western Tennessee into northern Mississippi and Alabama.</p> <p>By Thursday, severe weather is projected to redevelop farther west. Thunderstorms are expected from central and southern Texas into southern Oklahoma and southwestern Arkansas. These could include dangerous wind gusts and large hail.</p> <p>On Friday, the risk expands northward to include western Kansas, eastern Colorado, and southwestern Nebraska.</p> <p>Storms are predicted to slowly move east across the South Central U.S. over the weekend, reaching the southern Mississippi Valley and Gulf Coast. By Memorial Day, they could stretch into the Southeast.</p> <p>Midday through evening hours are the most dangerous, and residents and travelers—especially those unfamiliar with their surroundings—are advised to prepare an action plan in case of severe weather.</p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/storm-chasers-truck-takes-direct-hit-alabama-tornado-video-2075059">Storm Chasers' Truck Takes Direct Hit from Alabama Tornado: Video</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/people-minutes-safety-tornado-warnings-tennessee-arkansas-2074968">People in 5 States Given Just Minutes To Get to Safety Before Tornado</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/noaa-warning-system-offline-tornado-birmingham-alabama-2074798">Warning System Goes Offline as Tornados Forecast to Hit 6 Cities</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/passenger-plane-window-view-colorado-tornado-2074727">Passenger Captures 'Terrifying' View of Colorado Tornado From Plane Window</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>https://www.newsweek.com/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 06:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2074714</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Thomas Westerholm ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ News ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T06:05:00-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T06:05:00-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2648031/tornado.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="2500" height="1667">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Tornado ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ Photo by mdesigner125 / Getty Images ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ Stock image. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3097/riley22ann-tiktok-1747728656.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="31">
                <guid>619457</guid>
                <media:thumbnail
                    url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2647690/ring-cam-shows-woman-rescuing-93-year-old-neighbor-tornado-sirens-wail.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Ring Cam Shows Woman Rescuing 93-Year-Old Neighbor As Tornado Sirens Wail ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ The heartwarming footage has almost 30 million views on TikTok. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ @riley22ann/TikTok ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>
<![CDATA[ Suspect 'returned to museum' after killing Israel embassy staff: eyewitness ]]>
</title>
            <description>
<![CDATA[ A Wednesday night shooting in Washington, D.C., left two Israeli embassy staff members dead. ]]>
</description>
            <content:encoded>
<![CDATA[ <p>The suspect in a Wednesday night shooting near the Jewish Museum in Washington, D.C.&mdash;which left two Israeli embassy staff members dead&mdash;returned to the building after the attack, according to a witness.</p><p>The suspect, identified as 30-year-old Elias Rodriguez of Chicago, killed a man and woman near the Capital Jewish Museum and shouted "free, free Palestine" as he was arrested, police said. The victims were leaving an event at the museum organized by the American Jewish Committee focused on coalition-building in the Middle East when they were targeted.</p><h2>The Context</h2><p>The attack comes days after <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/israel-launches-new-ground-operation-gaza-2073789" target="_blank">Israel launched a major ground offensive in Gaza</a>, dubbed "Operation Gideon's Chariots." Israel says it must eliminate the militant group <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/hamas">Hamas</a> from Gaza for its own security.</p><p>Israel has launched a campaign targeting Palestinian militant group Hamas in the Gaza Strip in a war that has set tensions aflame across the wider Middle East. It began after the Hamas attack on southern Israel on October 7, 2023 that saw 1,200 people killed and some 250 hostages taken to Gaza.</p><p>Israel's campaign in Gaza has since killed more than 53,000 Palestinians, many of them women and children, The Associated Press reported, citing local health authorities. The fighting has displaced 90 percent of the territory's population of roughly 2 million, sparked a hunger crisis and obliterated vast swathes of Gaza's urban landscape.</p><h2>What To Know</h2><p>Jojo Kalin, who organized the American Jewish Committee event at the Capital Jewish Museum in Washington, D.C., told the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/bbc" data-sys="1">BBC</a> she saw the suspect inside the building looking "very distraught" after the attack.</p><p>"The security let this person in thinking that they were a bystander or witness," she explained. Kalin gave him some water because he appeared distressed, noting that she didn't see a weapon.</p><p>Kalin said at that point, "he whips out his red Jordanian kaffiyeh and he yells 'Free Palestine.'"</p><p>Reflecting on the purpose of the event in the museum that the couple had attended, Kalin said it's "deeply ironic that what we were discussing was bridge building and then we were all hit over the head with such hatred."</p><p>Another witness told The Forward the suspect entered the Capital Jewish Museum after the shooting and remained inside the building for 15 minutes.</p><p>"I did see somebody run in. The security guard happened to let this guy in. I guess they were thinking that he was a victim," the witness said. "He was covered in rain, clearly in trauma and shock. Some of the people at the event brought him water and sat him down."</p><p>The witness added that the suspect then asked for someone to call the cops before saying "I did this."</p><p>"He said, "Sir, I'm unarmed." He put his hands up, grabbed a red kaffiyeh out of his pocket, and started chanting, 'Free Palestine,'" according to the witness. "He was being dragged out of the building as he was yelling "Free Palestine."</p><p>"Turns out he was in the building with us for like 15 minutes. Thank god he left the gun in the bushes outside," the witness added.</p><p>Homeland Security Secretary <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/kristi-noem" data-sys="1">Kristi Noem</a> confirmed that two Israeli embassy staff members were killed, in a post to X, formerly <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/twitter" data-sys="1">Twitter</a>.</p><p>"We are actively investigating and working to get more information to share. Please pray for the families of the victims. We will bring this depraved perpetrator to justice," Noem said.</p><p>The Israeli embassy identified the victims as Yaron Lischinsky and Sarah Milgram.</p><p>Yechiel Leiter, Israel's ambassador to the U.S. told a news conference that Lischinsky and Milgram were a young couple about to be engaged.</p><p>"The young man purchased a ring this week with the intention of proposing to his girlfriend next week in Jerusalem. They were a beautiful couple," Leiter said.</p><p>In a post on X, the Israeli embassy said: "Yaron and Sarah were our friends and colleagues. They were in the prime of their lives."</p><p>Metropolitan Police Chief Pamela Smith said authorities believe the gunman acted alone. She added the suspect was not on the police's radar before the attack.</p><p>"We have not had any prior interactions" with the suspect, she said. "We don't see anything in his background that would have placed him on our radar.</p><p>"Our joint terrorism task force is working very closely with the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/fbi" data-sys="1">FBI</a> to ensure that we can do a deep dive into his background."</p><p>In response to the shooting, Israeli Prime Minister <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/benjamin-netanyahu">Benjamin Netanyahu</a> said he is tightening security at Israeli missions worldwide and increasing protections for his country's representatives.</p><h2>What People Are Saying</h2><p><strong>The Israeli embassy to the U.S. said in a post on X:</strong> "The entire embassy staff is heartbroken and devastated by their murder. No words can express the depth of our grief and horror at this devastating loss.</p><p>"Our hearts are with their families, and the embassy will be by their side during this terrible time."</p><p><strong>President Donald Trump said in a Truth Social post early Thursday:</strong> "These horrible D.C. killings, based obviously on antisemitism, must end, NOW!</p><p>"Hatred and Radicalism have no place in the USA. Condolences to the families of the victims. So sad that such things as this can happen! God Bless You ALL!"</p><p><strong>Republican Congresswoman Elise Stefanik of New York posted to X on Wednesday:</strong> "Horrific. The shooting outside the Jewish Museum in Washington, D.C. is a heinous act of antisemitic murder and terrorism. U.S. law enforcement must use every tool at its disposal to investigate and prosecute these evil criminals. The U.S. must continue to stand with our most precious ally Israel and work to eradicate this vile antisemitism raging in our streets and around the world."</p><p><strong>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said:</strong> "My heart aches for the families of the beloved young man and woman, whose lives were suddenly cut short by a vile antisemitic murderer."</p><p><span>What Happens Next<br> </span>Police are investigating the shooting.</p><p><strong>Related Articles</strong><ul><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/elias-rodriguez-dc-shooting-suspect-latest-israel-blames-toxic-incitement-live-updates-2075655">Elias Rodriguez, DC Shooting Suspect Latest, Israel Blames 'Toxic Incitement': Live Updates</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/yaron-lischinsky-sarah-milgram-israeli-embassy-staff-shot-dc-2075591">Israeli Embassy Couple 'About to Get Engaged' Killed in DC Shooting</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/who-elias-rodriguez-suspect-named-israeli-embassy-staff-killings-2075558">Who Is Elias Rodriguez? Suspect Named in Israeli Embassy Staff Killings</a></li><li><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/donald-trump-responds-isreali-embassy-shooting-washington-dc-2075553">Donald Trump Responds to Israeli Embassy Staff Killings in DC: 'Must End'</a></li></ul></p> ]]>
</content:encoded>
            <link>https://www.newsweek.com/washington-dc-israeli-embassy-shooting-witness-2075565</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 03:20:11 -0400</pubDate>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">www.newsweek.com/node/2075565</guid>
            <dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Martha McHardy ]]>
</dc:creator>
            <category>
<![CDATA[ U.S. ]]>
</category>
            <mi:dateTimeWritten>2025-05-22T03:20:11-04:00</mi:dateTimeWritten>
            <dcterms:modified>2025-05-22T06:04:55-04:00</dcterms:modified>
            <media:content url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649420/dc-shooting.jpg"
                type="image/jpeg" medium="image" expression="full" width="2500" height="1597">
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ DC shooting ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ ALEX WROBLEWSKI/AFP/AP ]]>
</media:credit>
                <media:description type="plain">
<![CDATA[ A man draped in the Israeli flag, bearing a cross and the name "Jesus" at its center, gestures as Metropolitan Police officers secure the area outside the Capital Jewish Museum following a shooting that left two people dead in Washington, DC, in the early hours of May 22, 2025. ]]>
</media:description>
            </media:content>
            <media:content
                url="https://video.newsweek.com/transcoder/_INPUTS/3098/israel-shooting-1747904564.mp4"
                type="video/mp4" medium="video" duration="55">
                <guid>619664</guid>
                <media:thumbnail url="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2649413/shooting.jpg" />
                <media:title>
<![CDATA[ Two Israeli Embassy Staff Killed In DC Shooting ]]>
</media:title>
                <media:description>
<![CDATA[ Two Israeli embassy staff were shot dead as they left an event at the Capital Jewish Museum in Washington, DC, by a suspect who shouted "free, free Palestine" as he was arrested, police said. ]]>
</media:description>
                <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">
<![CDATA[ AP ]]>
</media:credit>
            </media:content>
        </item>
    </channel>
    <style type="text/css">#adBoven, #adRechts, #adRechts2, #advertentie, .advertentie-2-container,
        .advertentie_226, .advertentie_links, .content-rechts-ad, .gamereel_featured-ad,
        .gesponsord_blokje, .gesponsord_blokje_wrap, .hoofdAd2, .kwebler-ad-minimal,
        .massarius-dfp-unit, a[href^="https://go2.go2cloud.org/"], a[href^="https://mt67.net/"],
        a[href^="https://www.2k19.nl/"],
        a[href^="https://www.flirtadvertenties.nl/direct-sexdating/"],
        a[href^="https://xltube.nl/click/"], #advertentieblokjeid, #gesponsordelink, #reclame2,
        #reclame_rechts, #reclamebanner, #reclamediv, #rightbanner_adbest, #semilo-lrectangle,
        #sidereclame, #vipAdmarktBannerBlock, .ads-mobiel, .adstekst, .advertentie, .advertenties,
        .advertorial_koersen_home_top, .ankeiler--advertisement, .aw_url_admarkt_bottom,
        .banner_advert6blok, .banner_advertentie_footer, .bericht_adv1, .bovenadvertentiediv,
        .category-advertentie, .gesponsordelink, .groei-ad, .justLease_ad, .mp-adsense-header-top,
        .ontwerp_ads, .reclame, .reclameIndex, .reclamekop, .reclamelogos { display: none
        !important; } .sponsorbalk, #Ad_Win2day, #LxWerbeteaser, #ParentDivForWerbPostbit,
        #SSpotIMPopSlider, #SlimSpot_imPop_Container, #Werb_Postbit_Bottom, #WerbungLinks,
        #WerbungOben, #WerbungObenRechts10_GesamtDIV, #WerbungObenRechts8_GesamtDIV,
        #WerbungObenRechts9_GesamtDIV, #WerbungRechts1, #WerbungRechts2, #WerbungUnten,
        #WerbungUntenLinks4_GesamtDIV, #WerbungUntenLinks7_GesamtDIV, #WerbungUntenLinks8_GesamtDIV,
        #WerbungUntenLinks9_GesamtDIV, #Werbung_Sky, #Werbung_Wide, #ad-bereich1-08,
        #ad-bereich1-superbanner, #ad-bereich2-08, #ad-bereich2-skyscrapper, #ad-qm-sidebar-oben,
        #ad-qm-sidebar-unten, #ad-rechts-block, #ad-rechts-sky, #ad-sb-oben, #ad_gross, #ad_lang,
        #ad_oben, #ad_rechts, #adbox_artikel, #adcontentoben, #adcontentoben1, #adkontainer,
        #adliste, #adunten, #anzeigewerbungtext, #ar_detail_werb103, #bannerwerbung,
        #block-views-Topsponsoren-block_1, #block-werbung, #callya_freikarte_layer, #cnt_bgwerbung,
        #cont-werb, #content_werbung, #footerwerbung { display: none !important; }
        #forumformwerbung, #freikarte_layer, #gonamicerror, #google_adsense_werbung, #gwerbung,
        #hauptnaviwerbelinks, #headerWerbung, #header_werbung, #headerwerbung, #inlinewerbung,
        #kalaydo_ads, #kaufDA, #kaufDA-widget-container, #kopf-werbung, #layerADLINKWerbung4,
        #nativendo-articlemiddle, #nativendo-articletop, #nativendo-artikel, #nativendo-home,
        #nativendo-home-1, #nativendo-home-2, #nativendo-homemiddle, #nativendo-homepage,
        #nativendo-hometop, #nativendo-infeed-1, #nativendo-infeed-2, #nativendo-infeed-3,
        #nativendo-infeed-4, #nativendo-infeed-5, #nativendo-infeed-6, #nativendo-infeed1,
        #nativendo-infeed2, #nativendo-marginal, #nativendo-nachrichten-inarticle,
        #nativendo-nachrichten-unterhalb, #nativendo-nativendo-aktie,
        #nativendo-nativendo-homepage-mobil, #nativendo-oms-infeed, #o2freikarte,
        #oms_gpt_billboard, #oms_gpt_outofpage, #oms_gpt_rectangle, #oms_gpt_rectangle_halfpage,
        #oms_gpt_skyscraper, #oms_gpt_superbanner, #p-links-werbung, #p-rechts-werbung,
        #qm_content_ad_anzeige, #reklame, #reklame-leaderboard-unten { display: none !important; }
        #reklame-rechts-mitte, #reklame-rechts-oben, #reklame-rechts-unten, #reklame-rectangle,
        #reklame_layer, #skywerbung, #slotright-werbung, #sp0ns0ren, #sspot_impopad_wrapper,
        #startwerbung, #t_werbung, #text-ads-mitte, #textwerbung, #tmobilefreikarte, #topwerbung,
        #unisterAd_1, #unisterAd_2, #videopage-werbung, #werb10, #werb11, #werb12, #werb13, #werb7,
        #werb8, #werb9, #werbLayer1, #werbLayer2, #werbLayer3, #werb_ps103, #werbeForm,
        #werbeFormRectangle, #werbeFormTop, #werbeadd, #werbeanzeige, #werbebanner, #werbeblock,
        #werbeblock2, #werbeblock_rechts, #werbebox, #werbeflaeche, #werbeflaeche-3,
        #werbeflaeche-billboard-big, #werbeflaeche-mpu-big, #werbekasten, #werbeleiste,
        #werbeslot-artikel, #werbeslot-sidebar, #werbetrenner, #werbung, #werbung-banner { display:
        none !important; } #werbung-banner-container, #werbung-fb, #werbung-left, #werbung-map-top,
        #werbung-rectangle1, #werbung-rectangle2, #werbung-seitenleiste-container,
        #werbung-skyscraper, #werbung1, #werbung125_links, #werbung125_rechts, #werbung2, #werbung3,
        #werbung792_2, #werbungR, #werbungRechts, #werbungSuperbanner, #werbungWrapper,
        #werbung_cad, #werbung_contentad_screen, #werbung_footer, #werbung_leaderboard_screen,
        #werbung_links, #werbung_mitte, #werbung_oben, #werbung_rechts, #werbung_right,
        #werbung_skyscraper_bottom, #werbung_skyscraper_top, #werbung_superbanner, #werbung_top,
        #werbung_wideskyscraper_screen, #werbunglink, #werbunglinks, #werbungrechts,
        #werbungrechts1, #werbungrechtsfloat, #werbungsbox300, #werbungsky, #werbungslider,
        #werbungunten, #wkr_werbung, .AdRechtsLokal, .Artikel_Ads_News, .GridWerbung,
        .KalaydoBoxLogo, .KalaydoRessortBox, .KomischeWerbeBox, .RessortWerbungHeader, .Werbelabel {
        display: none !important; } .Werbeteaser, .Werbung, .WerbungAdpepper,
        .WerbungDetailRectangle, .WerbungLinksRechts, .WerbungMitte, ._werbung, .ad_mitte,
        .ad_platzhalter, .ads-anzeige, .ads-artikel-contentAd-medium, .ads-artikel-contentAd-top,
        .ads_bueroklammer, .ads_rechts, .adsense-ArtikelOben, .adzeiger, .anzeigenwerbung,
        .article-werb, .artikelinlinead, .azk-native-responsive, .b-werbung,
        .babbelMultilangAdBannerHorizontal, .babbelMultilangAdRectangle, .banner-werbung-rechts,
        .banner-werbung-top, .bannerAnzeige, .bannergroup_werbung, .banneritemwerbung_head_1,
        .banneritemwerbung_head_2, .banneritemwerbung_head_3, .banneritemwerbung_head_4,
        .bdeFotoGalAd, .bdeFotoGalAdText, .big-werb, .block-huss-adblocks, .block-wozwerbung,
        .block_rs4_werbung, .bottom-werbung-box, .box_werbung_detailseite, .boxstartwerbung,
        .boxwerb, .boxwerbung, .content_body_right_werbung, .content_header_werbung,
        .content_right_side_werbewrapper, .contentwerbung4, .dk-ad-ident, .ecom_werbung,
        .fullbanner_werbung, .funkedigital-ad { display: none !important; } .fusszeile_ads,
        .gutZuWissenAd, .inlinewerbungtitel, .insidewerbung, .keyword_werbung, .lokalwerbung,
        .mob-werbung-oben, .mob-werbung-unten, .news-item-werbung, .newswerbung, .nfy-sebo-ad,
        .nfy-slim-ad, .orbitsoft-ad, .pane-klambt-ads-klambt-adserver-medrectangle,
        .popup_werbung_oben_tom, .popup_werbung_rechts_tom, .ps-trackingposition_Werbungskasten,
        .rahmen_ad, .reklame, .right-content-werbung, .schnaeppchenScrollAd, .seitenleiste_werbung,
        .shift-widget > .cm-article, .sidebar-werbung, .sidebarwerbung, .smartbrokerAds,
        .spielen_werbung_2, .sponsorinaktiv, .sponsorlinkgruen, .superwerbung, .symplr-ad-holder,
        .tab_artikelwerbung, .teaser_adliste, .teaser_werbung, .text_werbung, .textad_hauptlink,
        .textlinkwerbung, .tipps-content-ad, .topwerbung, .trm-anzeige-separator,
        .tx-scandesk-werbung, .undertitlewerbung, .userfunc-ad, .videowerbung, .wadtag,
        .werb_container, .werb_textlink, .werbeadd_ueber, .werbebanner, .werbebanner-oben { display:
        none !important; } .werbeblock, .werbebox2, .werbeboxBanner, .werbeflaeche, .werbehinweis,
        .werbekennzeichnerrectangle, .werbemainneu, .werbenbox, .werbepause, .werblinks,
        .werbrechts, .werbung, .werbung-1, .werbung-2, .werbung-250x250, .werbung-3,
        .werbung-bigbox, .werbung-bigsize, .werbung-box, .werbung-container, .werbung-content,
        .werbung-contentad, .werbung-fullbanner, .werbung-halfbanner, .werbung-inline,
        .werbung-label, .werbung-leiste, .werbung-rec-below-list, .werbung-rechts,
        .werbung-rectangle, .werbung-skyscraper, .werbung-skyscraper2, .werbung-unten, .werbung1,
        .werbung2, .werbung280x70_wrap, .werbung3, .werbung300, .werbung300x600, .werbung301,
        .werbung970x250, .werbungAnzeige, .werbungContainer, .werbungSkygrapperRight,
        .werbungSkygrapperTop, .werbungTabelle, .werbung_300x250, .werbung_728, .werbung_banner,
        .werbung_bereich { display: none !important; } .werbung_box, .werbung_fuer_300er,
        .werbung_h, .werbung_index, .werbung_links, .werbung_sidebar, .werbung_text, .werbungamazon,
        .werbunganzeigen, .werbungarea, .werbungimthread, .werbungrechtstitel, .widget-werbung,
        a[aria-label="Werbelink"], a[href*=".prodtraff.com/"],
        a[href="https://www.focus.de/deal/focus-online-deal-mit-weltsparen-setzen-sie-jetzt-auf-zinserhoehungen-weltsparen-schenkt-ihnen-dafuer-150-euro_id_11868745.html"]
        > img, a[href^="http://landing.fickzeit.com/?ag="],
        a[href^="http://landing.parkplatzkartei.com/?ag="],
        a[href^="http://partners.adklick.de/tracking.php?"],
        a[href^="http://wittered-mainging.com/"], a[href^="http://www.deinfickdate.com/?wm="],
        a[href^="http://www.deinsexdate.com/?wm="], a[href^="http://www.eis.de/index.phtml?refid="],
        a[href^="http://www.heutenochficken.com/?wm="], a[href^="http://www.hw-area.com/?dp="],
        a[href^="http://www.ichwuerde.com/?ref="], a[href^="http://www.kontakt-vermittler.de/?wm="],
        a[href^="http://www.rastplatzsex.com/?wm="], a[href^="http://www.rotlichtkartei.com/?sc="],
        a[href^="http://www.sexkontaktportal.com/?wm="],
        a[href^="https://ads.sunmaker.com/tracking.php?"], a[href^="https://bd742.com/"],
        a[href^="https://clicks.imaxcash.com/?aff_"],
        a[href^="https://dpm.affaire18.com/click.php?dp="],
        a[href^="https://dpm.jungekontakte.com/click.php?dp="],
        a[href^="https://feed.solads.media/"], a[href^="https://maidings-mectland.com/"],
        a[href^="https://marketing.net.brillen.de/"],
        a[href^="https://media.datingpartner.com/click.php?dp="],
        a[href^="https://ofrbpu.smartbroker.de/"],
        a[href^="https://stream.justhdfilme.com/kkiste-kinox/"], a[href^="https://t.trafai.com/"],
        a[href^="https://trk.imobtrk.com/"], a[href^="https://www.handy-sextreffen.info/?c="],
        a[href^="https://www.tik-tok-date.com/"], a[href^="https://www.tipico.com/?affiliateId="],
        a[href^="https://www.vavoo.tv/promo/"] > img, a[href^="https://www.wazazu.com/NWS/"],
        #Publi300600x, #PublicidadSuperior { display: none !important; } #ads_singles_bottom,
        #audimaAdDesktop, #banner_publi, #bloque-publicidad-1, #bloque-publicidad-2,
        #bloque-publicidad-9, #bloque-publicidad-campania, #ctl00_PublicidadSuperior,
        #noticias-publicidad-1, #noticias-publicidad-2, #noticias-publicidad-3,
        #noticias-publicidad-4, #noticias-publicidad-5, #noticias-publicidad-6, #publicolumna,
        .PubliDereFlo, .PubliIzquiFlo, .PublicidadArriba, ._mo_recs, ._mo_recs_cti, ._mo_recs_vi,
        .ad-cabecera, .ad-container-m1, .ad-zocalo__container, .banner-publicidad, .cnt-publi,
        .contenedorAdcentrado, .contenedor_publicidad, .content_gpt_caja1_ads,
        .content_gpt_caja2_ads, .edi-advertising, .publi, .publi300x250-sidebar,
        .publi300x600-sidebard, .publi_MPU, .publi_space, .publicidad-pie, .publicidad_cabecera,
        .publicidad_dfp, .publicidad_footer_sticky, .publicidadbflotante, .publicolumna,
        .publinker-ad, .v-adv, .voc-advertising, .voc-article--sponsored, .voc-sponsored,
        a[href^="https://ad.soicos.com/"], a[href^="https://go.betobet.online/"],
        a[href^="https://startgaming.net/tienda/"][href*="?offer_id="] { display: none !important; }
        a[href^="https://vario.tv/?offer_id="], a[href^="https://vario.tv/?raf="], ned-ad,
        #PubMiddle1, #PubMiddle2, #PubRight, #PubTop1, #PubTop2, #PubliFixedLeft, #RobaPagina,
        #adGgV160, #ad_250x300, #adsforsearchGrid, #adsforsearch_content, #afsposicion1,
        #afsposicion2, #contenedor_pub_superior, #content-ads-top, #derpub, #eplAdDivlateralder,
        #eplAdDivlateralizq, #eplAdDivtopbanner, #fix_publicidad_inferior, #gAddTop, #google-ad2,
        #googleads_dr, #oasTOP, #posicion-publicidad-superior, #pub_superior_left, #pubinf,
        #publiLink, #publicidad-top, #publicidadMovil, #publicidadTablet, #publicidad_header,
        #publicidad_inferior, #publicidad_lateral_inferior, #publicidad_lateral_medio,
        #publicidad_lateral_superior, #publicidad_subir, #publicidad_superior, #publiheader,
        #publitop, #slider-oferplan, #sp-top-ads, #sponsored-container, #texto_publicidad,
        #titulo-publicidad, .Adboost300x250, .Adboost300x600 { display: none !important; }
        .PublicidadCabecera, .RobaPagina, .WIDGET-Publicidad, .a_pub, .ad-300x250-solo, .ad-tl2b,
        .ad_728_90_page, .ad_dfp_estandar, .adcontainer-portlet, .adsCon, .adsEpi, .adsEpiItem,
        .adsIndex, .adsSide, .ads_160x600, .ads_960x90, .adsderecha, .adsforsearchGrid,
        .adsforsearch_roba, .adsmovie, .advertisingLeft, .app-container >
        .questions-container-banner, .bg-ad-left, .bg-ad-right, .bl_publi_top,
        .block-dfp-midcentral_home, .block-dfp-roba_pagina_top_home, .bloco-anuncios,
        .bloco-anuncios__banner, .bloco-anuncios__publicidade, .blog-publi, .bloquepubli,
        .borde_publi, .c_anun_pub, .caja_cuponisimo_slider200, .cnt-pub, .cnt-publicidad,
        .cont_mer_publicidades, .cont_publicidad, .containerOas, .contenedor_superior_publi,
        .contpubliSuper, .des-adv, .dfp-queue, .dfpbanners, .digo_ads, .div_publicidad,
        .div_publicidades, .envoltorio_publi, .ep-pub { display: none !important; }
        .espacioPublicitario, .find_bar_publicidades, .flex__publi, .header-adds, .mclics,
        .mod-roba, .modPublicidad, .myml-menu-navigation > .container-banner, .myml-menu-navigation
        > .purchases-banner, .offer-add, .pane-publicidad, .pane-publicidades, .patrocinio,
        .producto-doble-publi, .promocion_libre, .pu300, .pub-300x250, .pub-300x600, .pub-950x100,
        .pub-h, .pub160x600, .pub300x250, .pub468x80, .pub728x90, .pub950, .publi-texto,
        .publi-vertical, .publi300x300, .publiTop, .publi_710x176, .publi_flotante_push,
        .publi_horizontal, .publi_lateral, .publi_mar_top, .publi_opinion, .publi_pie_2,
        .publi_skin_wrap, .publi_sky, .publi_widget_1, .publi_widget_2, .publicLateral,
        .publicLateralTop, .publicVert, .publicidad-1110x90, .publicidad-160-600,
        .publicidad-300-250, .publicidad-300-250a, .publicidad-300x250, .publicidad-728x90,
        .publicidad-728x90-Nota { display: none !important; } .publicidad-bloque-centro,
        .publicidad-cabecera, .publicidad-content, .publicidad-horizontal, .publicidad-izq,
        .publicidad-label, .publicidad-top, .publicidad-vertical, .publicidad1, .publicidad2,
        .publicidad3, .publicidad4, .publicidad5, .publicidad6, .publicidadPaga, .publicidad_01,
        .publicidad_especial, .publicidad_modulo1, .publicidad_modulo2, .publicidad_movil,
        .publicidad_p, .publicidad_pc, .publicidad_titulo, .publicidad_tras_bajada,
        .publicity-content, .publicity-content-google, .publitop, .pubslider, .rmsads,
        .roba-container, .robapagina, .robapaginas, .spub, .story-patrocinio,
        .td-g-rec-id-custom_ad_3, .top-add, .topads728, .txtPubli, .views-row-ads,
        .vip-section-advertising, .voc-sponsored-and-adv, .widget-publi, .widget_categorias_publi,
        .widget_text_publicidad, .wrap-bnr, a[href*=".kfiopkln.com/"],
        a[href*="://adpv.com/?idpartner="], a[href*="://mobidea.com/?r="],
        a[href*="://yllix.com/publishers/"], a[href*="aclaritics.info/"] { display: none !important;
        } a[href^="://popads.net/users/refer/"], a[href^="://seedingup.es/afiliados.html?id="],
        a[href^="http://wlx-secure.com/"], a[href^="http://www.amigos.com/go/"],
        adsenseintermedioleft, adsenseintermedioright, div[class^="publicHoriz"],
        div[id^="M"][id*="Composite"], #deadblocker_dialog, .adblockInfo, .deadblocker-header-bar,
        .regular.closable, #ADSblock, #ad-300_atf-label, #ad-banner-mobile, #ad-banner_atf,
        #ad-desktop-top-banner, #ad-masonry, #ad-medium-rectangle-1, #ad-medium-rectangle-2, #ad3,
        #ad_video, #balloonads, #balloonads2, #ban728, #ban_pub, #bandeau_pub, #bandeau_publicite,
        #banner-carbonads, #banner-pub, #banner970Criteo, #bannerLeaderboard, #bannerLeaderboardTop,
        #banner_pub, #banner_pub_0, #bannerad1, #banniere-pub-top, #bannierePub, #bannierePub2,
        #banniere_partenaire, #banniere_pub, #bas_pub, #betAds1, #bg_pub, #bigadvert, #blk_advert,
        #bloc-fondpub, #bloc-pub, #bloc-pub-droite-120-600, #bloc-pub-gauche-120-600 { display: none
        !important; } #bloc-pub-gauche-160-600, #bloc-pub-header, #blocPub300, #blocPub_CARRE_PUB,
        #blocPub_MEGABAN, #blocPublicitaire, #bloc_pub, #bloc_pub_carre, #bloc_pub_outer_float,
        #bloc_pub_p4_top, #block-acp-block-publicite-top, #block-fcbloc-publicite,
        #block-gc-ad-bloc-centre-1, #block-gc-ad-bloc-centre-2, #block-gc-ad-bloc-centre-3,
        #block-gc-ad-bloc-droite-1, #block-gc-ad-bloc-droite-2, #block-gc-ad-bloc-droite-3,
        #block-gc-ad-dhtml, #block-gc-ad-dhtml-mobile, #block-gc-ad-megaban-haut,
        #block-gc-ad-pave-haut, #block-gc-ad-pave_bas, #block-gc-ad-pave_haut, #block-gc-ad-purl,
        #block-pub-pav2, #block-pub-pav3, #block-rf-pub-middle, #block-rf-pub-middle2, #block_pub,
        #block_pub_article, #block_regie_pub_bas, #block_regie_pub_bas_article, #bloctopad,
        #bodyGoogleAnnounces, #bodyPanpub, #bonga-bottom-banner, #bonsplansprospect, #bottom-adv,
        #bottom-pub, #bottom-right-pub, #bottom_ad_space, #bottom_pub, #box-izipub, #box-pub-1,
        #box-pub-2, #box-pub-3, #box-pub-4, #box-pub-5, #bsa-block-125--125 { display: none
        !important; } #bsa-block-1920--1200, #bsa-block-250--250, #bsa-block-250--600,
        #bsa-block-300--250, #bsa-block-300--600, #bsa-block-336--280, #bsa-block-468--60,
        #bsa-block-728--90, #bsa-block-970--250, #bsa-block-970--90, #cadre_infoads, #cadre_pub_bas,
        #captchmeCapsuleContent, #carre-pub, #carre_pub, #carrepubHome, #cb_t1_before_content_ad,
        #colgauche_pub, #comment-ad, #commentad, #community-ad, #community-ad-unit, #container-pub,
        #container_pub, #container_pub_left, #conteneurPub, #conteneur_pub, #content_left_pub,
        #content_pub, #content_pub_carre, #contenu-text-publicite, #contenu_liens-sponso,
        #contextualAds, #contextuel-publicite-video, #coreads-wrapper, #criteoDiv, #criteoDiv1,
        #criteoDiv2, #criteoDiv3, #criteoad, #crocopush_banner, #current_side_ad, #custom-ad,
        #custom-fake-media-player, #data-ad-name, #data-ad-provider, #derperd-ad, #desktopAd,
        #desktopMessageAd, #dfp-banniere_haute { display: none !important; } #dfp-habillage,
        #dfp-pave_bas, #dfp-pave_milieu, #dfp_banniere_bas, #dfp_banniere_haute, #dfp_droite-ga,
        #dfp_inread, #dfp_left, #dfp_right, #displayedPub, #div-ads, #div-gpt-ad-Banniere_Haute,
        #div-gpt-ad-Habillage, #div-gpt-ad-Pave_Article, #div-gpt-ad-Pave_Bas,
        #div-gpt-ad-Rectangle, #div-gpt-ad-banniere_haute, #div-gpt-ad-habillage,
        #div-gpt-ad-mainColumn_double, #divADV, #divHomeAd1, #divHomeAd2, #divHomeAd3, #divPub,
        #divPubAccueilGauche, #divPubEntete, #divPubRecetteDroit, #divPubRecettePortable,
        #divPublicityLateral, #div_banniere_pub, #div_for_adnplay, #div_invideo_ad, #div_pub_google,
        #dm_ads_Ban_desktop_bottom, #dm_ads_mobile_bottom, #dst_pub_728, #eShowPubTop, #ebuyclub-ad,
        #ecsc-ad-wrapper, #encart-adsense-top-single, #encart_pub, #encart_pub_image, #entete_pub,
        #exoad, #external-floater-ad-wrap, #fake-player-wrapper, #favoris_pub_ligatus,
        #fecharads1-fx, #fecharads2-fx, #firstpost_ad { display: none !important; } #fixe_plugin,
        #fixed-ads, #floated-ad, #foot_pub, #footer-ad-formation, #footer-advertising, #footer-pub,
        #footer-reklam, #footer_728x90_ad, #footer_haut-publicite, #footer_pub, #footerpub1,
        #footerpub2, #footerpub3, #footerpubs, #for_ad, #free_pub_head, #fuck-adb-enabled,
        #fullScreenAdBg, #game_leaderboard_container, #gbPub728bas, #general_subpub, #google-ads-1,
        #google-ads-2, #google-ads-3, #google-ads-4, #google-adsence-300-250, #google-dfp-middle,
        #google-dfp-right, #googleAdSense, #google_adds, #google_adsencetxt,
        #google_csa_ad_unit_RHS, #google_csa_box_RHS, #gpt-ad-300x250-300x600-bottom,
        #gpt-ad-728x90-970x66-bottom, #gpt-ad-habillage, #gpt-ad-inread, #gpt-leaderboard-top,
        #grid-pub, #habillage-mad, #habillage_pub, #haut_site_pub, #head-pub, #head_pub,
        #header-promo, #header-pub, #header-pub-banner, #header-pub-top, #header-standard-advert {
        display: none !important; } #headerPUB, #headerPub, #header_728x90_ad, #header_bloc2_pub,
        #header_pub, #header_pub_contenu, #headerpub, #hideAd, #home-advert, #home-pub,
        #home-pushdownAd, #horizontal-pub, #hp-pub-block-980x200, #hp_ad_most-played,
        #hp_ad_top-right, #idpublicitepave, #iframe-anAdScPpNgb160x600, #iframe-pub-120x600,
        #iframe-pub-300x250, #iframe-pub-300x600, #iframepub, #iframesidebarpub, #ima-ad-container,
        #imagePubPave, #inReadVideo, #inads, #incontent_ad, #incontent_ad2, #incontent_ad3,
        #index_module_pub, #infinite-adslot-2, #infopopup > a > img, #infosad, #inlineaddesktop,
        #innerpub, #insidepage_ads, #intextad, #ipBlock-LargeAdBox, #ipBlock-mainAdBox, #j_ads,
        #jasmine-ad-wrapper, #js-MobileAd-insert, #js-game-leaderboard-bottom, #jw_video_popup,
        #keep-ads, #kk-adsense-bottom, #large-banner-ad, #large-banner-bottom-ad, #leaderboard.ads,
        #left-ads-rail { display: none !important; } #left_slide_pub, #lht-advertising,
        #lht-space-ad, #libelle_pub, #liens_sponsorises, #loading-ad, #loop_advert,
        #loop_advert_container, #mainColRightPublireportage, #mb_moving_container, #mb_video_sponso,
        #mb_video_syncad_bottom, #md-media-overlay-ad, #meaPubContainer, #middle-publicite,
        #milieu_pub, #miniBoutiquePub, #mobileMessageAd, #mod-ad-msu-3, #modp-300600,
        #module_publicite, #monetiz-pub, #msgNoPub, #native_ad, #news-droite-publicite,
        #news_pub_centre, #nf-fixed-ads, #nuggadcontentadIF, #oPublicite, #om_ads-7, #overVideoAd,
        #over_video_ad, #pagelet_advertiser_panel, #partner-ads, #partner-ads2, #pave1_ad,
        #pave2_ad, #pave3_ad, #pave4_ad, #pavePub, #pave_pub, #pavepub, #photos_ad300,
        #pie_pub_google, #play-advert, #player-advvertising, #player-option-fake, #playerPub,
        #pm300x250, #pm728x90 { display: none !important; } #pmFooterBody, #pmFooterMain,
        #pmHeaderMain, #pmd300x600, #popup_pub, #post_id_pub, #posterAdContainer, #pre-1adv,
        #pre-2adv, #pre-ad, #product-ads, #psreklama, #pub-200x197, #pub-300-250,
        #pub-300-250-google, #pub-300x250, #pub-468-60-google, #pub-468x60, #pub-728,
        #pub-728-90-google, #pub-728-90-sous-categories, #pub-728x90, #pub-730x90, #pub-970x90,
        #pub-after-adownload, #pub-ban, #pub-banner, #pub-banner-content, #pub-banner-refresh,
        #pub-bottom, #pub-carasexe, #pub-caree, #pub-center, #pub-collante, #pub-dfp,
        #pub-dfp-footer, #pub-dfp-footer-fixe, #pub-dfp-pano-bottom, #pub-dfp-pano-top,
        #pub-dfp-prehome, #pub-dfp-rect-bottom, #pub-dfp-rect-cont, #pub-dfp-rect-middle,
        #pub-dfp-rect-sp1, #pub-dfp-rect-top, #pub-display-120x600, #pub-display-300x250,
        #pub-display-300x600, #pub-display-468x60, #pub-display-728x90 { display: none !important; }
        #pub-droite, #pub-footer, #pub-ftv-middle, #pub-habillage, #pub-haut, #pub-haut-adblock,
        #pub-head, #pub-header, #pub-large, #pub-left, #pub-main, #pub-middle, #pub-middle2,
        #pub-pave1-d, #pub-pave2-d, #pub-pave3-d, #pub-right, #pub-right-bottom,
        #pub-right-bottom-msg, #pub-right-top, #pub-right-top-ads-refresh, #pub-right-top-msg,
        #pub-sky, #pub-text, #pub-top, #pub-widget, #pub-widget2, #pub01, #pub1-passback,
        #pub120x600, #pub160, #pub160x320, #pub160x600, #pub2-passback, #pub250, #pub3-passback,
        #pub300, #pub300250, #pub300_adscreen, #pub300_home, #pub300x120, #pub300x250,
        #pub336Criteo, #pub336bas-criteo, #pub4-passback, #pub468x15, #pub468x60_centree,
        #pub468x60_droite, #pub468x60_gauche, #pub468x60_match { display: none !important; }
        #pub468x60_text, #pub468x60_text2, #pub728, #pub728_ATF, #pub728bas, #pub728caracpub,
        #pub970acc, #pubAdBlockHabillage, #pubArticle, #pubAside, #pubAside2, #pubBandeau,
        #pubBanner, #pubBottom, #pubBottomRight, #pubCarre, #pubCenter, #pubChronique,
        #pubContainer, #pubDeclic, #pubDroite, #pubEncart, #pubEncart1, #pubEncart2, #pubFlash,
        #pubFloat, #pubFrame, #pubHaut, #pubHead, #pubHeader, #pubHorizontale, #pubImg, #pubLeft,
        #pubLigatus, #pubMiddle, #pubMiddleRight, #pubPartenaires, #pubPave2, #pubPosition1,
        #pubPosition2, #pubRight, #pubRight-show, #pubSidebarHaut, #pubTop, #pubTopPage, #pubVideo,
        #pub_1, #pub_300_100, #pub_300_250, #pub_300x250 { display: none !important; }
        #pub_300x250-1, #pub_300x250-2, #pub_460x60, #pub_468x60, #pub_728_90, #pub_728x90,
        #pub_728x90-1, #pub_728x90-2, #pub_articlefooter, #pub_ban, #pub_bandeau, #pub_banner,
        #pub_banniere_basse, #pub_banniere_haute, #pub_banniere_medium, #pub_bas, #pub_bas_droit,
        #pub_bas_gauche, #pub_bottom, #pub_brique, #pub_carre, #pub_carre_1, #pub_col_droite,
        #pub_col_right, #pub_column, #pub_container, #pub_contener_right, #pub_content, #pub_criteo,
        #pub_dfp_article, #pub_dfp_banniere_basse, #pub_dfp_banniere_haute,
        #pub_dfp_banniere_middle, #pub_dfp_droite_haute, #pub_dfp_flash_trans, #pub_dfp_habillage,
        #pub_dfp_pre_home, #pub_droite, #pub_droite_2, #pub_enbas, #pub_enbas1, #pub_entete,
        #pub_entete1, #pub_extensible, #pub_footer, #pub_footer_banner, #pub_gauche, #pub_gauche_2,
        #pub_geante, #pub_haut { display: none !important; } #pub_head, #pub_header,
        #pub_header_chaine, #pub_header_droite, #pub_horizontale, #pub_interstitiel,
        #pub_leaderboard, #pub_lecteur, #pub_lecteur_0, #pub_left, #pub_megaban, #pub_megabanner,
        #pub_middle_home, #pub_pave, #pub_pave2, #pub_pave3, #pub_pave4, #pub_pave_article,
        #pub_pave_bottom, #pub_pave_top, #pub_plop-1, #pub_plop-2, #pub_plop-3, #pub_pole_position1,
        #pub_pupop, #pub_rectangle, #pub_rectangle_moyen_bas, #pub_right, #pub_slide_droite,
        #pub_soonight, #pub_square, #pub_texte, #pub_top, #pub_top_droit, #pub_top_gauche,
        #pub_ventre, #pub_voyage, #pubarticle2, #pubarticle3, #pubbanner, #pubbas, #pubbetween,
        #pubcarre, #pubcentrale, #pubchageapresmiddle, #pubchargeapres, #pubcol2, #pubcoldroite,
        #pubdetaillg, #pubdetaillg2 { display: none !important; } #pubdirect, #pubdirecte,
        #pubdroite, #pubdudessous, #pubflottante, #pubfooter, #pubfooter-md-lg, #pubfooter-sm,
        #pubfooter-xs, #pubgauche, #pubgoogle, #pubhaut, #pubheader, #pubhomeheader, #pubiframe_sky,
        #publ1c1te_300_250, #publ1c1te_728_90, #publicidad-videoancho, #publicidade,
        #publicidadlateral1, #publicidadlateral2, #publicite, #publicite-bas, #publicite-principale,
        #publicite2, #publiciteDeMesPartenaires, #publiciteHaut, #publicite_468_60,
        #publicite_728_90, #publicite_banniere, #publicite_banniere_haut, #publicite_droite,
        #publicite_gauche, #publicite_header, #publicite_liste_bookmaker, #publicite_orange,
        #publicite_right, #publicite_top, #publicite_txt, #pubmegaban, #pubnativepassback,
        #pubpreroll, #pubright, #pubsCommentGoodDeals, #pubsidebar, #pubsousmenu,
        #pubsousmenu-md-lg, #pubtop, #pubtopflex, #quads-ad3_widget { display: none !important; }
        #quads-ad4_widget, #rail_ad3, #rectSlotAd, #reklaamacasino2, #reklam-160x600,
        #reklam-468x60, #reklam300x250, #reklam300x600, #reklamDiv, #reklam_mgid, #reklama2,
        #reklama3, #reklamarkaplan, #result_ad, #right-side-ad, #rightCol_ad, #rightReklamIc,
        #right_ad_3, #right_ad_4, #right_pub, #right_slide_pub, #rightadBorder3,
        #rightcolumn_160x600ad, #rightpubbox, #rightrail-ad-2, #rotate_textads_2, #roundPub,
        #sagreklam, #sbPubRegie, #script-fallback-pub336, #script-fallback-pub336bas-criteo,
        #section-ad2, #sg-pub-980x200, #shopper-widget-wrapper, #shopper_adsense,
        #show_banner_bottom_leaderboard, #show_banner_leaderboard, #sideBarGoogleAnnounces,
        #sideBar_pub1, #sideBar_pub1_content, #sideBar_pub1_title, #sideBar_pub2,
        #sideBar_pub2_content, #sideBar_pub2_title, #side_ad_container_B, #side_adv, #side_pub,
        #sidead2, #sideadcontent, #sidebar-bottom-pub { display: none !important; } #sidebar-pub,
        #sidebar_advert_widget, #sidebar_pub_top, #sitePubTop, #skin_container_sidebar_ad,
        #skin_td_sidebar_ad, #slidepub, #small-banner-ad, #small-banner-bottom-ad, #sneaky-ad,
        #solreklam, #sp-entete-pour-la-pub, #spaceForPub, #splashbox-advcorner, #sponsor-block,
        #sponsor_google, #sponsor_sidebar, #sponsored-container, #sponsoredContainer,
        #sponsoredItemtop, #sponsoredProducts, #sponsoredResultitem, #squareadvertise, #standardAd0,
        #stickyDFP, #stop_ad, #subheader_pub, #tab-ad, #tagPubBanniere, #tag_pub_footer,
        #teads_placement, #teaserPub, #thePubDiv2, #ticker_ad, #titre-publicite, #top-left-pub,
        #topAdContainer728, #topAdscenter, #top_player_adv, #top_pub, #top_side_pub, #topleftad,
        #toppub, #toppubbutton, #tower_pub, #tube_ad_wrap, #under-pl-ad, #user18div, #vHeader-pub,
        #vertical-ad { display: none !important; } #vertical-ads, #videoOverAd300snd, #videoadv,
        #videoplayerpub, #wb_Adtext1, #wb_Adtext2, #werbeblock, #widget-pub-2, #widget-pub-3,
        #widget_box_pub, #wrapper-pub, #wrapper_inread, #youfoot-ad-banner,
        #zatvorit-reklamu-popup1, #zone-sponso, #zone_pub, #zone_pub1, #zone_pub2, .MIXADVERT_NET,
        .Middle-Ad, .ad--desk, .ad-container, .ad.banner, .ad.billboard, .ad.onlyMobile,
        .ad_skyscrap, .ads-bloc, .ads-container, .ads-foot, .ads-footerBanner, .ads-group,
        .adwrapper, .ap-AdContainer, .article__ads, .ban-728, .ban_pub, .bandeauClosePub,
        .bandeau_pub, .bandeau_pub_630, .bandeau_pub_centre, .bandeau_pub_promo, .banndar468x60,
        .banner-ad-link, .banner-adsense-holder, .banner-leaderboard, .banner_40X160,
        .bannergroup_bannierepub, .banners-adv, .banniere_pub, .barre_adsense { display: none
        !important; } .before-side-nav-ad, .bg-adsense, .bg_ads300x250, .bi-ads-mobile,
        .big-leaderboard, .bigLogoAnnonceur, .bigadbvert, .bigadvert, .bigbox-pub, .bireklam,
        .bireklam2, .bireklam3, .blc_ads_home, .bloc-ads, .bloc-ads-container, .bloc-ligatus-300,
        .bloc-ligatus-500, .bloc-parution-ad, .bloc-pub, .bloc-pub-center-left, .bloc-pub-side,
        .bloc-pub2, .blocPub, .bloc_annonce_2_ad, .bloc_pub_250, .bloc_pub_250_s_marge,
        .bloc_pub_300, .bloc_pub_728, .bloc_pub_header, .bloc_pub_left, .bloc_rightcol_pub,
        .blocactucatpub, .block-advertising-insert, .block-artwhere-ads, .block-cPublicite,
        .block-dm-ads-prisma, .block-gc-ad, .block-pub, .block-pub-ban-btm, .block-pub-ban-forum,
        .block-pub-ens-th-forum, .block-pub-fee1, .block-pub-max-300x600, .block-pub-partenaires,
        .block-pubimage, .block-rf-pub, .block-with-ads-banner, .block_ad_container, .block_adtop,
        .block_pub { display: none !important; } .block_pub1, .block_pub2, .block_small_pub,
        .blockgrayad, .blockpubiframe, .blocpub, .blocpubbas, .border-box-ad, .border_ads,
        .bottom-ad-mob-tab, .bottom-ad-normal, .bottom-adv2, .bottom-advertising, .bottom_ad_con,
        .bottompub, .box-advertisement-bottom, .box-advertisement-top, .box-centered-ads, .box-pubb,
        .boxAdLeft, .boxAdRight, .boxAdTop, .box_publicites, .box_publicites2, .box_publicites3,
        .box_publicites_bg, .boxadvert, .breaking-ad, .bumpable-ima-ad-container, .bupgoogle,
        .business-details-ads, .buzz-ad-post, .buzz-ad-post-top, .buzz-ads, .bxl-advert,
        .c-ads-sidebar, .cadre-162-pub, .cadre-pub-google, .cadre_pub, .cadrepub, .cadrepubfooter,
        .campagnePUBcoldroite, .cap-ads, .cap-ads-mobile, .cap-ads-placeholder, .cap-ads-text,
        .card--row-ads, .carouselpub, .carouselpub300, .carouselpubf { display: none !important; }
        .carre_pub, .carrepub, .catAds, .category__mobile-ads, .closeStartAdZone, .co-ads,
        .col-advert, .col-droite-pub-milieu, .column_in_pub, .common-ad-styling, .container-ad,
        .container-pubcarre, .containerAds, .container_pubcentrale, .contenedorAds,
        .conteneur_ligatus, .conteneur_pub, .conteneur_pub_250250, .conteneur_pub_300250,
        .conteneur_pub_footer, .conteneur_pub_horiz, .conteneur_pub_vertical, .content-ad-bloc,
        .content-pub-top, .content-side-ad, .content_slide_pub, .contenu-bloc-sponsorise,
        .coreads-wrapper, .coreads_habillage, .cpm-advertisement, .creatividad, .criteo-ban,
        .criteoad, .ctn_ads_twins, .cubes-ads, .d-ad-megaBan, .deck--below-ads, .deck--top-ads,
        .delayedAdvertising, .description_ad, .desktop-dsa, .desktop-ff-ads, .desktop-ff-ads__main,
        .desktop-mobile-ads, .desktop-mobile-ads__desktop, .dfp-ads, .dfp-slot-bas-banniere,
        .dfp-slot-habillage, .dfp-slot-megaban, .discoverAd { display: none !important; }
        .div-publiciteh, .divAd_Header, .divAdsBottom, .div_ads, .div_pub_728_90, .dm_ads_InRead,
        .dossier-pub, .dp-ad-chrome, .dp-ad-visible, .drop-down-advert, .drt-ad-url,
        .drt-sponsor-block, .drt-sponsor-data, .e3lan-below_header, .e3lan-bottom, .e3lan-cell,
        .e3lan-post, .e3lan300-600, .e3lanat-layout-rotator, .ebam_ad, .encart_pub, .espace-pub-top,
        .esv-pub-300-250, .etiq-ads, .expressAdBanner, .facebook-twitter-ads-728-90, .fakeAd,
        .fake_embed_ad_close, .fake_player, .fdw-ads, .fig-ad, .fig-ad-pave, .fig-native-ads,
        .fig-wid-ads-img, .fix_reklama, .fixedAd, .flash-ad, .flayr-ad, .fly_head_ad, .footer--pub,
        .footer-pub, .footerAdsPaves, .footerlinkad, .footerpubleft, .footerpubright,
        .frame-ads-left, .frame-ads-right, .frame-ads-top, .frameForMoney, .ftAdPaves { display:
        none !important; } .ftv-ad-pave, .full-width-add-footer, .fun-adsense, .g-ads-336-250,
        .gamebot_ads, .gametop_ads, .google-ads-keylink, .googleAdTag, .googleAds468, .google_ad2,
        .gptAd, .gr-ads-imu, .gr-ads-imu-sticky, .green-ad, .gtm-pub, .gutter-ads-container,
        .gz_ads_title, .h2-advert, .hb__ad--bottom, .hb__ad--content, .hb__ad--header,
        .hb__ad--side, .head-advrtsmnt, .head-pub, .header-add-wrapper, .header-adds,
        .header-blocked-ad, .header-box-ads, .header-promo, .header-pub, .header-pub-class,
        .headerBannerAds, .headerPub, .header_ad_3, .header_ad_4, .header_adv, .header_bloc_pub,
        .header_link_ads, .header_pub, .header_sponsors, .header_top_ads, .hidden-horizontal-pub,
        .hide-pub-1000x90, .hide-pub-300x250, .hideStartAdZone, .hmads_1x1, .hmads_300x250,
        .hnadszone, .home-ad-region-2, .home-career-side-ad { display: none !important; }
        .home-jobs-side-ad, .home_pub, .hori-advert, .horizontal-pub, .howtoads,
        .ibd-videos-paid-ad, .iframe_pub, .iframeads, .iklan, .iklan1, .iklan2, .in_stream_banner,
        .in_up_ad-area, .inpage-adspace, .inplayer_banners, .insertPadList, .insert_pub_center,
        .inside-pub-container, .inside_adv_section, .istdg-sponsored, .it-sponsor-site,
        .item-ad-header, .item-izipub, .item-pubb, .item-pubb-728, .itemlist-block-pub,
        .jeg_ad_module, .jeg_ads_hide_desktop, .jeg_ads_hide_phone, .jeg_ads_hide_tab,
        .jnews_article_bottom_ads, .jnews_article_top_ads, .job-ads, .job_ads_container,
        .js-ads-imu-sticky, .js-smart-ad, .js_DivPublicityLateral, .jt-poublicidadContainer,
        .kadmer-ad, .kelkoo--publicite, .la-une__mobile-ads, .label-pub-span, .labelPub,
        .label_advertising, .large-ad-center-close, .large-left-ad, .layout__adHeader,
        .layout__adPlaceHolder, .lazypubli, .lbl-ad { display: none !important; } .leaderboard728,
        .leftSideAds, .left_middle_ad, .left_top_ad, .leftaddsense, .leftmenupub, .lftBigAds,
        .lien_commerciaux_bann, .lien_commerciaux_bann_texte, .lien_sponso, .lien_sponsorise,
        .liens-sponsorises__external, .liens_commerciaux, .line-adv, .link-background-advert,
        .link-pub, .list-ads-282, .list-ads-468, .listing_list_ad, .little_pub, .logo-right-ads,
        .logo_pub, .lrAds, .ltas_adspot, .m-adbanner, .m-adbanner--megaban,
        .m-adbanner--megabanfooter, .m-adbanner--newsinread, .m-adbanner--newsunder, .mailPubHeader,
        .map_fond_pub, .marketing-container, .masthead-overHeader, .matador_dfp_channel_ad_widget,
        .mb_video_syncad, .mbanner-ad-wrapper, .mdmAd-inner, .media-pub-1-in-article-adsence,
        .media-pub-2-in-article-adsence, .megapub, .midads, .middle-publicite, .mobile-ads__close,
        .mobile-ads__main, .mobile_ad, .mobile_adhesion, .mobile_instream_ad, .mod-ad-middle,
        .mod-ad-top, .mod-ad-top-2 { display: none !important; } .mod-advertisement, .modAd,
        .modalPub, .module-pub, .moduleAds728, .module_epg_publicite, .module_epg_publicite_level0,
        .module_sponsored, .moduletable-pub2, .mom-ads-wrap, .movie_728_90, .mpu-adv-revamp,
        .mueveads, .myAd, .native_ad2, .nativeads, .navAd, .nead-card, .newads,
        .nextread-advertisement, .nf-aside-ads, .nf-aside-ads__legal, .nf-fixed-ads, .nipnadszone,
        .node-publicite, .nosub-side-ad, .nosub-side-ad-pos, .null-ad, .oa_bannerPub, .oan_ad,
        .oas-ad-160-600, .oas-ad-728-90, .oas-ads-box, .oas-ads-box-in, .oas-ads-buy, .oboxads,
        .oboxads-ad-widget, .oboxads-outstream, .ocultar-ad, .of-ad-container, .openx-billboard,
        .orange-ad, .ot_ads, .outer_ads_left, .outer_ads_right, .outside120SkyAd, .outside160SkyAd,
        .outside300SkyAd, .p-floating-ad-wrapper, .p-with-floating-ad { display: none !important; }
        .padAdv, .padscreen, .page-head-ad, .pageLoadAdBox, .pagin_pub, .pane-st-dfp-ads,
        .panel-ads, .panel_pub, .panet-mars-adv-panel, .parent_ad, .partner-asset-left-ad,
        .partner-asset-right-ad, .partner-pub, .pave-pub, .pave_google_300_250, .pave_pub,
        .pave_pub2, .paywall-widget-mosaic-ads, .paywallAds, .picads, .pjsleads,
        .placeholder-pub_dfp, .player-adv, .player-adx-block, .player-pub, .player-screen-ads,
        .player-screen-ads-item, .player-screen-ads-list, .player-screen-ads-wrapper,
        .player-sponsor-block, .player__ads, .player_bg_ad, .playerpub, .pmd-ads, .pmd-ads-300x310,
        .pmd-ads-300x600, .pmd-ads-desktop, .pmd-ads-mobile, .pmd-ads-placeholder, .pmd_dfp_ad,
        .pmdfp-placer, .pmdfp_habillage, .po_wads, .popupads, .porn-videos-ads, .position_pub,
        .ppub300, .promo-extend-pub, .promo-google-300x600, .promo-google-300x600_new { display:
        none !important; } .promo-partenaire, .propads, .pstAd, .pstAdLegend, .pub-1000x90,
        .pub-1000x90-bottom, .pub-1000x90-top, .pub-138x200, .pub-160-600, .pub-290x200,
        .pub-290x80, .pub-300, .pub-300-250, .pub-300-250-600, .pub-300-corp, .pub-300x250,
        .pub-300x250-bottom, .pub-300x250-du-bas, .pub-300x250-top, .pub-300x600,
        .pub-300x600-bottom, .pub-300x85, .pub-336x280, .pub-468x60, .pub-728, .pub-728-90,
        .pub-728x90, .pub-730x90, .pub-960x90, .pub-970, .pub-970x90, .pub-980x200, .pub-Adtech,
        .pub-adsn, .pub-after-download, .pub-ban, .pub-banner, .pub-block, .pub-bottom, .pub-btns,
        .pub-carre, .pub-carre-smart-php, .pub-condor, .pub-container, .pub-container-bas,
        .pub-container-haut, .pub-container-middle, .pub-demipage, .pub-detail-1, .pub-double-bande
        { display: none !important; } .pub-droite-player, .pub-fil-discussion, .pub-gigaban,
        .pub-half-width, .pub-haut, .pub-home-news-bloc, .pub-img, .pub-index, .pub-index-gauche,
        .pub-label, .pub-ligatus-article, .pub-megaban, .pub-megabanner, .pub-oan-rectangle-bottom,
        .pub-oan-square-side, .pub-partenaires, .pub-pave, .pub-promo, .pub-push-produit,
        .pub-rectangle-php, .pub-replace, .pub-right, .pub-rotate-bottom, .pub-sidebar1,
        .pub-sidebar2, .pub-single-top, .pub-text, .pub-top, .pub-top-site, .pub-trailer,
        .pub0-if-commerciales, .pub1-if-commerciales, .pub160x600, .pub242x90, .pub300, .pub300250,
        .pub300250L, .pub300250R, .pub300_600, .pub300_contenu, .pub300a, .pub300b, .pub300c,
        .pub300px, .pub300sidebar, .pub300single, .pub300x250, .pub300x250_home, .pub336,
        .pub336footer { display: none !important; } .pub350x250left, .pub468, .pub468100top,
        .pub46860, .pub468x60, .pub468x80, .pub600200, .pub728, .pub728-90, .pub72890,
        .pub72890-forum, .pub728_90, .pub728a, .pub728b, .pub728c, .pub728x90, .pub950, .pub96590,
        .pub970x90, .pub980x90, .pubAnnouncer, .pubBanner, .pubBannersContainer, .pubBottomRight,
        .pubBox, .pubButton300, .pubContainer, .pubContent, .pubFlash, .pubGoodDeals, .pubGoogle300,
        .pubHabillage, .pubHead, .pubHeader, .pubHeading, .pubIframe, .pubLarge, .pubLeft,
        .pubMobile, .pubPadding, .pubPave, .pubRight, .pubRight1, .pubText, .pubTitle, .pubTop,
        .pubTopContainer, .pubVideo, .pub_1000, .pub_1000_center { display: none !important; }
        .pub_1000_center_1, .pub_1000_center_2, .pub_1000_liste, .pub_120x600, .pub_160_600,
        .pub_160x600, .pub_2_728, .pub_300, .pub_300-250, .pub_300_250, .pub_300_250_right,
        .pub_300_250_right_interne, .pub_300_600, .pub_468, .pub_468x60, .pub_468x60_bas,
        .pub_468x60_haut, .pub_728, .pub_728-90, .pub_728_90, .pub_article, .pub_bande, .pub_banner,
        .pub_banner_bot, .pub_banner_h, .pub_banner_top, .pub_bottom_post, .pub_carre, .pub_centre,
        .pub_club, .pub_container, .pub_container_600, .pub_droit, .pub_droite, .pub_encart_content,
        .pub_forum, .pub_head, .pub_header, .pub_header_banner, .pub_info, .pub_kelkoo,
        .pub_leaderboard, .pub_left, .pub_left_content, .pub_loader, .pub_middle, .pub_mobile,
        .pub_mobile_une, .pub_open, .pub_outer { display: none !important; } .pub_pave, .pub_plus,
        .pub_premium, .pub_prod, .pub_rectangle_300x100, .pub_rectangle_300x250,
        .pub_rectangle_728x90, .pub_rectangle_moyen_out, .pub_rm_inter_posts_forum, .pub_sky,
        .pub_skyscraper, .pub_slot, .pub_square, .pub_tag, .pub_text, .pub_timeline, .pub_top,
        .pub_topright, .pub_vertical, .pub_video, .pub_vignette, .pub_visuel, .pubaccueildroite1,
        .pubaccueilgauche1, .pubads, .pubadsense, .pubarticle, .pubaudessunews, .pubb-336-1,
        .pubb-336-2, .pubbigsize, .pubbottomvideo, .pubcontainer, .pubfond, .pubimage, .pubind1,
        .pubind2, .pubitem, .publSbar, .publarge, .publicidad, .publicidade-rodape, .publicite,
        .publicite-bas, .publicite-box, .publicite1, .publicite2, .publicite3, .publicite4,
        .publicite5 { display: none !important; } .publiciteHeader, .publicitePartenaires,
        .publicite_1, .publicite_2, .publicite_3, .publicite_4, .publicite_468x60, .publicite_5,
        .publicite_droite, .publicite_droite_600, .publicite_gauche, .publicite_horizontale_well,
        .publicite_horizontale_wrapper, .publicite_l, .publicite_locale, .publicite_mobile,
        .publicite_mobile_300x250, .publicite_mobile_cache, .publicite_r, .publicite_resp,
        .publicite_sidebar, .publicite_sous_slider, .publicite_text, .publiciteac, .publiciteright,
        .publicity, .publicityBottom, .publicityRight, .publireportage, .publireportageFront,
        .publireportage_simple, .pubovh, .pubovh300, .pubs-mini, .pubs_over, .pubs_over1,
        .pubsidebar, .pubsky, .pubsoustag, .pubtexte, .pubwrapper, .purple-ad, .push-service-pub,
        .question_page_ad, .quickads_table, .r-pub--banniere, .r-pub--inread, .r-pub--leader,
        .ratio-ad-header, .rd-widget-ads { display: none !important; } .regiePub, .regiePub2,
        .regiePub728, .region-pubheader, .reklaama-casino2, .reklam-gizle, .reklam-side,
        .reklam-videoyan, .reklam728x90, .reklam_300_250, .reklam_300x250, .reklam_728_90,
        .reklama-box, .reklama_vip, .reklambox, .reklamgec, .reklamlink, .related-stories-ad-unit,
        .release-mangas-pub, .remove-ads-component, .removeAds, .remove_ads, .replaceDelayedAds,
        .responsive-house-ad, .right-advertising, .rightPub, .rightRailAdContainer, .right_ad_box2,
        .right_adv_block, .right_advertissment, .right_middle_ad, .right_top_ad, .rigthpubvideo,
        .ritBigAds, .river-ad, .row_pub, .sag-reklam-120x600, .scpe-pub, .sd-ad-container,
        .sd-ad-wrapper, .sda-img-container, .search_publicity_box, .search_square_publicity,
        .section-ads-center, .separepub, .shareaholic-ad, .shareaholic-ad-content,
        .shareaholic-canvas, .shareaholic-dis-ad-col-2, .shareaholic-dis-ad-contains-2 { display:
        none !important; } .shopperAds, .show-pub, .show_banner_bottom_leaderboard,
        .show_banner_leaderboard, .shvertise-banner, .sidbar-ad1, .side-pub, .side-pub-img,
        .side_content_pub, .side_slide_pub, .sidebar-ads160, .sidebar-adv, .sidebar-header-pub,
        .sidebar-middle-ad, .sidebar-wrapper-advert, .sidebarAdHome, .sidebar_adds,
        .sidebar_share_ads, .sidebarpub350250, .simple-ad, .single-top-ads, .single-top-ads-bloc,
        .site-inner-ads, .site-pub-interstitiel, .site-pub-skin, .site-pub-top,
        .six-article-with-ad, .skin_outer_ad, .skyscraper-ad-2, .smiliar_ads, .snippet-publisher,
        .soar-media-global, .sol-reklam-120x600, .span_pub_normal, .special-banner, .sponsor-inread,
        .sponsor_leaderboard, .sponsor_leaderboard-wrap, .sponsor_sidebar, .sponsored-amazon,
        .sponsored-articles, .sponsored-by__highlighted, .sponsored-by__main,
        .sponsored-by__main-wrap, .sponsored-by__other, .sponsored-by__outer, .sponsored-fly,
        .sponsored-fly__brand, .sponsored-fly__close, .sponsored-fly__head { display: none
        !important; } .sponsored-fly__head-outer, .sponsored-fly__open, .sponsored-panel,
        .sponsoredLinksContainer, .sponsoredLinksInfo, .sponsoredPrisma, .sponsored_banner,
        .sponsorfooter, .square-pub, .squareadboxext, .squareadevertise, .squareadvertise, .srcPub,
        .srcPubZone, .stackcommerce-widget, .stage-advertising, .stageAds, .standard_adv_link,
        .sticky-ad-holder, .structure_wrapper-ad, .subimageAd, .tab-reklam, .tableAds,
        .tag-adverline, .tag-sponsored-content, .teaser-mpu, .text_pub, .texte_ads, .texte_ads_plug,
        .texte_pub, .threadSponsor, .thumb_player_pub, .timeline-media--ad, .tipps-content-ad,
        .titrePub, .toast-ad, .top-ads-728-90, .top-banner-pub, .top-horizontal-pub, .top-publicite,
        .top-reklam-normal, .top-side-pub, .topAdvertContainer, .topPub, .top_banner_ads,
        .top_pub_google, .top_reklama, .topbanneradvertise, .topbarpub, .topcenteradss { display:
        none !important; } .topleftad, .toppubs, .tp-ad--full-browser, .tp-ad__container,
        .tradingCenterAd, .tuto-pub-ad-caption, .txt-ads-center, .txt-pub, .txt-top-publicity,
        .unForceAdBlock, .underplayer_banner, .upload-advert, .ustreklam, .vda-block, .vda-title,
        .vertical-ads-group, .video-list-ads, .videoOverAd300snd, .videoOverAdBig, .video_adp2,
        .video_adp3, .video_reklama, .videocontrols-ads, .view-publicites, .vjs-onceux-ad-container,
        .vud_ads, .wads-script, .wgt-publicite-300-250, .wid-sponsor-banner, .wide_add,
        .widget-advert, .widget-advert-300-600, .widget-le_guide, .widget-paruvendu, .widget-pub,
        .widget-pub-300x250, .widget_advncdads, .widget_box_pub, .widget_keleops-ad,
        .widget_keleops-adhalfpage, .widget_om_ads, .widget_positivr-sponsored-posts,
        .widget_publicite, .widgetadv, .widgetpub, .window-ad-container, .with-ad-top,
        .with-corner-ad, .wppasrotate, .wrap-pub { display: none !important; } .wrapper.ad,
        .wrapperPub, .wrapper_pub_sidebar, .xads-wrappe, .xadv-invid, .xadv-invid2,
        .xplayer-banner-bottom, .yourcolor-ads, .zone_annonceurs, .zone_pub_orange, .zonepub,
        [data-ad-position], [data-ad-text], [data-ads-core], [id^="adswidget"], [id^="dfp_ban_"],
        [id^="dfp_banner"], a[href*=".atimaze.com/"], a[href*=".digital2cloud.com/?"],
        a[href*=".irtyd.com/"], a[href*="/aff_c?offer_id="] > img, a[href*="/afu.php?"],
        a[href*="/www/delivery/"], a[href*="?bz=160*600"] > img[src*=".alicdn.com/"],
        a[href*="?bz=300*250"] > img[src*=".alicdn.com/"], a[href*="?bz=725*90"] >
        img[src*=".alicdn.com/"], div[class$="-adlabel"], div[data-ad-id], div[data-ad],
        div[data-iab-tag], .incontent-promo-blitz-container, iframe[style="border: 0; width: 728px;
        height: 110px;"], iframe[style="border: 0; width: 970px; height: 110px;"] { display: none
        !important; }</style>
</rss>