<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News - Octane Magazine</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.octane-magazine.com/category/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.octane-magazine.com/category/news/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 15:34:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2024/04/octane-favicon.svg</url>
	<title>News - Octane Magazine</title>
	<link>https://www.octane-magazine.com/category/news/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Royal Tunbridge Wells Festival of Motoring to mark 130 years since Britain’s first motor show</title>
		<link>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/royal-tunbridge-wells-festival-of-motoring-to-mark-130-years-since-britains-first-motor-show/</link>
					<comments>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/royal-tunbridge-wells-festival-of-motoring-to-mark-130-years-since-britains-first-motor-show/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Hayward]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 16:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.octane-magazine.com/?p=83733</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Tunbridge Wells Festival of Motoring to celebrate 130 years since Britain’s first motor show, held in the town in 1895. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The inaugural Royal Tunbridge Wells Festival of Motoring will take place on 2-3 August 2025, celebrating 130 years since the Kent town hosted the UK&#8217;s first motor show.</p><p>Set in the Georgian colonnades of The Pantiles, the free-to-attend event will showcase over 20 cars and motorcycles from across the eras, honouring the legacy of the 1895 ‘Horseless Carriage Exhibition’. That original show, organised by Sir David Lionel Salomons, featured five pioneering motor vehicles including the first car imported into the UK – a Panhard-Levassor powered by a Daimler engine – alongside a Peugeot, Daimler fire engine, and two De Dion-Bouton machines.</p><p>This summer’s festival aims to reconnect Tunbridge Wells with its these motoring roots. The line-up will include a 1911 Rolls-Royce Silver Ghost, a Jaguar D-type, a 1960 Aston Martin DB4 GT Lightweight, and a Bugatti Type 35. Modern classics such as the Ferrari Testarossa, Porsche 993 GT2 Evo and Bugatti Veyron will feature alongside the latest Hertz Team Jota Cadillac V-Series R, fresh from the 2025 World Endurance Championship.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/TW-Festival-Cadillac-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83736" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/TW-Festival-Cadillac-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/TW-Festival-Cadillac-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/TW-Festival-Cadillac-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/TW-Festival-Cadillac-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/TW-Festival-Cadillac-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/TW-Festival-Cadillac-640x427.jpg 640w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>The event is being curated by a team with deep local and industry ties, and seeks to highlight both the historic and contemporary importance of the area to British motoring. The Pantiles, once famed for its chalybeate spring, has since become home to over 70 galleries, shops and restaurants, and now adds this celebration of automotive heritage to its calendar.</p><p>‘We are extremely excited to bring back this historically significant motoring showcase to an area that is so rich in automotive knowledge, specialist engineering and history,’ said co-organiser Dylan Miles.</p><p>Co-organiser Daniel Cogger of Hagerty Private Client Services added: ‘The 4th Horseless Carriage Exhibition will not only celebrate the 130th anniversary of the very first motor show in Britain, but will also champion the thriving local automotive business in the area.’</p><p>Further details on the Royal Tunbridge Wells Festival of Motoring can be found at <strong><a href="http://www.rtwmotorfest.com" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">rtwmotorfest.com</a></strong></p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/TW-Festival-1-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83735" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/TW-Festival-1-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/TW-Festival-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/TW-Festival-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/TW-Festival-1-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/TW-Festival-1-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/TW-Festival-1-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/TW-Festival-1-640x427.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/TW-Festival-1.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/royal-tunbridge-wells-festival-of-motoring-to-mark-130-years-since-britains-first-motor-show/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<main_image>https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/TW-Festival-lead-e1747671795169-1024x400.jpg</main_image>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>De Tomaso P72: Production-spec analogue supercar unveiled</title>
		<link>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/de-tomaso-p72-production-spec-analogue-supercar-unveiled/</link>
					<comments>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/de-tomaso-p72-production-spec-analogue-supercar-unveiled/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Hayward]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 16:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New cars]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.octane-magazine.com/?p=83698</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A revived De Tomaso unveils production-spec P72: a 700bhp, analogue supercar inspired by the 1965 P70 ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>De Tomaso has revealed the final production version of the P72, a homage to mid-century sports car design and a revival of the marque’s 1960s spirit. First seen as a concept at the 2019 <a href="https://www.octane-magazine.com/events/goodwood-festival-of-speed/"><strong>Goodwood Festival of Speed</strong></a>, the P72 now appears in its completed form, marking a significant milestone for the revived manufacturer.</p><p>Unveiled at the company’s facility in Affalterbach, Germany, the car is heavily inspired by the 1965 De Tomaso P70 – a short-lived but influential collaboration between Alejandro De Tomaso and Carroll Shelby. The P72 channels this heritage with unapologetically sculptural bodywork, analogue instrumentation and what the company calls mechanical purity.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-02-1024x683.jpg" alt="De Tomaso P72" class="wp-image-83704" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-02-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-02-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-02-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-02-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-02-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-02-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-02-640x427.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-02.jpg 1800w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>The platform is new from the ground up, underpinned by a clean-sheet carbon fibre chassis – using a 4&#215;4 twill weave. The centrepiece is an unbonded carbon monocoque – a single uninterrupted structure that extends from the main tub through the front and rear subframes. This construction enhances torsional rigidity and reduces weight, resulting in a rigid but lightweight structure, fundamental to the P72’s intended driving characteristics.</p><p>De Tomaso’s engineers developed this bespoke chassis to accommodate the P72’s low driving position and mid-mounted powertrain, with a focus on achieving a low centre of gravity and optimal weight distribution. A full carbon fibre body sits on top, available either painted in heritage hues or finished in exposed carbon fibre.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Interior-02-1024x683.jpg" alt="De Tomaso P72" class="wp-image-83699" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Interior-02-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Interior-02-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Interior-02-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Interior-02-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Interior-02-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Interior-02-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Interior-02-640x427.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Interior-02.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>The powertrain is equally considered. At the heart of the P72 lies a supercharged 5.0-litre V8 engine, developed specifically for De Tomaso and hand-assembled with forged internals. It produces 700bhp and 605lb ft of torque. Power is sent to the rear wheels through a six-speed manual gearbox, operated via an exposed metal linkage that sits proudly within the cabin – a nod to 1960s racing tradition and a focal point of the interior. Short gear ratios are intended to deliver sharp throttle response and mid-range urgency rather than outright top-speed. </p><p>In the pursuit of purity, the car does not feature drive modes or electronic overlays. There are no screens, no digital clusters or infotainment. Instead, drivers are presented with a suite of mechanical dials and hand-finished switchgear, set within a cabin trimmed in leather and machined metal. </p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-04-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83702" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-04-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-04-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-04-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-04-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-04-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-04-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-04-640x427.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-04.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>&#8216;The P72 was our promise to faithfully revive a historic marque,&#8217; said De Tomaso CEO Norman Choi. &#8216;This first production-specification vehicle embodies everything we stand for: a mechanical soul, timeless beauty, and a driving experience that rises above modern convention.&#8217;</p><p>With the first deliveries scheduled to begin in late 2025, the P72 represents a deliberate counterpoint to the digitised supercar landscape. For more information, see <a href="https://www.detomaso-automobili.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>detomaso-automobili.com</strong></a></p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-05-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83701" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-05-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-05-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-05-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-05-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-05-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-05-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-05-640x427.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Exterior-05.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/de-tomaso-p72-production-spec-analogue-supercar-unveiled/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<main_image>https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/De-Tomaso-P72-Hero-1024x683.jpg</main_image>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hangar Fire claims three lives on Bicester Motion site</title>
		<link>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/update-fire-claims-three-lives-at-bicester-heritage-site/</link>
					<comments>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/update-fire-claims-three-lives-at-bicester-heritage-site/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Hayward]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 11:20:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.octane-magazine.com/?p=83668</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A fire at the Bicester Heritage UK classic car hub, located on a former RAF base, has claimed three lives]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A fire at Bicester Motion has claimed three lives. It has been confirmed that two firefighters and a member of the public have died during the incident, with a further two firefighters being treated in hospital for injuries.</p><p>The three individuals who lost their lives have now been named. Dave Chester, 57, was a member of the well-known family firm Chester &amp; Sons, specialists in groundworks and fencing. The company had long been associated with the Bicester Heritage site, undertaking contracted works on behalf of English Heritage and Bicester Heritage over many years. Also confirmed are firefighters Jennie Logan, 30, of Oxfordshire County Council Fire and Rescue Service, and Martyn Sadler, 38, who served with both Oxfordshire and the London Fire Brigade.</p><p>Emergency services were called to Bicester Motion, located in Oxfordshire, on 15 May after a fire broke out in one of the former RAF base’s historic hangars at around 6.30pm. Nearby residents described seeing thick smoke, ash falling from the sky and ‘loud explosions’. The fire raged into the night, but the ten fire and rescue crews in attendance were eventually able to control the blaze.</p><p>Videos show flames consuming the structure, with helicopters surveying the scene and police, fire and ambulance services responding in force. <strong><a href="https://bicestermotion.com/">Bicester Motion </a></strong>issued a statement around 9pm, confirming the incident and stating that it is working closely with the emergency services. The full extent of the damage is not yet known.</p><p>It’s currently thought that the fire started in Building 79, one of the two smaller hangars on the site, used for storage of vehicles and parts – not to be confused with the larger Historit storage hangar, which is unaffected. It can be seen on the left-hand side of this map from a 2022 event at the site, showing that the hangar is a short distance from the surround buildings, which are thought to be unaffected.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="587" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Bicester-Heritage-map-1024x587.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-83673" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Bicester-Heritage-map-1024x587.webp 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Bicester-Heritage-map-300x172.webp 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Bicester-Heritage-map-768x440.webp 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Bicester-Heritage-map-1536x881.webp 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Bicester-Heritage-map-1200x688.webp 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Bicester-Heritage-map-100x57.webp 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Bicester-Heritage-map-640x367.webp 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Bicester-Heritage-map.webp 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>Daniel Geoghegan, CEO, Bicester Motion issued the following statement: </p><p>&#8216;<em>The last 24 hours have been tragic in so many ways. For the families of those we have lost, the incredible and brave emergency services who have worked tirelessly, our team who has worked relentlessly and the wider Bicester and Oxfordshire community which has shown the most generous support and kindness.</em></p><p><em>I wanted to first pay tribute to the three lives that have been lost. To Jennie Logan and Martyn Sadler, the two firefighters who so bravely tackled the scene. The epitome of selfless service.</em></p><p><em>We extend our heartfelt condolences to their families and loved ones. They have gone above and beyond under unprecedented circumstances. No words can ever make up for what has happened, but they are all very much in our hearts.</em></p><p><em>And to Dave Chester, who ran Chesters &amp; Sons his family business, who has had a long history with the estate – indeed from man and boy. He joined us 12 years ago when we first bought the site and, with his wife and two sons, has been a pillar of our whole business community.</em></p><p><em>We considered him a member of our team, part of the fabric of our estate and a friend to us all. Whenever you had a question, you would “just ask Dave”, not just him but his whole family as they all cared about this place just as much as we do.</em></p><p><em>Our whole community used to say that “Dave always had our back.” Yesterday, he was doing just that – the epitome of his selfless spirit. We will cherish you Dave and you will be sorely missed, and we send our utmost love to Sue, Jordan and Riley.</em></p><p><em>We continue to pray for the two firefighters in hospital. Today we mourn together as a whole community and as an extended family. We will always remember with love those who selflessly served.</em></p><p><em>Thank you everyone for your support.&#8217;</em></p><p>Founded in 2013 on the site of a disused RAF base, Bicester Heritage has become one of the UK’s most significant hubs for historic motoring. The site has grown to encompass more than 50 specialist businesses and regularly hosts events such as the Scramble. In recent years, the wider Bicester Motion development has expanded to include new buildings and modern automotive facilities.</p><p></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/update-fire-claims-three-lives-at-bicester-heritage-site/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<main_image>https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/497842879_1122544586554305_2846930529344874794_n.jpg</main_image>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>London Concours 2025: AC Cars, hypercars and Youngtimer displays announced</title>
		<link>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/london-concours-2025-ac-cars-hypercars-and-youngtimer-displays-announced/</link>
					<comments>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/london-concours-2025-ac-cars-hypercars-and-youngtimer-displays-announced/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Hayward]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 15:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.octane-magazine.com/?p=83531</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The London Concours returns on 3-5 June 2025 with curated displays of legendary AC Cars, Hypercars and Yougtimers]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Honourable Artillery Company in London will once again provide the backdrop for one of the UK&#8217;s most exclusive motoring events, as the London Concours returns from 3-5 June 2025. Now in its ninth edition, the event brings together over 100 significant cars across three days, with each day bringing different themes.</p><p>Tuesday’s opening day will showcase Aston Martin, with over 50 examples lined up on the lawn to celebrate the marque. Wednesday will mark Mercedes-Benz day, and will chart the evolution of one of the most storied marques in motoring. Highlights are set to include a 1954 W198 SL Gullwing, the W100 ‘Grosser’ limousine. Thursday’s ‘Need for Speed – Supercar Day’ will provide a contrasting finale. This section will feature more than 50 performance cars from the past four decades, ranging from poster icons of the 1980s and 1990s to contemporary hypercars.<br><br>Running across all three days will be eight main classes, with the most recently announced being Legendary AC Cars. The display will feature a dozen examples drawn from the marque’s long and varied history, including a number of rarely seen prototypes and competition cars. Chief among them is ‘CPG 4C’, a 1964 AC Cobra with extensive period race provenance, having been campaigned by Roy Salvadori, Chris Amon and Bob Bondurant.</p><div class="image-block-quote">
  <div>
    <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="712" height="666" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/GOODWOOD-75-FULL-©JORDAN-BUTTERS-7-712x666.jpg" class="attachment-image-block-quote-top-left size-image-block-quote-top-left" alt="" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/GOODWOOD-75-FULL-©JORDAN-BUTTERS-7-712x666.jpg 712w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/GOODWOOD-75-FULL-©JORDAN-BUTTERS-7-640x599.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/GOODWOOD-75-FULL-©JORDAN-BUTTERS-7-480x449.jpg 480w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 712px) 100vw, 712px" />
    <div class="block-quote-container">
      <blockquote class="show-for-medium">
        <p>Also on display will be a unique AC Aceca prototype, built for the 1954 Earls Court Motor Show and subsequently purchased by Donald Campbell.</p>
      </blockquote>
    </div>
  </div>
  <div>
    <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="389" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/1954-AC-Aceca-Shilling-AC-Bluebird-front-and-right-side-640x389.jpg" class="attachment-image-block-quote-top-right size-image-block-quote-top-right" alt="" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/1954-AC-Aceca-Shilling-AC-Bluebird-front-and-right-side-640x389.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/1954-AC-Aceca-Shilling-AC-Bluebird-front-and-right-side-480x292.jpg 480w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />
    <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="811" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/AC-Ace-Ruddspeed-Hillary-640x811.jpg" class="attachment-image-block-quote-bottom-right size-image-block-quote-bottom-right" alt="" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/AC-Ace-Ruddspeed-Hillary-640x811.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/AC-Ace-Ruddspeed-Hillary-480x608.jpg 480w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" />
    <blockquote class="hide-for-medium">
      <p>Also on display will be a unique AC Aceca prototype, built for the 1954 Earls Court Motor Show and subsequently purchased by Donald Campbell.</p>
    </blockquote>
  </div>

</div><p>Also on display will be a unique AC Aceca prototype, built for the 1954 Earls Court Motor Show and subsequently purchased by Donald Campbell. Painted in Campbell’s signature Bluebird Blue, the car has undergone a sympathetic restoration and retains its original 100B Bristol engine. Also starring in the AC display will be one of only three surviving AC 428 Frua Spyders, a 1967 prototype combining Anglo-Italian styling with <strong><a href="https://www.octane-magazine.com/articles/ac-cobra-mk1-shelby-the-anglo-american-joybringer/">Cobra</a></strong> underpinnings.</p><p></p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/DSC02178-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83533" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/DSC02178-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/DSC02178-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/DSC02178-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/DSC02178-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/DSC02178-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/DSC02178-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/DSC02178-640x427.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/DSC02178.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>Several other classes will run across all three days, including the Dream Cars display, which this year will star a Bugatti EB110 SS originally delivered to the Sultan of Brunei. Chassis 0001 of only 30 Super Sport variants produced, the car stands out not only for its rarity but for its provenance – having previously been part of the world’s most secretive car collection. </p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/DSC02360-1024x683.jpg" alt="London Concours 2025" class="wp-image-83534" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/DSC02360-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/DSC02360-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/DSC02360-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/DSC02360-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/DSC02360-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/DSC02360-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/DSC02360-640x427.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/DSC02360.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>The growing appeal of late-20th-century modern classics is addressed by this year’s ‘Youngtimers’ class. The display includes a 1994 Alpina B10, a Porsche 930 Flatnose and a BMW Z3 M Coupe. </p><p>Other classes include The Wildcards, The Fast Fords, The Hypercars and &#8216;Celebrating 50 Years of Ferrari&#8217;s V8 engines&#8217;. Now firmly established in the British concours calendar, the 2025 edition of the London Concours looks set to be the most comprehensive yet. Full details of each class, and tickets are available now at <a href="http://londonconcours.co.uk" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>londonconcours.co.uk</strong></a> – use the code OCTANELC for a 20% discount!</p><p></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/london-concours-2025-ac-cars-hypercars-and-youngtimer-displays-announced/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<main_image>https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/1964-AC-Cobra-Bryant-EraMedia_MikaPietrus-4-1024x683.jpg</main_image>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sensational Talbot-Lago survivor to be auctioned in Italy</title>
		<link>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/sole-surviving-1949-talbot-lago-t26-grand-sport-coupe-by-dubos-freres-to-be-sold/</link>
					<comments>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/sole-surviving-1949-talbot-lago-t26-grand-sport-coupe-by-dubos-freres-to-be-sold/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[James Elliott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 15:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Auctions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Market]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.octane-magazine.com/?p=83464</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of just two Talbot-Lago T26 Grand Sport Coupés bodied by Dubos Frères will be auctioned by Broad Arrow at Villa d'Este]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The sole-surviving 1949 Talbot-Lago T26 Grand Sport Coupé by Dubos Frères is coming up for sale for the first time since 2009. The fascinating car, once owned by famed US racer and car importer Otto Zipper, is to be sold at Broad Arrows’ inaugural 70-car sale at the <a href="https://www.octane-magazine.com/events/concorso-deleganza-villa-deste/"><strong>Concorso d’Eleganza Villa d’Este</strong></a> on 24-25 May, although the actual auction takes place at the neighbouring Villa Erba.</p><p>Estimated to make €1.2-1.5million, chassis T26GS110102 car is one of two originally built in the distinctive coupé style by the Dubos brothers and is the only one known to survive. Talbot made only 32 short-wheelbase (265cm) underslung T26 Grand Sports packing the brilliant, hemispherical combustion chambered 4.5-litre twin-cam that Anthony Lago developed with Carlo Marchetti.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_007-1-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83482" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_007-1-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_007-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_007-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_007-1-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_007-1-640x427.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_007-1.jpg 1200w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>The advanced car has independent front suspension, worm and sector steering and Wilson pre-selecter transmission. The Dubos Frères bodywork was designed by Carlo Delaisse and so pleased Anthony lago that an illustration of it was used in the factory brochure.</p><p>This actual car was commissioned by the works and initially entered into concours, including winning a Grand Prix in the 1949 Concours d&#8217;Elegance du Bois de Boulogne in Paris. Its first owner was Wight Whiting, who bought it in September 1949.&nbsp;</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="686" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_003-1-1024x686.jpg" alt="One of just two Talbot-Lago T26 Grand Sport Coupés bodied by Dubos Frères will be auctioned by Broad Arrow at Villa d'Este, estimate €1.2-1.5m" class="wp-image-83478" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_003-1-1024x686.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_003-1-300x201.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_003-1-768x515.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_003-1-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_003-1-640x429.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_003-1.jpg 1200w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>Shortly after it cropped up at International Motors in Hollywood, California and m oved onto Otto Zipper’s Precision Motors on the corner of Wilshire Boulevard and 26th Street in Santa Monica.</p><p>Many years later it was with Southern California Ferrari restorer Richard Straman who started a restoration before selling it to Jerome Sauls, proprietor of the famous Ritz Garage in Warrington, Pennsylvania, in 1997. During Sauls’s tenure it had a full restoration before appearing at Pebble Beach after which it moved back to Europe and was seen at both Rétromobile and Villa d&#8217;Este.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_052-1024x683.jpg" alt="One of just two Talbot-Lago T26 Grand Sport Coupés bodied by Dubos Frères will be auctioned by Broad Arrow at Villa d'Este, estimate €1.2-1.5m" class="wp-image-83495" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_052-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_052-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_052-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_052-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_052-640x427.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_052.jpg 1200w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>Chassis T26GS110102 is currently owned by a well known Talbot-Lago authority, still wears its original body and has matching-numbers chassis, engine, and transmission. You can read the full catalogue description <a href="https://www.broadarrowauctions.com/vehicles/ve25_r001/1949-talbot-lago-t26-grand-sport-coupe-by-dubos-freres">here</a>.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_011-1-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83486" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_011-1-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_011-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_011-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_011-1-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_011-1-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_011-1-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_011-1-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_011-1-640x427.jpg 640w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>Other highlights of the sale include a1938 Talbot-Lago T150 C Lago Spéciale Teardrop Coupé (Estimate: €4.5-6.5m), 1948 Ferrari 166 Spyder Corsa by Ansaloni (€5.5-7.5m)1939 Lagonda V12 Rapide James Young Drophead Coupé (€600-700.000) 1965 Ferrari 275 GTS (€1.5-1.8m) and 1954 Siata 208S Motto Spider (€1.5-1.7m).</p><p>Joe Twyman, VP of Sales for Broad Arrow’s EMEA Region, said: ‘We are thrilled to be presenting some of the most historically significant classic cars at our inaugural Concorso d’Eleganza Villa d’Este auction. Being entrusted with the first ever public sale of the Ferrari 166 Spyder Corsa is an incredible privilege, and testament to the expertise within our team and the prestige of the highly respected Concorso d’Eleganza Villa d’Este. Its presence at the auction along with many other coveted automobiles will make this one of the most important sales of the year.’</p><div class="carousel-container contained block">
    <div class="carousel init-slick" data-slick='{"dots": true, "arrows": true}'>
              <div class="slide image-3-2">
          <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1200" height="800" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_041.jpg" class="attachment-image-3-2 size-image-3-2" alt="" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_041.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_041-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_041-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_041-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_041-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_041-640x427.jpg 640w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" />
        </div>
              <div class="slide image-3-2">
          <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1200" height="789" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_018.jpg" class="attachment-image-3-2 size-image-3-2" alt="" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_018.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_018-300x197.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_018-1024x673.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_018-768x505.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_018-640x421.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_018-480x316.jpg 480w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_018-100x66.jpg 100w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" />
        </div>
              <div class="slide image-3-2">
          <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1200" height="860" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_004-1.jpg" class="attachment-image-3-2 size-image-3-2" alt="One of just two Talbot-Lago T26 Grand Sport Coupés bodied by Dubos Frères will be auctioned by Broad Arrow at Villa d&#039;Este, estimate €1.2-1.5m" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_004-1.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_004-1-300x215.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_004-1-1024x734.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_004-1-768x550.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_004-1-100x72.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_004-1-640x459.jpg 640w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" />
        </div>
              <div class="slide image-3-2">
          <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1200" height="800" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_024.jpg" class="attachment-image-3-2 size-image-3-2" alt="" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_024.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_024-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_024-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_024-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_024-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_024-640x427.jpg 640w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" />
        </div>
              <div class="slide image-3-2">
          <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1200" height="800" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_019.jpg" class="attachment-image-3-2 size-image-3-2" alt="" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_019.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_019-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_019-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_019-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_019-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_019-640x427.jpg 640w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" />
        </div>
          </div>
    <div class="slick-nav-wrap"></div>
  </div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/sole-surviving-1949-talbot-lago-t26-grand-sport-coupe-by-dubos-freres-to-be-sold/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<main_image>https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/VE25_r001-1949-Talbot-Lago-T26-Dubos-Freres-Grand-Sport-Coupe_001-1-1024x683.jpg</main_image>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK-US trade deal: Historic vehicle parts sector remains uncertain</title>
		<link>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/uk-us-trade-deal-historic-vehicle-parts-sector-remains-uncertain/</link>
					<comments>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/uk-us-trade-deal-historic-vehicle-parts-sector-remains-uncertain/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Hayward]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 12:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.octane-magazine.com/?p=83457</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[UK-US trade deal reduces tariffs for new car exports, but historic vehicle parts remain subject to 25% duty, warns HCVA.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The UK Government’s new trade agreement with the United States has brought welcome relief for British vehicle manufacturers – but has left the historic vehicle parts sector facing continued uncertainty. While a quota of up to 100,000 UK-built cars per year will now enter the US at a reduced 10% tariff, parts for historic and classic vehicles will remain subject to the existing 25% rate, prompting concern from the industry.</p><p>The deal – announced on 8 May following weeks of negotiation – softens the blow of a March policy announcement by US President Donald Trump, which introduced sweeping tariffs on imported goods. This included a proposed 25% levy on all new vehicles and components. British car makers, who exported some 102,000 vehicles to the US in 2024 – worth around £9billion – now have cause for optimism. The reduced tariff is expected to benefit manufacturers such as Jaguar Land Rover, Aston Martin and McLaren among others that count the US among key export markets.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/classicworkslaunch462-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83459" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/classicworkslaunch462-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/classicworkslaunch462-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/classicworkslaunch462-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/classicworkslaunch462-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/classicworkslaunch462-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/classicworkslaunch462-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/classicworkslaunch462-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/classicworkslaunch462-640x427.jpg 640w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>But for the UK’s historic vehicle community, there is no such reprieve. While the import of classic vehicles (those over the age of 25) will be exempt from the tariffs, <strong><a href="https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/trumps-automotive-tariffs-threaten-us-classic-car-imports/">as reported last month</a></strong>, the Historic and Classic Vehicles Alliance has highlighted a significant oversight in the deal: it offers no relief for exporters of parts in this vital sector.</p><p>‘UK historic vehicles have long been popular with enthusiasts in the USA, and keeping these vehicles on the road depends on importing parts from the UK’s specialist supply chain,’ said <strong><a href="https://www.hcva.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">HCVA</a></strong> CEO Dale Keller. ‘By applying the automotive tariff relief through a quota mechanism on 100,000 vehicles, the trade agreement has left many in the parts sector high and dry.’</p><p>Keller argues that components for historic vehicles should not fall within the scope of US protectionist policy, particularly as many parts are bespoke, hand-made, or rebuilt to order – and have little or no equivalent in US domestic manufacturing. ‘These pre-existing and replacement parts for historic vehicles have no reasonable prospect of being recreated as newly manufactured in the USA and surely should fall outside the US policy objectives.’</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/080816lresolihulltour061-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83460" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/080816lresolihulltour061-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/080816lresolihulltour061-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/080816lresolihulltour061-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/080816lresolihulltour061-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/080816lresolihulltour061-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/080816lresolihulltour061-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/080816lresolihulltour061-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/080816lresolihulltour061-640x427.jpg 640w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>The HCVA is urging the UK Government to return to the negotiating table and secure more favourable terms for the sector in future talks. While Prime Minister Keir Starmer hailed the vehicle quota agreement as ‘a huge and important reduction’, he confirmed that discussions on the wider tariff framework – including parts – remain ongoing.</p><p>As things stand, the cost of maintaining historic vehicles in the US with British-supplied components is set to remain high. For many firms already facing increased material costs and transatlantic shipping delays, the continued tariff on components may force further price increases for overseas buyers, or lead to reduced demand.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/uk-us-trade-deal-historic-vehicle-parts-sector-remains-uncertain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<main_image>https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1-1024x683.jpg</main_image>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Peking to Paris 2025: 55 teams prepare for epic 14,988km adventure</title>
		<link>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/peking-to-paris-2025-55-teams-prepare-for-epic-14988km-adventure/</link>
					<comments>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/peking-to-paris-2025-55-teams-prepare-for-epic-14988km-adventure/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Hayward]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 09:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.octane-magazine.com/?p=83422</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The 2025 Peking to Paris Motor Challenge sets off on 17 May, with 55 international crews tackling 14,988km across 11 countries in the world’s toughest vintage rally.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Peking to Paris Motor Challenge returns on 17 May for its ninth edition, promising 14,988km of intense endurance rallying across 11 countries and nearly six weeks of non-stop mechanical and human challenge. Starting from the foot of the Great Wall of China, 55 international crews will attempt to conquer the world’s toughest vintage and classic car rally, with a route that stretches to Paris and traverses everything from the Gobi Desert to the high passes of the Alps.</p><p>Following its <a href="https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/vintage-bentley-wins-epic-peking-to-paris-rally/"><strong>delayed 2024 running</strong></a> due to the pandemic, the back-to-back scheduling of the 2025 edition has placed additional demands on organisers HERO-ERA. Competition Director Guy Woodcock describes this year’s route as a refined version of 2024’s, drawing from lessons learned and logistical challenges overcome. Chief Route Planner Chris Elkins, who has worked on seven P2Ps, emphasises the nuance: ‘The route looks similar on a map, but the day-to-day is completely different. We’ve rebuilt it based on feedback and field notes.’</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="682" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/P2P-24-wb-2839-l-1024x682.jpg" alt="Peking to Paris Motor Challenge" class="wp-image-83427" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/P2P-24-wb-2839-l-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/P2P-24-wb-2839-l-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/P2P-24-wb-2839-l-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/P2P-24-wb-2839-l-1536x1023.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/P2P-24-wb-2839-l-1200x799.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/P2P-24-wb-2839-l-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/P2P-24-wb-2839-l-640x426.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/P2P-24-wb-2839-l.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>The route will span from China to Kazakhstan, cross the Caspian Sea into Azerbaijan, and pass through Türkiye before threading through eastern and central Europe into France. That includes ten international borders, six nights under canvas, and punishing terrain – particularly in the Gobi Desert, which dominates the early stages. Only four crews from last year’s field are returning, underlining the rally’s status as a once-in-a-lifetime endeavour.</p><p>Among the standout entrants is 1993 Le Mans winner Christophe Bouchut, sharing a 504 Coupé with P2P veteran and Dakar navigator Prince Alfonso de Orléans-Borbón. It marks a major departure from Bouchut’s career in circuit racing – now testing his mettle on gravel and sand instead of tarmac. Other notable entries include former WRC competitor Jorge Perez Companc, campaigning a 1939 Chevrolet Master Coupe alongside his son Cristobal.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="682" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/car20-Perez_Companq-WB-13315-l-1024x682.jpg" alt="Peking to Paris Motor Challenge" class="wp-image-83441" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/car20-Perez_Companq-WB-13315-l-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/car20-Perez_Companq-WB-13315-l-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/car20-Perez_Companq-WB-13315-l-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/car20-Perez_Companq-WB-13315-l-1536x1023.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/car20-Perez_Companq-WB-13315-l-1200x799.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/car20-Perez_Companq-WB-13315-l-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/car20-Perez_Companq-WB-13315-l-640x426.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/car20-Perez_Companq-WB-13315-l.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>Entrepreneur and philanthropist John Caudwell makes his P2P debut with his brother Brian, also in a 1938 Chevrolet Coupe, while the smallest car on the rally – a 1973 Fiat 500 – will be driven under the flag of San Marino by Tourism Minister Federico Pedini Amati, with support from desert specialist Fabio Longo. </p><p>Two entries from the UK stand out for their contrasting approaches. HERO-ERA chairman Tomas de Vargas Machuca returns after a dramatic fire-related retirement in 2024, this time driving a 1926 Bentley solo – an unprecedented feat if completed. Jonathan Turner, meanwhile, returns with the same 1929 Bentley he drove in the second P2P in 1997, now paired with first-time navigator Nick English.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="653" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/008457-P2P-2024-BP-l-1024x653.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83442" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/008457-P2P-2024-BP-l-1024x653.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/008457-P2P-2024-BP-l-300x191.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/008457-P2P-2024-BP-l-768x490.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/008457-P2P-2024-BP-l-1536x980.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/008457-P2P-2024-BP-l-1200x765.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/008457-P2P-2024-BP-l-100x64.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/008457-P2P-2024-BP-l-640x408.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/008457-P2P-2024-BP-l.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>This year&#8217;s Peking to Paris machinery ranges from pre-war veterans to post-war classics. Australia’s Alan and Leigh Maden will compete in the oldest car in the field – a 1917 American LaFrance Type 12 with a 14.5-litre engine – while 25 of the 55 entrants run in pre-war classes. The Classic Category sees a mix of expected rally fare – Escorts, Datsuns, and Porsche 911s – alongside more idiosyncratic entries like the Volvo 220 Estate of John and David Houck.</p><p>For all the drama and mechanical romance, organisers are keen to stress the rally is not a race. ‘First and foremost, you have to get the car to the end,’ says Guy Woodcock. With early starts, long hours, and tough terrain, the P2P remains a test of endurance, patience, and camaraderie – qualities that will bind this year’s entrants as firmly as those who went before them.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="768" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/car55-orleans-1024x768.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83444" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/car55-orleans-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/car55-orleans-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/car55-orleans-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/car55-orleans-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/car55-orleans-1200x900.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/car55-orleans-100x75.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/car55-orleans-640x480.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/car55-orleans.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>The 2025 Peking to Paris flag drops on 17 May. By the time the last car rolls into Paris on 22 June, drivers and machines will have covered nearly half the globe – and written a new chapter in one of the great modern adventures in historic motoring.</p><p>For more info, visit <a href="https://www.hero-era.com/"><strong>hero-era.com</strong></a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/peking-to-paris-2025-55-teams-prepare-for-epic-14988km-adventure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<main_image>https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/004821-P2P-2024-BP-l-1024x598.jpg</main_image>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Singer launches reimagined, 1980s-inspired Porsche 911 Carrera</title>
		<link>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/singer-launches-reimagined-1980s-inspired-911-carrera-wide-body/</link>
					<comments>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/singer-launches-reimagined-1980s-inspired-911-carrera-wide-body/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Hayward]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 14:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Restomods]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.octane-magazine.com/?p=83325</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Singer reveals the Porsche 911 Carrera Coupe Reimagined by Singer – a 420bhp, wide-body homage to the 1980s Carrera]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Singer Vehicle Design has revealed its latest project: the <a href="https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/911-spirit-70-brings-back-porsches-pasha-trim-and-safety-stripes/"><strong>Porsche 911</strong></a> Carrera Coupe Reimagined by Singer. Drawing inspiration from the rare wide-bodied Carrera models of the 1980s, the new car (as usual) combines retro design cues with cutting-edge engineering – headlined by a bespoke naturally-aspirated powertrain developed with Cosworth.</p><p>At the heart of this new model is a 4.0-litre, air- and water-cooled flat-six engine that delivers 420bhp and revs beyond 8000rpm. Based on the original Type 964 unit, the engine incorporates four-valve cylinder heads, variable valve timing and combustion architecture refined with Cosworth’s expertise. It’s the first naturally aspirated engine developed by Singer to feature water-cooled heads, too.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-14-1024x576.jpg" alt="Porsche 911 Carrera Coupe Reimagined by Singer" class="wp-image-83338" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-14-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-14-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-14-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-14-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-14-1200x675.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-14-100x56.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-14-640x360.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-14.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>Singer’s restoration process begins with an owner-supplied Type 964, stripped to its monocoque and structurally enhanced using a reinforcement programme developed in partnership with Red Bull Advanced Technologies. The carbonfibre bodywork is an original Singer design, taking cues from Porsche’s Super Sport Equipment of the 1980s. It features a deep front spoiler for improved aerodynamics and cooling, flared wheelarches, and the option of either a fixed or speed-activated rear wing. Intakes in the rear quarters feed air to the engine bay, while pop-up driving lamps can be specified for a period-correct competition look.</p><p>The cabin offers Singer’s signature blend of analogue precision and exquisite detail. Buyers can opt for track-focused interiors with lightweight seats and exposed shift linkages, or more luxuriously appointed touring specifications with full leather and deep-pile finishes. Interior materials range from Interferenza cloth and burnished leather to corduroy and velour, while the dashboard houses Singer’s reinterpreted 911 dials.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-12-1024x576.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83337" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-12-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-12-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-12-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-12-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-12-1200x675.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-12-100x56.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-12-640x360.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-12.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>Underneath, the chassis benefits from a fully reworked suspension set-up, derived from Singer’s earlier turbocharged projects. Four-way adjustable dampers with electronic control come as standard, with optional carbon-ceramic brakes and 18-inch centre-lock wheels. Michelin Pilot Sport tyres provide modern grip levels, and a suite of modern electronic aids – including ABS, traction and stability control – is available across five selectable driving modes.</p><p>Singer will offer two example specifications as inspiration: a touring-focused version in Celeste Passalacqua with a Mars Pink interior, and a more aggressive sports version in Giallo Segnale, complete with fixed wing, lightweight track seats and auxiliary lighting. Owners seeking the ultimate in versatility can specify both front and rear body configurations, supplied with a bespoke storage case for easy swapping.</p><p>Each car will be tailored to its owner’s preferences through Singer’s renowned bespoke commissioning process. Price is dependent on specification, and each build will be one of only 100 examples worldwide. For more info, visit <a href="https://singervehicledesign.com/"><strong>singervehicledesign.com</strong></a>.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-37-1024x576.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83363" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-37-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-37-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-37-768x432.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-37-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-37-1200x675.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-37-100x56.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-37-640x360.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-37.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/singer-launches-reimagined-1980s-inspired-911-carrera-wide-body/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<main_image>https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/Image-04-1024x576.jpg</main_image>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jochen Mass: German racing legend dies aged 78</title>
		<link>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/jochen-mass-german-racing-legend-dies-aged-78/</link>
					<comments>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/jochen-mass-german-racing-legend-dies-aged-78/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Hayward]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 11:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Obituaries]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.octane-magazine.com/?p=83280</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jochen Mass, the Le Mans winner, F1 veteran and mainstay of Porsche and Mercedes-Benz racing, has died aged 78. ]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jochen Mass, legendary racing driver, Le Mans winner and much-loved Mercedes-Benz Classic brand ambassador, has died aged 78. Mass passed away on 4 May 2025, leaving behind an enduring legacy in motorsport that stretched from Formula 1 to the pinnacle of sports-car racing.</p><p>Mass was born on 30 September 1946 in Dorfen, near Munich, and grew up close to Mannheim. His diverse career began in touring cars and quickly escalated, seeing him compete in 105 Formula 1 Grands Prix, primarily with <strong><a href="https://www.mclaren.com/">McLaren</a></strong> and Arrows. Mass achieved eight podium finishes, scored 71 World Championship points, and won the 1975 Spanish Grand Prix, marking him as Germany’s most accomplished Formula 1 driver at that particular point in history.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/S25_0416_a3_rgb-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83299" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/S25_0416_a3_rgb-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/S25_0416_a3_rgb-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/S25_0416_a3_rgb-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/S25_0416_a3_rgb-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/S25_0416_a3_rgb-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/S25_0416_a3_rgb-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/S25_0416_a3_rgb-640x427.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/S25_0416_a3_rgb.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>Between 1976 and 1987, Mass was a key member of Porsche’s works team, piloting cars such as the 935, 936, 956, and 962 to numerous victories, including the World Sportscar Championship. Mass also helped facilitate Porsche’s influential sponsorship partnership with Rothmans. He was crowned German Sports Car Champion in 1985, capping more than a decade as a Porsche works driver.</p><p>His greatest motorsport triumph, however, came at the wheel of the legendary Sauber-Mercedes C9. Mass clinched overall victory at the 24 Hours of Le Mans in 1989 alongside co-drivers Manuel Reuter and Stanley Dickens, achieving Mercedes-Benz’s first outright win at the famous endurance race since 1952. He went on to finish runner-up in that year’s World Endurance Championship for Prototypes.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="688" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_019-1024x688.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83304" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_019-1024x688.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_019-300x202.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_019-768x516.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_019-1536x1033.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_019-1200x807.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_019-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_019-640x430.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_019.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>Beyond Formula 1 and Le Mans, Mass’s versatility and adventurous spirit saw him compete in the gruelling 1984 Paris-Dakar Rally, driving a Mercedes-Benz 500 SLC. In 1990, Mass notably mentored young Mercedes-Benz drivers Michael Schumacher, Heinz-Harald Frentzen and Karl Wendlinger.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="693" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_024-1024x693.jpg" alt="Jochen Mass and his protégés " class="wp-image-83307" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_024-1024x693.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_024-300x203.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_024-768x520.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_024-1536x1039.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_024-1200x812.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_024-100x68.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_024-640x433.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_024.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>After retiring from active racing, Mass maintained a close relationship with Mercedes-Benz, becoming a beloved ambassador for Mercedes-Benz Classic. Regularly seen piloting iconic vehicles from Mercedes’ history, Mass delighted crowds at prestigious events, notably the Mille Miglia and Goodwood Festival of Speed. Sir Stirling Moss described Mass as ‘a driver with an extraordinary feel for racing cars and great expertise’, praising his exceptional understanding of racing history and cars from all eras. </p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="680" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_012-1024x680.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83302" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_012-1024x680.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_012-300x199.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_012-768x510.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_012-1536x1020.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_012-1200x797.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_012-100x66.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_012-640x425.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/25c0091_012.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>A man of broad interests, Mass was also known for adventures beyond motorsport. In 1992, he participated in a balloon race across the Atlantic, and from 1993 to 1997 he served as a respected Formula 1 commentator on German television.</p><p><em>In tribute, we have published our full interview with Jochen Mass, conducted in December 2019. </em><strong><em><a href="https://www.octane-magazine.com/articles/features/jochen-mass-the-octane-interview/">Read it here.</a></em></strong></p><p></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/jochen-mass-german-racing-legend-dies-aged-78/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<main_image>https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/05/S25_0423_a3_rgb-e1746528775264-1024x410.jpg</main_image>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>911 Spirit 70 brings back Porsche&#8217;s Pasha trim and safety stripes</title>
		<link>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/911-spirit-70-brings-back-porsches-pasha-trim-and-safety-stripes/</link>
					<comments>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/911-spirit-70-brings-back-porsches-pasha-trim-and-safety-stripes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Hayward]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 14:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New cars]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.octane-magazine.com/?p=83149</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Porsche reveals the 911 Spirit 70, a 541bhp hybrid cabriolet inspired by 1970s design]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Porsche Exclusiv Manufaktur – the somewhat more expressive arm of the company that offers an increased level of personalisation and exclusive models, as well as Paint To Sample colours – has already brought us a number of classic-themed models such as the 911 Sport Classic and Targa 4S Heritage Design Edition. Designed to evoke nostalgia from the 1950s and &#8217;60s, the department has continued the evolution of the range with the introduction of the 911 Spirit 70. </p><p>Quite obviously, this new model moves things forward into the vibrant, somewhat psychedelic 1970s with retro-style colours, and most noticeably the return of the Pasha trim. Based on the latest-generation 911 Carrera GTS Cabriolet, what&#8217;s immediately apparent is the model&#8217;s bespoke Olive Neo paintwork – a deep green developed specifically for this model. Grey-gold Bronzite accents, including the front and rear lower sections and Fuchs-style Sport Classic wheels, provide subtle contrast. Black elements – the soft-top roof and windscreen frame – add further definition.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="768" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/008_Batch-1024x768.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83154" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/008_Batch-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/008_Batch-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/008_Batch-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/008_Batch-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/008_Batch-1200x900.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/008_Batch-100x75.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/008_Batch-640x480.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/008_Batch.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>Three satin-black longitudinal stripes – to those familiar with the 1970s Porsche accessory catalogue known as Safety Stripes – run up the bonnet, continuing along the fabric of the roof. Side graphics, featuring Porsche script and a race-inspired lollipop roundel, complete the vintage look. </p><p>While talking to Porsche designer Thorsten Klein, he explained the desire to include these on the car: &#8216;This graphic caught my eye when I was a kid. I learned later that this was not something that has something to do with motorsport, but it was safety: every manufacturer was building these safety concept cars, and this was about visibility in traffic, but also visibility for pedestrians. Like every detail on the car, it&#8217;s an interpretation of the original rather than a copy, so we actually redesigned the font to better suit the 992-generation car.&#8217;</p><p>Attention to detail extends to the badging. A Porsche crest near-identical to the 1963 original sits proudly on the bonnet, while gold-coloured Porsche lettering and model designation at the rear reference 1950s 356 badges. A Porsche Heritage badge also features on the rear grille.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="768" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/007_Beifahrer_Seite-1024x768.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83155" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/007_Beifahrer_Seite-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/007_Beifahrer_Seite-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/007_Beifahrer_Seite-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/007_Beifahrer_Seite-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/007_Beifahrer_Seite-1200x900.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/007_Beifahrer_Seite-100x75.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/007_Beifahrer_Seite-640x480.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/007_Beifahrer_Seite.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>Inside things really get wild. The seats, door panels and glovebox lid are trimmed in a new black-and-Olive Neo Pasha fabric, recalling the moving chequered-flag designs of Porsche’s classic era. Unlike the original jacquard velour, this new textile uses flocked yarns to deliver better comfort and a more premium feel. </p><p>Boris Apenbrink, head of Porsche Exclusiv Manufaktur, explains that bringing Pasha back is not as simple as it sounds: &#8216;It really is more complex than it looks. If you think of this modern material and compare it visually with the old Pacha, of course it looks familiar. But obviously you cannot just put the old fabrics in the modern car. You have completely different specifications and requirements on durability, fire proof tests and everything. So every technical development of a new pattern is really a new material. It has nothing to do with the old stuff, but we want to make it feel and look right. You feel it and, of course, it is not like the old one – that was very thick and like something you would find on furniture. Today&#8217;s doesn&#8217;t feel like just a regular fabric from cheaper cars, it is soft and very sophisticated that reminds you of the good old times. </p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="768" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/004_3-4_Heck-1024x768.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83156" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/004_3-4_Heck-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/004_3-4_Heck-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/004_3-4_Heck-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/004_3-4_Heck-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/004_3-4_Heck-1200x900.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/004_3-4_Heck-100x75.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/004_3-4_Heck-640x480.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/004_3-4_Heck.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>The instrumentation continues the retro theme, with white pointers and green numerals recalling early Porsche dials. Even the Sport Chrono stopwatch echoes this look, combining period-correct detailing with fully digital functionality.</p><p>Alongside the car itself, Porsche Design has created a matching Spirit 70 chronograph, exclusive to buyers. The watch mirrors the car’s Pasha theme and Olive Neo highlights, offering owners a further connection to their vehicle. A Spirit 70 Porsche Lifestyle Collection has also been announced, offering clothing, accessories and model cars inspired by the 1970s to complement the new model’s ethos.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="768" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/003_Seite-1024x768.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83157" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/003_Seite-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/003_Seite-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/003_Seite-768x576.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/003_Seite-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/003_Seite-1200x900.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/003_Seite-100x75.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/003_Seite-640x480.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/003_Seite.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>The 911 Spirit 70 follows the successful launches of the 911 Targa 4S Heritage Design Edition in 2020 and the 911 Sport Classic in 2022.  ‘The limited-edition collector’s items are particularly desirable for our customers worldwide,’ said Alexander Fabig, Vice President Individualisation and Classic. ‘We are proud to present the third, highly exclusive model in this series.’</p><p>Under its specially finished skin, it&#8217;s basically a standard 911 Carrera GTS Cabriolet features Porsche’s newly developed performance hybrid system, pairing a 3.6-litre twin-turbo flat-six with an electric motor and eTurbo technology. The result is a combined 398kW (541bhp) and 610Nm of torque, offering all the familiar 911 driving engagement with enhanced efficiency. European deliveries begin this month, with other markets to follow.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/015_Handschuhfach-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83152" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/015_Handschuhfach-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/015_Handschuhfach-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/015_Handschuhfach-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/015_Handschuhfach-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/015_Handschuhfach-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/015_Handschuhfach-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/015_Handschuhfach-640x427.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/015_Handschuhfach.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>For more information, see <strong><a href="https://www.porsche.com/uk/models/911/911-spirit-70/911-spirit-70/">porsche.com</a></strong> or if you have access to an Apple Vision Pro, take a look at the bespoke app. </p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/911-spirit-70-brings-back-porsches-pasha-trim-and-safety-stripes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<main_image>https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/002_3-4_Front-1024x768.jpg</main_image>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>International Historic Motoring Awards 2025 categories announced and nominations opened</title>
		<link>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/international-historic-motoring-awards-2025-categories-announced-and-nominations-open/</link>
					<comments>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/international-historic-motoring-awards-2025-categories-announced-and-nominations-open/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Hayward]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 10:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Historic Motoring Awards]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.octane-magazine.com/?p=83172</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nominations are now open for the 2025 International Historic Motoring Awards, returning to The Peninsula London on 14 November with refreshed categories and new honours]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nominations have officially opened for the 2025 International Historic Motoring Awards, set to take place once again at the Peninsula London on Friday 14 November. Sponsored by Lockton, the awards evening is one of the most prestigious fixtures in the collector car world, drawing industry leaders, enthusiasts, restorers and racers from across the globe to celebrate excellence in all facets of the historic motoring scene.</p><p><a href="https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/2024-international-historic-motoring-awards-winners-announced/"><strong>Following a successful relaunch in 2024</strong></a>, this year’s ceremony promises a refined list of categories and the introduction of a few new awards. The changes include the debut of Historic Race Series of the Year, the renaming of Young Achiever of the Year to Rising Star of the Year, and the integration of Book of the Year into the broader Best Use of Media category.</p><p>As before, Car of the Year will be decided by public vote, with a shortlist curated by the editorial teams at <em>Octane</em> and <em>Magneto</em> magazines. All other awards – apart from the Lifetime Achievement Award – will be adjudicated by an independent panel of judges drawn from across the historic vehicle world.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="683" height="1024" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/Historic_Motoring_Awards_2024_321_9490-683x1024.jpg" alt="International Historic Motoring Awards 2025" class="wp-image-83175" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/Historic_Motoring_Awards_2024_321_9490-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/Historic_Motoring_Awards_2024_321_9490-200x300.jpg 200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/Historic_Motoring_Awards_2024_321_9490-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/Historic_Motoring_Awards_2024_321_9490-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/Historic_Motoring_Awards_2024_321_9490-800x1200.jpg 800w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/Historic_Motoring_Awards_2024_321_9490-67x100.jpg 67w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/Historic_Motoring_Awards_2024_321_9490-640x960.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/Historic_Motoring_Awards_2024_321_9490.jpg 1200w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /></figure><p>In total, 16 categories will be contested, with a new focus on inclusivity and breadth across the sector. These range from Restoration of the Year and Motorsport Event of the Year to Club of the Year and the coveted Specialist of the Year title. Notably, the Rising Star of the Year category seeks to recognise those under 30 who have made a meaningful contribution to the classic car world, whether through paid work or volunteer activity.</p><p>For 2025, the event will again offer collectors and enthusiasts the chance to be part of one of the most glamorous evenings in the motoring calendar. Tables are already in high demand, with last year’s allocation selling out well ahead of the event. Early booking is encouraged via events manager Jasmine Love (<a href="mailto:jasmine@hothousemedia.co.uk" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">jasmine@hothousemedia.co.uk</a>), while sponsorship opportunities are being handled by managing director Geoff Love (<a href="mailto:geoff@hothousemedia.co.uk" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">geoff@hothousemedia.co.uk</a>).</p><p>Attendees can expect an evening of elegance and inspiration, where everything from painstaking restorations and innovative tours to ground-breaking media and motorsport endeavours is recognised in a suitably celebratory setting.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/Historic_Motoring_Awards_2024_159_9349-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83176" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/Historic_Motoring_Awards_2024_159_9349-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/Historic_Motoring_Awards_2024_159_9349-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/Historic_Motoring_Awards_2024_159_9349-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/Historic_Motoring_Awards_2024_159_9349-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/Historic_Motoring_Awards_2024_159_9349-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/Historic_Motoring_Awards_2024_159_9349-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/Historic_Motoring_Awards_2024_159_9349-640x427.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/Historic_Motoring_Awards_2024_159_9349.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><h2 class="wp-block-heading">International Historic Motoring Awards 2025 Categories</h2><p>•&nbsp;Rising Star of the Year</p><p>•&nbsp;Personal Achievement of the Year</p><p>•&nbsp;Car of the Year</p><p>•&nbsp;Bespoke Car of the Year</p><p>•&nbsp;Specialist of the Year</p><p>•&nbsp;Restoration of the Year</p><p>•&nbsp;Race Series of the Year</p><p>•&nbsp;Club of the Year</p><p>•&nbsp;Industry Supporter of the Year</p><p>•&nbsp;Museum of the Year</p><p>•&nbsp;Best Use of Media</p><p>•&nbsp;Breakthrough Event of the Year</p><p>•&nbsp;Rally or Tour of the Year</p><p>•&nbsp;Motoring Event of the Year</p><p>•&nbsp;Motorsport Event of the Year</p><p>•&nbsp;Lifetime Achievement</p><p>As ever, the Historic Motoring Awards remain a key barometer of success and influence within the global collector car world – and 2025 promises to be no exception. To nominate or learn more about each category, visit <a class="" href="http://www.historicmotoringawards.co.uk"><strong>www.historicmotoringawards.co.uk</strong></a>. </p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/international-historic-motoring-awards-2025-categories-announced-and-nominations-open/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<main_image>https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/Historic_Motoring_Awards_2024_378_9524-e1745920789871-1024x536.jpg</main_image>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Soft Top Defender makes a return with Land Rover Classic&#8217;s latest V8 Works model</title>
		<link>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/soft-top-defender-makes-a-return-with-land-rover-classics-latest-v8-works-model/</link>
					<comments>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/soft-top-defender-makes-a-return-with-land-rover-classics-latest-v8-works-model/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Hayward]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 09:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Restomods]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.octane-magazine.com/?p=83160</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Land Rover Classic revives the Defender Soft Top with a new V8-powered, bespoke-built model – hand-crafted from original 90 chassis]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Land Rover Classic has unveiled the Classic Defender V8 Works Bespoke Soft Top. The name might be a little long-winded, but it marks the latest in a now comprehensive line-up of restored and modern V8-powered Defenders, marking the long-awaited return of one of the most desirable Defender variants. </p><p>Built exclusively on short-wheelbase 90 chassis, the new V8 Soft Top revives the spirit of classic soft-top Defenders, such as the coveted NAS 90 of the 1990s. As with the previous V8 Works models, each vehicle is carefully sourced from 2012-2016 production and undergoes a comprehensive rebuild, including installation of Land Rover’s 5.0-litre naturally aspirated 405bhp V8 which is paired with an eight-speed ZF automatic gearbox.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="585" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_05_Rear34_v3a-1024x585.jpg" alt="Classic Defender V8 Works Bespoke Soft Top" class="wp-image-83165" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_05_Rear34_v3a-1024x585.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_05_Rear34_v3a-300x171.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_05_Rear34_v3a-768x439.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_05_Rear34_v3a-1536x877.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_05_Rear34_v3a-1200x685.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_05_Rear34_v3a-100x57.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_05_Rear34_v3a-640x366.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_05_Rear34_v3a.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>Every example is completely dismantled and rebuilt to OEM standards at Land Rover Classic’s Coventry headquarters. Suspension and braking systems have been comprehensively uprated, with bespoke Bilstein dampers, Eibach springs and anti-roll bars, and Alcon four-piston brakes bringing the driving dynamics up to modern expectations. <em>Octane</em> has driven the standard V8 Works as well as both Trophy and Trophy II cars, and can confirm that these are about as good as the classic Defender experience can be. </p><p>This version&#8217;s Soft Top’s bespoke canvas hood, available in four colours – Black, Sand, Dark Khaki and Navy – is inspired by the last Defender to roll off the Solihull line in 2016. Side and rear panels can be unzipped and rolled up for open-air driving, while tie-down points ensure stability even at speed. A ‘Bikini Hood’ option, covering only the front seats, is also available.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="660" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_06_Dash_v3a-1024x660.jpg" alt="Classic Defender V8 Works Bespoke Soft Top" class="wp-image-83164" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_06_Dash_v3a-1024x660.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_06_Dash_v3a-300x194.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_06_Dash_v3a-768x495.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_06_Dash_v3a-1536x991.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_06_Dash_v3a-1200x774.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_06_Dash_v3a-100x65.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_06_Dash_v3a-640x413.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_06_Dash_v3a.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>Customisation and customer experience is a huge part of the appeal. Buyers can personalise their Soft Top with 49 standard paint colours or commission a bespoke match-to-sample finish. Wheels are offered in either classic 16-inch Wolf steel rims or 18-inch Sawtooth alloys, with a range of finishes to suit individual tastes. Inside, five monotone and eight duo-tone leather upholstery options are available, including Caraway, Liberty Blue and Garnet, alongside custom touches such as onboard wine coolers or surfboard racks.</p><p>Dominic Elms, Director of Land Rover Classic, said: ‘With the Classic Defender V8 Soft Top, we provide an even greater opportunity to turn Classic Defender V8 dreams into reality. At Land Rover Classic we work with clients to provide a one‑to‑one bespoke service, so they can enjoy their vehicle safe in the knowledge it has been designed and engineered exclusively for them, by the original manufacturer – the people who know it best’</p><p>Prices for the new Classic Defender V8 Works Bespoke Soft Top start from £195,000 plus local taxes. Each vehicle is covered by a one-year unlimited mileage warranty and is supported directly by Land Rover Classic in Coventry and Essen.</p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_01_Overhead_v3a-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-83162" srcset="https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_01_Overhead_v3a-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_01_Overhead_v3a-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_01_Overhead_v3a-768x512.jpg 768w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_01_Overhead_v3a-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_01_Overhead_v3a-1200x800.jpg 1200w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_01_Overhead_v3a-100x67.jpg 100w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_01_Overhead_v3a-640x427.jpg 640w, https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_01_Overhead_v3a.jpg 1800w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p>For more information, see <a href="https://www.landrover.com/explore-land-rover/land-rover-classic/index.html"><strong>landrover.com</strong></a></p><p></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.octane-magazine.com/news/soft-top-defender-makes-a-return-with-land-rover-classics-latest-v8-works-model/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<main_image>https://www.octane-magazine.com/app/uploads/2025/04/1326_SC_HP_LRCLASSIC_V8_SOFTTOP_HERO_03_Front34_v3a-1024x585.jpg</main_image>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
