<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">

	<channel>
		<title>Wccftech</title>
		<atom:link href="https://wccftech.com/feed/?feed_name=purenews" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<link>https://wccftech.com/</link>
		<description>We bring you the latest from hardware, mobile and gaming industries in news, reviews, and guides.</description>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 21:04:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
		<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.8.2</generator>
		<item>
			<title>75% Keyboards Just Make More Sense than 60% Keyboards &#8211; Here&#8217;s Why Gamers (And Non-Gamers) Need To Step Up</title>
			<link>https://wccftech.com/75-keyboards-just-make-more-sense-than-60-keyboards/</link>

			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarfraz Khan]]></dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 19:53:02 +0000</pubDate>
			<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[75% Keyboard]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[gaming keyboards]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Keyboards]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[TKL Keyboard]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/?p=1661158</guid>

			<description><![CDATA[For a lot of gamers, a standard 104-key keyboard isn't the ideal form-factor as it makes the desk feel more cramped, giving less space for the mouse movements. Smaller form-factor keyboards exist for the same reason, but they come in a variety of sizes like TKL (TenKeyLess: around 87-88 keys), 80%, 75%, and even more compact options like 60% (reducing the number of keys to around 58-65). 60% keyboards are often preferred by many as they're one of the smallest form factors and offer almost all the necessary keys to get the job done without occupying your whole desk. Technically, [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>For a lot of gamers, a standard 104-key keyboard isn't the ideal form-factor as it makes the desk feel more cramped, giving less space for the mouse movements. Smaller form-factor keyboards exist for the same reason, but they come in a variety of sizes like TKL (TenKeyLess: around 87-88 keys), 80%, 75%, and even more compact options like 60% (reducing the number of keys to around 58-65). </p>



<p>60% keyboards are often preferred by many as they're one of the smallest form factors and offer almost all the necessary keys to get the job done without occupying your whole desk. Technically, it can do the job of full 104-key keyboards with key combinations and mapping, but that's tricky and time-consuming. A 75% keyboard is yet another option with somewhat bigger form factor than a 60% keyboard, but can be hugely advantageous for several reasons. </p>



<p>Here are the top four reasons why it's better to settle for a 75% keyboard than a 60% one, and you will be surprised at just how convenient it is.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-arrow-keys-save-you-from-the-headache">Arrow Keys Save You From The Headache</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image wp-lightbox size-full"><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-keyboard-2.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1920" height="1280" src="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-keyboard-2.jpg" alt="Unbranded keyboard with a distinctive yellow enter key on a desk." class="wp-image-1661366" srcset="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-keyboard-2.jpg 1920w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-keyboard-2-540x360.jpg 540w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-keyboard-2-728x485.jpg 728w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-keyboard-2-1456x971.jpg 1456w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Keyboards without arrow keys are like a mouse without a right-click; Image Credit: wccftech.com</figcaption></figure>



<p>Arrow keys are basically absent on almost all 60% keyboards, but 75% keyboard does a favor by simply using a little more space. A 65% keyboard also has arrow keys, but there are some caveats it comes with it, which we will be talking about in the next section. Now, switching from a full-length keyboard to a 60% keyboard is generally a difficult transition, as we frequently need the arrow keys for various tasks, including typing, editing, and sometimes playing games. By reducing the overall chassis size, the 60% keyboard tries to enable these arrow keys through a different layer. </p>



<p>On 60% keyboards, the arrow key functions can be generally achieved by pressing FN+A/W/S/D, but that's going to be quite difficult in the beginning and will consume a lot of time. This can be a pain when there is a need to press an arrow key and another key to execute a particular function, because you then have to press three keys simultaneously. For instance, jumping word by word when typing/editing requires pressing CTRL+Right/Left Arrow key, and on a 60% keyboard, you will have to press CTRL+FN+A/D key to achieve the same. Thankfully, a 75% keyboard keeps these onboard and saves you from this headache.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-function-keys-row-is-a-dealbreaker">The Function Keys Row is a Dealbreaker </h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image wp-lightbox size-full"><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-keyboard.jpg"><img decoding="async" width="1920" height="1080" src="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-keyboard.jpg" alt="Unbranded keyboard with Esc and function keys F1-F5." class="wp-image-1661365" srcset="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-keyboard.jpg 1920w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-keyboard-564x317.jpg 564w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-keyboard-728x410.jpg 728w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-keyboard-1456x819.jpg 1456w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Function keys on 75% keyboards retain good functionality and versatility; Image Credit: wccftech.com</figcaption></figure>



<p>The Function keys (F1-F12), which are usually present at the top, serve a lot of applications, and whether you want to refresh your computer or quickly open the Inspect tab, you will need them. A 60% keyboard has the entire row absent (65% keyboard as well), and to get those working, it uses a third layer, which can be accessed through a particular button combo, which usually requires pressing three keys simultaneously.</p>



<p>It would have made more sense if you could just access the function keys by pressing the FN button with the number keys, but since the number keys already have another layer for symbols, you will have to press a third key to get those. So, for most 60% keyboards, you will have to press the FN+Shift+Number Key to get a function key working, which is so frustrating. Therefore, the availability of the entire Function Row on the 75% keyboard is so convenient.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-you-re-still-gonna-have-a-small-footprint">You're Still Gonna Have a Small Footprint</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image wp-lightbox size-full"><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-vs-65-percent-keyboard-1.jpg"><img decoding="async" width="1920" height="1280" src="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-vs-65-percent-keyboard-1.jpg" alt="Unbranded keyboards on a black desk mat." class="wp-image-1661364" srcset="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-vs-65-percent-keyboard-1.jpg 1920w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-vs-65-percent-keyboard-1-540x360.jpg 540w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-vs-65-percent-keyboard-1-728x485.jpg 728w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-vs-65-percent-keyboard-1-1456x971.jpg 1456w" sizes="(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">75% keyboards are mostly bigger due to height, but length-wise, the difference is around 1 inch; Image Credit: wccftech.com</figcaption></figure>



<p>I understand that the 60% keyboard is smaller than a 75% keyboard, but the difference isn't huge. You get an additional inch or two added to the height and length, but that's it. This isn't really a dealbreaker since you will still get enough space for mouse movement, but you will have immense versatility with those extra keys. The amount of key combinations you have to get used to on a 60% keyboard is just overwhelming, and it hurts productivity.</p>



<p>Some 75% keyboards have almost the same length as most 60% keyboards, which essentially gives you the same amount of space for your mouse movements. And that additional &lt;1" space gives you three more keys like Home, Page Up, and Page Down for additional functions. And yes, you also get a dedicated Delete button on the top row, which is a frequently used key.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-dedicated-multi-media-options-will-likely-be-available">Dedicated Multi-Media Options Will Likely Be Available</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image wp-lightbox size-full"><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-keyboard-4.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1920" height="1280" src="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-keyboard-4.jpg" alt="White keyboard with keys labeled Delete, Backspace, Home, PgUp, PgDn, and a volume knob." class="wp-image-1661363" srcset="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-keyboard-4.jpg 1920w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-keyboard-4-540x360.jpg 540w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-keyboard-4-728x485.jpg 728w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-keyboard-4-1456x971.jpg 1456w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Most 75% keyboards come with a Volume knob, but some come with even more multimedia keys; Image Credit: wccftech.com</figcaption></figure>



<p>Multimedia keys or volume knobs are almost absent on all 60% keyboards, but they are quite handy. Dedicated multi-media controls are usually more abundant on full-length keyboards, but many 75% keyboards do have a few of them. The most common multimedia control on 75% keyboards is the Volume knob, and once you start using it, you won't go back. Using a mouse for simple tasks like increasing or decreasing volume feels cumbersome, but a knob does both jobs and can also mute. </p>



<p>I don't know how popular the Play, Pause, and Stop multimedia keys are among users, but the Volume knob is one of the most convenient multimedia controls to have at your fingertips. Some exceptions are keyboards like <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0CT2HDJMS/?tag=wccftech0a9-20" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Redragon K655</a>, which replaces the Function keys row with a dedicated multimedia row, but personally, I would trade multimedia controls for a function row any day.</p>



<p>That said, we all have preferences, but swapping a 60% keyboard with a 75% one has always felt better. More keys don't necessarily mean more convenience, but the reason why most opt for 60% is the smaller footprint. However, I see hardly any benefit in going smaller than 75%, unless you really don't have that additional inch of space on your desk.</p>
]]>			</content:encoded>



			<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Op-Ed]]></category>
			<media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/75-percent-vs-65-percent-keyboard-1456x819.jpg" width="1456" height="819" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ubisoft Might&#8217;ve Shut Down The Crew&#8217;s Servers, But The Crew Unlimited Community Effort Has Brought the Game Back to Life</title>
			<link>https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-shut-down-the-crew-but-the-crew-unlimited-brought-it-back-to-life/</link>

			<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Carcasole]]></dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 18:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
			<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[The crew]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[The Crew Unlimited]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Ubisoft]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/?p=1661348</guid>

			<description><![CDATA[Ubisoft shut down the servers for its open-world MMO racing game, The Crew, on March 31, 2024. It was unfortunate news, but not particularly surprising in today's modern age of online games having an expiration date of 'whenever the developer decides it can't/won't pay for the servers anymore.' But while the occurrence of online games being shuttered is now commonplace, The Crew's shutdown sparked something more. It not only sparked a lawsuit that made players more aware than ever that they've always been buying a license to play a game, instead of a copy of a game. It sparked enough [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Ubisoft shut down the servers for its open-world MMO racing game, The Crew, on <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-us/help/purchases-and-rewards/article/decommissioning-of-online-services-for-older-legacy-ubisoft-games-n-to-z/000105855">March 31, 2024</a>. It was unfortunate news, but not particularly surprising in today's modern age of online games having an expiration date of 'whenever the developer decides it can't/won't pay for the servers anymore.' But while the occurrence of online games being shuttered is now commonplace, The Crew's shutdown sparked something more.</p>



<p>It not only sparked a lawsuit that made players more aware than ever that they've <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-responds-to-the-crew-lawsuit-tells-prosecuting-players-they-never-owned-their-games/">always been buying a license to play a game</a>, instead of a copy of a game. It sparked enough backlash that Ubisoft committed to <a href="https://wccftech.com/ubisoft-says-the-crew-2-and-the-crew-motorfest-will-get-offline-modes/">adding offline modes for The Crew 2 and The Crew Motorfest</a>. It caused enough uproar that <a href="https://www.videogameschronicle.com/news/steam-now-warns-players-theyre-only-buying-a-license-to-a-game-at-checkout/">Valve added a warning to Steam purchases</a>, making it clear to players they're buying a license to play a game, instead of a copy of the game. And, perhaps most significantly, it was the match that lit the flame under the <a href="https://wccftech.com/publishers-argue-stop-killing-games-proposals-would-make-online-games-prohibitively-expensive/">Stop Killing Games Initiative</a>.</p>



<p>While the Stop Killing Games and the Stop Destroying Videogames initiatives and petitions continue, and the lawsuit two Californian The Crew fans began is still underway, a group called <a href="https://thecrewunlimited.com/about/">The Crew Unlimited (TCU)</a> has been working hard to bring The Crew back the old-fashioned way, by creating an emulator to run the servers on.</p>



<p>Today, <a href="https://thecrewunlimited.com/news/?post=news-tcu-release">TCU realized its goal</a>, and players with a copy of the game can jump back into The Crew thanks to their hard work.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="IT&#039;S BACK! Playing The Crew 1 in 2025!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mqbKAMq029A?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>If you own a copy of The Crew on PC, then you should be able to set TCU up for yourself to continue playing a game that's shutdown seems to have had more of an impact on the videogame industry than it did when it was still being distributed by Ubisoft.</p>
]]>			</content:encoded>



			<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
			<media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/The-Crew-Lawsuit.jpg" width="1280" height="720" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Apple Releases visionOS 26 and tvOS 26 With Widgets, Updated Personas, Safari Enhancements, and More</title>
			<link>https://wccftech.com/apple-releases-visionos-26-tvos-26-features/</link>

			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ali Salman]]></dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:29:38 +0000</pubDate>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[tvOS 26]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[visionOS 26]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/?p=1661277</guid>

			<description><![CDATA[Today, Apple has seen fit to release visionOS 26 and tvOS 26 to the public for all compatible devices. The latest updates arrive a week after the company seeded the release candidate builds to developers. If you are interested, visionOS 26 and tvOS 26 can be downloaded on all compatible Vision Pro and Apple TV models for free. Apple rolls out visionOS 26 and tvOS 26 with major interface changes, upgraded features, and much more visionOS 26 can be downloaded on the Vision Pro headset by navigating to the Settings app, then selecting General and then clicking on the Software [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Today, Apple has seen fit to release visionOS 26 and tvOS 26 to the public for all compatible devices. The latest updates arrive a week after the company seeded the <a href="https://wccftech.com/ios-26-ipados-26-release-candidate-liquid-glass/">release candidate </a>builds to developers. If you are interested, visionOS 26 and tvOS 26 can be downloaded on all compatible Vision Pro and Apple TV models for free.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-apple-rolls-out-visionos-26-and-tvos-26-with-major-interface-changes-upgraded-features-and-much-more">Apple rolls out visionOS 26 and tvOS 26 with major interface changes, upgraded features, and much more</h2>



<p>visionOS 26 can be downloaded on the Vision Pro headset by navigating to the Settings app, then selecting General and then clicking on the Software Update option. To install the update, the Vision Pro needs to be removed and you will see the progress bar ib the front EyeSight display. </p>



<p>visionOS is a <a href="https://wccftech.com/apple-officially-announces-visionos-26/">major update</a> bringing a new class of widgets that can be integrated into the space around you. Personas have also been upgraded with more lifelike hair and movement, Sparial Scenes have been updated to add depth to 2D images, along with a handful of Safari improvements.</p>



<p>As mentioned, the company has also released tvOS 26 that can run on the Apple TV 4K. To install the latest build, all you have to do is launch the Settings app and go to the Software Update section. if you have automatic updates enabled, the latest tvOS 26 build will be installed automatically. </p>



<p>Similar to the rest of the updates, tvOS 26 has new poster art and an iterface that displays more movies and shows at once. Profiles can also be shown when the AppleTV wakes up from sleep, which makes it easier for each person to select their personalized settings and recommendations. The iPhone can now also serve as a mic when using Apple Music Sing with support for Lyrics Translation and pronunciation. We will be sharing additional details on the updates, so do keep an eye out. </p>
]]>			</content:encoded>



			<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
			<media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Vision-Pro-Title-1456x819.jpg" width="1456" height="819" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Xiaomi Skips A Number For Its Latest Smartphones To Better Align With Apple&#8217;s iPhone 17, Announces The &#8220;Most Significant Leap Forward&#8221; With The Xiaomi 17 Smartphones</title>
			<link>https://wccftech.com/xiaomi-skips-a-number-for-its-latest-smartphones-to-better-align-with-apples-iphone-17-announces-the-most-significant-leap-forward-with-the-xiaomi-17-smartphones/</link>

			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rohail Saleem]]></dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
			<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[iPhone 17]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[xiaomi]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Xiaomi 17]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/?p=1661318</guid>

			<description><![CDATA[One should never discount the inordinate capacity of Chinese smartphone manufacturers to mimic Apple to the umpteenth extent. As a case in point, consider the fact that Xiaomi has now skipped an entire number and changed the naming convention for its upcoming smartphone lineup, all to better align itself with Apple's iPhone 17. To wit, Xiaomi was due to launch its 16-series smartphones in the next few weeks. However, the company has now skipped the 16th-gen label and jumped straight to the 17-series label for its upcoming smartphone lineup. What's more, in what is likely a nod to Apple's naming [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>One should never discount the inordinate capacity of Chinese smartphone manufacturers to mimic Apple to the umpteenth extent. As a case in point, consider the fact that Xiaomi has now skipped an entire number and changed the naming convention for its upcoming smartphone lineup, all to better align itself with Apple's iPhone 17.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">xiaomi’s NEVER beating the iPhone copy allegations <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/16.0.1/72x72/1f62d.png" alt="😭" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br><br>their last phones were called the Xiaomi 15, Xiaomi 15 Pro, and Xiaomi 15 Ultra<br><br>this year, they’ve completely skipped the 16 series and also changed the naming system to Xiaomi 17, Xiaomi 17 Pro, and Xiaomi 17 Pro Max <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/16.0.1/72x72/1f926.png" alt="🤦" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> <a href="https://t.co/JF44UphNz5">pic.twitter.com/JF44UphNz5</a></p>&mdash; System Settings (@app_settings) <a href="https://twitter.com/app_settings/status/1967507359028420894?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 15, 2025</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>To wit, Xiaomi was due to launch its 16-series smartphones in the next few weeks. However, the company has now skipped the 16th-gen label and jumped straight to the 17-series label for its upcoming smartphone lineup. What's more, in what is likely a nod to Apple's naming convention for its top-of-the-line iPhone model, Xiaomi has changed the name of its high-end 'Ultra' variant to 'Pro Max.' </p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Xiaomi just announced the all-new 17 Series - their “biggest upgrade ever”, coming a month earlier than usual. Three models are coming:<br><br>• Xiaomi 17<br>• Xiaomi 17 Pro<br>• Xiaomi 17 Pro Max<br><br>Larger Pro displays, major camera upgrades and a serious performance leap. Big move for… <a href="https://t.co/KKHqG2DXWZ">pic.twitter.com/KKHqG2DXWZ</a></p>&mdash; Ben Geskin (@BenGeskin) <a href="https://twitter.com/BenGeskin/status/1967477976406110479?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 15, 2025</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>Xiaomi claims in a <a href="https://preview.redd.it/snapdragon-8-elite-gen-5-name-official-qualcomm-announced-v0-0skjuds3q8pf1.png?width=1035&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=7f9152850f2dcea3bfc072c3e767d8003fc974d7">Weibo post</a> that its upcoming 17-series smartphone lineup is its "most significant leap forward." Notably, its base smartphone is expected to experience no price hikes, despite a material performance upgrade, thanks to Qualcomm's most advanced processor to-date: the Snapdragon 8 Elite Gen 5 SoC.</p>



<p>Do note that the Xiaomi 15 smartphone launched at a price point of 4,499 CNY or around $630. This means that the upcoming base variant of the Xiaomi 17 lineup is also expected to launch at around this price point.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Weibo user guarantees this is Xiaomi 17 Pro Max.<br><br>Design = Xiaomi 11 Ultra rear display energy. <a href="https://t.co/49c41Q6kaI">pic.twitter.com/49c41Q6kaI</a></p>&mdash; Abhishek Yadav (@yabhishekhd) <a href="https://twitter.com/yabhishekhd/status/1967527561296281988?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 15, 2025</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>Elsewhere, as per a leaked tidbit, the Xiaomi 17 Pro Max is also expected to feature a rear display, which <a href="https://www.gadgets360.com/mobiles/news/xiaomi-17-pro-max-rear-display-design-render-leaked-september-launch-confirmed-9280927/">aligns</a> with a previous rumor for the now-skipped 16th gen Xiaomi smartphones. Specifically, as per the leaked information, the rear display will be integrated within the back-camera island of sorts, and would likely serve as a handy tool to remain abreast with upcoming notifications without having to pick up the smartphone.</p>



<p>The render in the above X post also features a third camera module below the primary one, which is likely to be an ultra-wide angle camera lens.</p>
]]>			</content:encoded>



			<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
			<media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Xiaomi-17-1-1456x1092.jpg" width="1456" height="1092" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Samsung One UI 8 Rollout: Android 16 Update Begins With Galaxy S25, Expanding To Older Devices Through 2025</title>
			<link>https://wccftech.com/samsung-one-ui-8-rollout-android-16-update-begins-with-galaxy-s25-expanding-to-older-devices-through-2025/</link>

			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ezza Ijaz]]></dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:17:52 +0000</pubDate>
			<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/?p=1661303</guid>

			<description><![CDATA[Samsung has been criticized in the past for its snail-paced schedules for software updates, but it seems like the tech giant has pivoted in a different direction with its One UI 8 by opting for a more transparent and structured process that lets users know where the company is headed and what to expect. Continuing with this strategy, the company has officially started rolling out its One UI 8 update based on Android 16, spelling out the device schedule. Samsung rolls out One UI 8 with Android 16: here is the updated timeline for Galaxy devices With Samsung rolling out [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Samsung has been criticized in the past for its snail-paced schedules for software<a href="https://wccftech.com/android-16-qpr2-beta-1-features/"> updates</a>, but it seems like the tech giant has pivoted in a different direction with its One UI 8 by opting for a more transparent and structured process that lets users know where the company is headed and what to expect. Continuing with this strategy, the company has officially started rolling out its One UI 8 update based on Android 16, spelling out the device schedule.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-samsung-rolls-out-one-ui-8-with-android-16-here-is-the-updated-timeline-for-galaxy-devices">Samsung rolls out One UI 8 with Android 16: here is the updated timeline for Galaxy devices</h2>



<p>With Samsung<a href="https://sammyguru.com/breaking-one-ui-8-stable-update-released-for-galaxy-s25-series/"> rolling out</a> One UI 8 with Android 16, many have expected how the South Korean tech giant would approach the update, and it seems to mirror the anticipation. As expected, the company will begin with its latest flagship models and then move down to foldables, tablets, and lastly, mid-range devices.</p>



<p>When you look at Samsung's update schedule, the first in line is the Galaxy S25 series, which includes the S25, S25 Plus, and S25 Ultra, along with the S25 Edge model. This update started rolling out on September 15, 2025. Samsung is ensuring that the latest flagship models are updated with the new software without any delays.</p>



<p>The latest flagship series' predecessor, the Galaxy S24 lineup, which includes the FE model, will follow. After this will be the Galaxy Z Fold 6, Z Flip 6, and Z Fold Special Edition. The Galaxy S23, S23 Plus, S23 Ultra, and S23 FE will all be getting the update, as will the S22 series. Selected A-series models, like the A36, A35, A25, A56, and A53, will also receive the latest version. Samsung seems to be stretching out the schedule through the rest of the year, with many Galaxy tablets also expected to get the update by late October.</p>



<p>Older Galaxy devices will receive the update in a phased rollout that will continue through the end of 2025. While the company has painted a clear picture of the devices getting the update, the latest interface does not merely revolve around bringing some basic changes. Users can expect big improvements, such as in privacy and security capabilities, AI-powered tools, multitasking, and more enhanced and smoother animations. The system apps will also be seeing improvements.</p>



<p>Several factors, such as the region, carrier, and device model, can still influence the timeline of the update landing on your devices, but those with the latest flagships can be assured they will not be the ones waiting the longest. Overall, One UI 8 appears to be a meaningful update packed with tons of advanced features and improvements.</p>



<p></p>



<p></p>
]]>			</content:encoded>



			<media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Galaxy-S25-series-1456x971.jpg" width="1456" height="971" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Apple Has Released watchOS 26 To The Public For All Supported Apple Watch Models</title>
			<link>https://wccftech.com/watchos-26-release-apple-watch-update-features/</link>

			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ali Salman]]></dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:07:48 +0000</pubDate>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[watchOS 26]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[watchOS 26 Released]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/?p=1661255</guid>

			<description><![CDATA[After months of anticipation, watchOS 26 has finally been released to the general public, which means that all compatible models can now head over to the Settings app and download it right away. The update is available for free and brings a handful of new features and changes to the Apple Watch. Apple has finally released watchOS 26 with new features, updated UI, and much more Unlike the beta updates, the final watchOS 26 build does not require you to connect your Apple ID to your Developer Account. The update will show up in the Apple Watch app on your [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After months of anticipation, watchOS 26 has finally been released to the general public, which means that all <a href="https://wccftech.com/watchos-26-supported-apple-watch-models/">compatible models</a> can now head over to the Settings app and download it right away. The update is available for free and brings a handful of new features and changes to the Apple Watch.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-apple-has-finally-released-watchos-26-with-new-features-updated-ui-and-much-more">Apple has finally released watchOS 26 with new features, updated UI, and much more</h2>



<p>Unlike the beta updates, the final watchOS 26 build does not require you to connect your Apple ID to your Developer Account. The update will show up in the Apple Watch app on your iPhone automatically, but before you download it, there are a few prerequisites that you have to follow to ensure an uninterrupted installation experience.</p>



<p>The first thing you must make sure of is to create ample space for the update to be downloaded and installed. You can delete unwanted apps and files from the Apple Watch, which will create the necessary storage space required for the update. Secondly, your Apple Watch should be at least 50 percent charged and placed on a charger to download and install the watchOS 26 update. If it is not, the installation process will not begin, and it will keep reminding you to charge your Apple Watch. Your Apple Watch should also be connected to a secure Wi-Fi network to download the update. Lastly, your Apple Watch should be within range of your iPhone, as it is receiving all the data from the smartphone.</p>



<p>To install the update, simply launch the Apple Watch app on your iPhone and navigate to General &gt; Software Update and follow the on-screen instructions to download the update. The process is fairly simple and does not require any third-party help. The Apple Watch will restart once the process is complete, and you will have to enter your passcode.</p>



<p>watchOS 26 is a <a href="https://wccftech.com/watchos-26-announced-with-new-liquid-design-language-apple-intelligence-features-wrist-flick-gesture-workout-buddy-and-more/">major update</a> that brings a plethora of new utilities and features to the table. The update is designed to take advantage of the bigger Apple Watch displays. In addition, the company has also added under-the-hood improvements for a smoother user experience. We will be covering more details on the watchOS 26 update, so be sure to keep an eye out.</p>
]]>			</content:encoded>



			<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
			<media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/IMG_0171-1456x813.jpg" width="1456" height="813" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Download: macOS Tahoe 26 Released for All Macs With Liquid Glass Redesign and Major Productivity Upgrades</title>
			<link>https://wccftech.com/macos-tahoe-26-release-liquid-glass-upgrade/</link>

			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ali Salman]]></dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:07:26 +0000</pubDate>
			<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[macOS Tahoe 26]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[macOS Tahoe Released]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/?p=1661235</guid>

			<description><![CDATA[A week after Apple seeded the release candidate build to developers, macOS Tahoe 26 has finally been released for all supported Macs. The update is finally out of the beta and testing cycle, which means that everyone can enjoy the new Liquid Glass redesigned interface along with a plethora of new productivity upgrades. Apple finally releases macOS Tahoe 26 to the public for all compatible Macs - Download Now! Since macOS Tahoe 26 is out of the beta cycle, you are not required to link your Apple ID to your Developer Account. What this means is that the update will [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A week after Apple seeded the <a href="https://wccftech.com/macos-tahoe-26-release-candidate-liquid-glass/">release candidate build</a> to developers, macOS Tahoe 26 has finally been released for all supported Macs. The update is finally out of the beta and testing cycle, which means that everyone can enjoy the new Liquid Glass redesigned interface along with a plethora of new productivity upgrades.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-apple-finally-releases-macos-tahoe-26-to-the-public-for-all-compatible-macs-download-now">Apple finally releases macOS Tahoe 26 to the public for all compatible Macs - Download Now!</h2>



<p>Since macOS Tahoe 26 is out of the beta cycle, you are not required to link your Apple ID to your Developer Account. What this means is that the update will show up in Settings without you having to do anything. However, there are some prerequisites that you have to follow to install the update on your compatible Mac.</p>



<p>You have to make sure that your Mac has some free storage space, as it could become a hurdle in the download process later on. We would advise you to have at least 20GB of free space before you begin the download process for a seamless experience. Other than this, you are also advised to keep your MacBook models charged during the download and installation process. It is wise to plug into a power source for an uninterrupted operation. Lastly, make sure that your Mac is connected to a secure internet connection.</p>



<p>To install the macOS Tahoe 26 update on your Mac, all you have to do is head over to the Software Update section in System Settings and follow the on-screen instructions. The process is fairly simple and requires no third-party help.</p>



<p>macOS Tahoe is a <a href="https://wccftech.com/macos-tahoe-brings-liquid-glass-ui-new-spotlight-games-app-more/">noticeable update</a> over the current version as it brings a plethora of upgrades to the mix of utilities. The company has also introduced the Liquid Glass redesign for macOS, which puts the platform in line with iOS as well as iPadOS. There are a handful of productivity upgrades and updates for existing features, so be sure to check that out as well. We will be covering more details on macOS Tahoe, so be sure to stick around. Let us know in the comments if you are looking to install the latest update today or wait for a stable build free of initial bugs and issues?</p>
]]>			</content:encoded>



			<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
			<media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/IMG_0146-2-e1757946108535.jpg" width="1456" height="804" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Download: Apple Releases iOS 26 Final Update For All iPhone Models</title>
			<link>https://wccftech.com/ios-26-release-liquid-glass-download-install/</link>

			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ali Salman]]></dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
			<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[iOS 26]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[iPhone update]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/?p=1661199</guid>

			<description><![CDATA[iOS 26 is finally out of the testing phase, as Apple has released it to the general public. If you happen to have a compatible iPhone, you can download and install the latest stable build through the stock Settings app. The public release comes a week after the company seeded the release candidate builds to developers for final testing and bug fixes. If you are unsure, also check out how you can download iOS 26 on your iPhone. Apple releases iOS 26 to the public for all compatible iPhone models - Here's how to download iOS 26 is a major [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>iOS 26 is finally out of the testing phase, as Apple has released it to the general public. If you happen to have a compatible iPhone, you can download and install the latest stable build through the stock Settings app. The public release comes a week after the company seeded the <a href="https://www.google.com/search?client=safari&amp;rls=en&amp;q=iOS+26+release+candidate+wccftech&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;oe=UTF-8">release candidate</a> builds to developers for final testing and bug fixes. If you are unsure, also check out how you can download iOS 26 on your iPhone.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-apple-releases-ios-26-to-the-public-for-all-compatible-iphone-models-here-s-how-to-download">Apple releases iOS 26 to the public for all compatible iPhone models - Here's how to download</h2>



<p>iOS 26 is a major update, considering the number of front-facing features it brings to the table. You not only get a new redesigned Liquid Glass interface, but the company has also made sure that there are new additions and extensions for existing features. Since iOS 26 has been publicly released, you no longer need a Developer Account to download and install it. However, you do need to prepare your iPhone for the update.</p>



<p>Make sure that your iPhone has free storage for the update, and Apple recommends a total of 20GB at least for a smooth and seamless download process. Additionally, make sure that your iPhone has enough battery life during the installation process, and we recommend that you connect a charger. This is because if your device shuts down during the installation process, it could create serious issues, which would require you to get professional help to revive your iPhone. Lastly, your compatible iPhone should also be connected to a secure internet connection to download the update.</p>



<p>To install the update, all you have to do is launch the Settings app on your iPhone and navigate to General > Software Update and then follow the on-screen instructions to download the latest iOS 26 update. The process could take some time, depending on the speed of your internet connection, so do not be alarmed. </p>



<p>Since the iOS 26 update is being released across the globe, if the update is not showing up in the Software Update section, we would advise you to wait. This is because Apple’s servers are quite busy soon after a <a href="https://wccftech.com/apple-announces-ios-26-with-new-glass-dsign-updated-features-more/">major update</a> has been released. We will be covering the update in extensive detail, so be sure to keep an eye out.</p>
]]>			</content:encoded>



			<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Software]]></category>
			<media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Screenshot-2025-09-15-at-6.08.25-PM-1456x810.png" width="1456" height="810" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Download: iPadOS 26 Has Been Released To the Public For All Supported iPad Models</title>
			<link>https://wccftech.com/ipados-26-release-for-all-ipad-models/</link>

			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ali Salman]]></dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
			<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[iPadOS 26]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[ipadOS 26 Released]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/?p=1661223</guid>

			<description><![CDATA[Apple has finally seen fit to release iPadOS 26 to the public, making it available on all compatible iPad models, ranging from the entry-level iPad to the latest iPad Pro. If you are up for it, the latest update can be downloaded through the stock Settings app on your iPad. Since it is a brand-new update with a brand-new Liquid Glass redesign, we would recommend that you follow instructions carefully before installing. Apple’s iPadOS 26 public release brings Liquid Glass redesign, multitasking, and resizable windows to all compatible iPad models As mentioned, iPadOS 26 is a significant update which finally [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Apple has finally seen fit to release iPadOS 26 to the public, making it available on all compatible iPad models, ranging from the entry-level iPad to the latest iPad Pro. If you are up for it, the latest update can be downloaded through the stock Settings app on your iPad. Since it is a brand-new update with a brand-new Liquid Glass redesign, we would recommend that you follow instructions carefully before installing.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-apple-s-ipados-26-public-release-brings-liquid-glass-redesign-multitasking-and-resizable-windows-to-all-compatible-ipad-models">Apple’s iPadOS 26 public release brings Liquid Glass redesign, multitasking, and resizable windows to all compatible iPad models</h2>



<p>As mentioned, iPadOS 26 is a significant update which finally justifies the hardware of the iPad Pro and utilizes the bigger screen real estate. Since it is a public build, you no longer have to connect your Apple ID to your <a href="https://wccftech.com/ios-26-ipados-26-release-candidate-liquid-glass/">Developer Account</a> to receive the update over the air. Instead, Apple will just display the update on all compatible iPad models. To install the update, there are some prerequisites that you have to follow, which will allow you to safely download the build and avoid unnecessary issues.</p>



<p>Make sure that your iPad Pro has enough free storage for the iPadOS 26 update to be downloaded. We recommend that you keep at least 20GB free for the update to download without interruptions. Make sure that your iPad also has ample battery left, and if it does not, we would advise you to connect it to a charger during the installation process. Lastly, your iPad should be connected to a secure internet connection for the update.</p>



<p>To download and install iPadOS 26 on your iPad, the process is pretty straightforward and the same as the iPhone. All you have to do is launch the Settings app and head over to General &gt; Software Update and follow the on-screen instructions to download it on your device. After downloading has finished, you will be guided to install the update, unless you have set it to install overnight.</p>



<p>iPadOS 26 is a <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-ipados-multitasking-features-to-make-ipad-more-mac-like/">major update</a>, which brings the iPad closer to the Mac in terms of functionality and visual design. Apple has finally listened to users and given them proper multitasking capabilities with resizable windows, a new menu bar up top, a proper mouse pointer, and much more. It also features enhancements under the hood for improved overall performance. Are you planning to download the latest update or waiting for iOS 26.1?</p>
]]>			</content:encoded>



			<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
			<media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Screenshot-2025-09-15-at-6.31.39-PM-1456x774.png" width="1456" height="774" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Initiative Head Leaves Xbox Following Perfect Dark Remake Cancellation, Feels &#8216;Pride for What We Accomplished Together&#8217;</title>
			<link>https://wccftech.com/the-initiative-studio-head-leaves-xbox-feels-pride-perfect-dark-remake/</link>

			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alessio Palumbo]]></dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Darrell Gallagher]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[perfect dark remake]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[the initiative]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Xbox]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/?p=1661321</guid>

			<description><![CDATA[A couple of hours ago, Initiative Studio Head Darrell Gallagher announced on LinkedIn that he's leaving Xbox. He expressed his pride in the work done by the development team on the Perfect Dark remake despite its final cancellation by Microsoft. After an incredible journey, my time at Xbox has come to a close with the wind-down of Perfect Dark and The Initiative. I couldn’t be prouder of the talented and passionate team I had the privilege assemble and lead. Together, we set out to reimagine an iconic franchise and poured creativity, craft, and dedication into every step of the way. The public [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A couple of hours ago, <span style="box-sizing: border-box; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Initiative Studio Head Darrell Gallagher announced <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7373350179040714752/" target="_blank">on LinkedIn</a> that he's leaving Xbox. He expressed his pride in the work done by the development team on the Perfect Dark remake</span> despite its final cancellation by Microsoft.</p>



<p><em>After an incredible journey, my time at Xbox has come to a close with the wind-down of Perfect Dark and The Initiative. I couldn’t be prouder of the talented and passionate team I had the privilege assemble and lead. Together, we set out to reimagine an iconic franchise and poured creativity, craft, and dedication into every step of the way. The public reception and excitement for what we were building has been inspiring and deeply appreciated by all of us.</em></p>



<p><em>While this chapter is ending sooner than hoped, the spirit, talent, and achievements of the team will live on well beyond the project. I’m grateful to Xbox for the opportunity, to our partners for their support, and to the community for their belief in what we were creating. I leave with nothing but pride in what we accomplished together and excitement for what’s next — both for myself and for the amazing developers I was fortunate enough to work with.</em></p>



<p>The Perfect Dark project was officially <a href="https://wccftech.com/perfect-dark-cancelled-the-initiative-shut-down-microsoft-layoffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">canceled</a> over two months ago, but Gallagher is only formally announcing his departure from The Initiative now because, as Jason Schreier <a href="https://wccftech.com/perfect-dark-nearly-saved-take-two-deal-fell-through/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reported</a> earlier this month, there was a last-ditch attempt to save the project by selling the game rights to Take-Two Interactive. Unfortunately, no agreement was ever reached between Take-Two and Microsoft, who could not find common ground on who would remain the long-term owner of the storied franchise.</p>



<p>Gallagher was Studio Head of The Initiative for seven and a half years. Before that, his career includes tenures at Sony, Rockstar, THQ, and Crystal Dynamics, where he began as Director of Art and was then promoted to Studio Head, leading the Tomb Raider reboot trilogy, which is the main reason he was picked to reboot Perfect Dark. Between Crystal Dynamics and The Initiative, he worked for two years at Activision as Senior VP and Head of Development. He is credited for Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice, Call of Duty: Modern Warfare - Remastered, Call of Duty: WWII, Call of Duty: Infinite Warfare, Destiny 2, Skylanders: Imaginators, and Crash Bandicoot: N. Sane Trilogy.</p>
]]>			</content:encoded>



			<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
			<media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/WCCFperfectdark2-HD-1456x819.jpg" width="1456" height="819" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds Calls Out Mario Kart in New Trailer Ahead of Launch Next Week</title>
			<link>https://wccftech.com/sonic-racing-crossworlds-calls-out-mario-kart-in-new-trailer-ahead-of-launch/</link>

			<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Carcasole]]></dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 16:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
			<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Mario Kart]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Mario Kart World]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[SEGA]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[sonic]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Sonic Racing: Crossworlds]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/?p=1661314</guid>

			<description><![CDATA[SEGA's latest trailer for the next Sonic game calls out Nintendo, and no, we've not time-travelled back to the 80s/90s. Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds is due out next week at the time of this writing on September 25, 2025, and ahead of that launch, and the release of a demo this coming Wednesday, September 17, SEGA put out a new trailer showcasing CrossWorlds that included a coy call out to Nintendo's Mario Kart franchise. The trailer is titled, "Come Race on Our Level," and begins with a blurred image of Mario Kart on one screen with a narrator saying, "We all [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>SEGA's latest trailer for the next Sonic game calls out Nintendo, and no, we've not time-travelled back to the 80s/90s. Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds is due out next week at the time of this writing on September 25, 2025, and ahead of that launch, and the release of a demo this coming Wednesday, September 17, SEGA put out a new trailer showcasing CrossWorlds that included a coy call out to Nintendo's Mario Kart franchise.</p>



<p>The trailer is titled, "<em>Come Race on Our Level</em>," and begins with a blurred image of Mario Kart on one screen with a narrator saying, "<em>We all know that kart racing game. It's great. We don't need to show it to you.</em>"</p>



<p>"<em>But what if you can blast through and race on a whole other level?</em>,<em>"</em> the narrator continues, before diving into a showcase of gameplay from Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds - Come Race on Our Level Commercial" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CYOfP1a7xjc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>The trailer goes on to list a few gameplay features in Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds, and before it ends, takes one more shot at Mario Kart, though the second seems more specifically targeted at <a href="https://wccftech.com/review/mario-kart-world/">Mario Kart World</a>, by listing a slew of features in CrossWorlds and then saying, "<em>Or, what if you want to roam around on the open road?</em>"</p>



<p>It's all just a bit of fun, of course, but there's a certain tinge of nostalgia the comes from seeing SEGA pull stunts like this.</p>



<p>In any case, players will be able to make up their own minds if Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds will be worth picking up for their Nintendo Switch 2 consoles or other devices, as a demo will be available on all platforms tomorrow.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">A free, single-player demo for Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds will be arriving Wednesday, September 17 at 12:01AM (ET)!<br><br>Now&#39;s your chance to try out the game ahead of its official release! <a href="https://t.co/t1ItHIcRiP">pic.twitter.com/t1ItHIcRiP</a></p>&mdash; Sonic the Hedgehog (@sonic_hedgehog) <a href="https://twitter.com/sonic_hedgehog/status/1965807483630330188?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 10, 2025</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>When <a href="https://wccftech.com/sonic-racing-crossworlds-gamescom-hands-on-preview-racing-to-the-top/">Wccftech's Francesco De Meo checked out Sonic Racing: CrossWorlds at Gamescom 2025</a>, he wrote, "<em>the experience I had was more than enough to make me hunger for more and see for myself how all of these advanced mechanics will come together at higher difficulties and in online play</em>."</p>



<p></p>
]]>			</content:encoded>



			<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
			<media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Sonic-Racing-CrossWorlds-1456x817.png" width="1456" height="817" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>HDD &#038; SSD Prices Are Expected to Skyrocket By Up To 30% as NAND Firms Cash In on AI Mania, Driven By Huge Demand From Data Centers</title>
			<link>https://wccftech.com/consumer-hdd-ssd-prices-are-expected-set-to-skyrocket-by-up-to-30/</link>

			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Muhammad Zuhair]]></dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 16:36:12 +0000</pubDate>
			<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Enterprise storage]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[hdd]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[HDD Prices]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[NAND]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[NAND Prices]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[SSD]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[SSD Prices]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/?p=1661306</guid>

			<description><![CDATA[NAND-based products, including consumer SSDs, could see a sharp rise in the coming weeks, as major suppliers raise prices to meet the massive AI demand. The Increase in AI Data Center Capacity Has Brought In Huge Demand For Enterprise Storage Well, it seems like gamers might need to combat another shortage coming their way. According to reports quoting supply chain sources, NAND firms such as Western Digital, SanDisk, and Micron are raising NAND prices by up to 30%. The demand for AI and enterprise storage is rapidly increasing due to a surge in data center capacity. For now, major NAND [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NAND-based products, including consumer SSDs, could see a sharp rise in the coming weeks, as major suppliers raise prices to meet the massive AI demand.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-increase-in-ai-data-center-capacity-has-brought-in-huge-demand-for-enterprise-storage">The Increase in AI Data Center Capacity Has Brought In Huge Demand For Enterprise Storage</h2>



<p>Well, it seems like gamers might need to combat another shortage coming their way. According to reports quoting supply chain sources, NAND firms such as Western Digital, SanDisk, and Micron are raising NAND prices by up to 30%. The demand for AI and enterprise storage is rapidly increasing due to a surge in data center capacity. For now, major NAND suppliers have stopped giving out quotes to customers, and with that, it won't be wrong to say that we can see a widespread price increase, not just limited to enterprise storage.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="zh" dir="ltr">2025年9月12日<br><br>親愛的客戶：<br><br>人工智慧時代以數據為動力，而HDD硬碟則確保資料安全、可存取、經濟實惠，並為創新做好準備。… <a href="https://t.co/cu42ONMsqp">pic.twitter.com/cu42ONMsqp</a></p>&mdash; 駿HaYaO (@QQ_Timmy) <a href="https://twitter.com/QQ_Timmy/status/1967484148605653408?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 15, 2025</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>Western Digital recently made an official announcement disclosing changes in the NAND pricing structure. Based on a <a href="https://www.digitimes.com/news/a20250915PD203/nand-sandisk-price-memory-dram.html">report by DigiTimes</a>, companies like SanDisk are anticipated to raise prices for NAND products by up to 10%. One of the biggest suppliers, Micron, is factoring in a price hike as significant as 30%, but the firm hasn't officially notified the raise to its customers, which means that the supply chain is still adjusting to the situation. However, in the broader scheme of things, consumer-focused NAND products could see a drastic increase in prices.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image wp-lightbox size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="485" src="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Samsung-QLC-V-NAND-728x485.jpg" alt="Samsung QLC V-NAND" class="wp-image-1544535" style="width:840px;height:auto" srcset="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Samsung-QLC-V-NAND-728x485.jpg 728w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Samsung-QLC-V-NAND-541x360.jpg 541w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Samsung-QLC-V-NAND.jpg 1000w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Image Credit: Samsung</figcaption></figure>



<p>For those curious about how AI is gobbling up enterprise storage, well, they are the primary 'container' of datasets needed to train LLMs, and in particular, HDDs act as cold storage for raw datasets. Given how quickly data center computing power is expanding worldwide, the demand for enterprise storage is also rising in parallel, which is why NAND firms are capitalizing on the hype. Since HDDs don't employ NAND chips, they won't see as aggressive of a price rise as SSDs, but they are still expected to be influenced.  </p>



<p>Interestingly, I remember how just last year, the <a href="https://wccftech.com/dram-nand-prices-drop-dwindling-consumer-demand/">NAND industry was struggling to profit</a>, since consumer demand was at its rock bottom.</p>
]]>			</content:encoded>



			<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
			<media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/V-NAND_editorial_main1-1-1-1456x810.jpg" width="1456" height="810" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>STALKER-Like MMOFPS Pioner to Host Open Beta Next Month</title>
			<link>https://wccftech.com/stalker-like-mmofps-pioner-open-beta-october/</link>

			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alessio Palumbo]]></dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 16:35:29 +0000</pubDate>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[GFA Games]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[MMOFPS]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[PIONER]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/?p=1661305</guid>

			<description><![CDATA[Developer GFA Games has announced today that its upcoming MMOFPS game Pioner will host an Open Beta test at some point in October. The game is still scheduled to launch later this year on PC, with consoles to follow at a later time. Pioner was actually already available for a limited time as part of June's Steam Next Fest. Following that test, GFA Games shared some adjustments planned for Pioner's PvP mode: Honestly, though, the game generally felt rough during the Steam Next Fest demo. As someone who has been looking forward to Pioner for a while (you might have [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Developer GFA Games has announced today that its upcoming MMOFPS game Pioner will host an Open Beta test at some point in October. The game is still scheduled to launch later this year on PC, with consoles to follow at a later time.</p>



<p>Pioner was actually already available <a href="https://wccftech.com/pioner-demo-confirmed-for-steam-next-fest/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">for a limited time as part of June's Steam Next Fest</a>. Following that test, GFA Games shared some adjustments planned for Pioner's PvP mode:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><em><strong>Current Capture Point Method:</strong> We’re working on making the “Capture the Flag” mode feel more classic. Players will no longer be forced to spend excessive time capturing a flag.</em></li>



<li><em><strong>Point Names: </strong>We'll assign point names — A, B, and C — to make it easier for players to navigate the map and communicate with each other.</em></li>



<li><em><strong>Enemy visualization in TDM:</strong> We're addressing visibility issues by adding a special type of visualization for enemies (NPCs and players) that makes them stand out against the environment. We're also adjusting lighting components that interfere with visibility.</em></li>



<li><em><strong>Player movement:</strong> We’ll work on fixing player movement desynchronization, which can cause noticeable "jitter" in the movement of enemies and allies.</em></li>



<li><em><strong>Hit registration:</strong> The netcode is still being fine-tuned. It’s not fully polished yet, which may cause hits not to register or kills/deaths to happen much faster than intended.</em></li>



<li><em><strong>Hit collision:</strong> We’ll improve hitbox accuracy on certain environmental objects. We tried to identify as many of these issues as possible before the test, but some may still remain in certain areas of the map.</em></li>



<li><em><strong>Balance: </strong>We’ve gathered all the current feedback on PvP weapon balance and will make additional adjustments in the near future.</em></li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="PIONER - Frontier" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xGXEA0Exa50?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>Honestly, though, the game generally felt rough during the Steam Next Fest demo. As someone who has been looking forward to Pioner for a while (you might have guessed it from the two <a href="https://wccftech.com/pioner-qa-2-devs-reveal-pve-pvp-mechanics-of-this-stalker-like-mmofps-confirm-beta-in-2023/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">interviews</a> I previously conducted with GFA Games), I think it could use some additional time in the oven to improve its polish. Still, maybe there was a big improvement in the last four months, so let's check this new build first. Meanwhile, check out the new gameplay trailer embedded above.</p>



<p></p>
]]>			</content:encoded>



			<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
			<media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/DarkSwamps-1-1456x819.jpg" width="1456" height="819" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Netflix&#8217;s The Witcher Season 4 Premieres This October, New Teaser Shows Off Liam Hemsworth as Geralt</title>
			<link>https://wccftech.com/netflix-the-witcher-season-4-liam-hemsworth/</link>

			<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Carcasole]]></dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 16:19:40 +0000</pubDate>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[CD Projekt Red]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Liam Hemsworth]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[netflix]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[the witcher]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/?p=1661284</guid>

			<description><![CDATA[Netflix's adaptation of The Witcher is set to begin its fourth and second-last season this coming October 30, 2025, the streaming company has announced, with Liam Hemsworth in Geralt's boots after Henry Cavill left the show. Alongside the premiere date announcement, Netflix also debuted the first proper clip of Hemsworth in the role. While Cavill got the show going, and Netflix's adaptation is certainly part of what helped get the momentum going in what can now be called a renaissance for videogame to TV and film adaptations, it'll be up to Hemsworth to close out the show as he helms [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Netflix's adaptation of The Witcher is set to begin its fourth and second-last season this coming October 30, 2025, the streaming company has announced, with Liam Hemsworth in Geralt's boots after Henry Cavill left the show. Alongside the <a href="https://x.com/witchernetflix/status/1967075836911030453">premiere date announcement</a>, Netflix also debuted the first proper clip of Hemsworth in the role.</p>



<p>While Cavill got the show going, and Netflix's adaptation is certainly part of what helped get the momentum going in what can now be called a renaissance for videogame to TV and film adaptations, it'll be up to Hemsworth to close out the show as he helms its final two seasons, which were shot all together so once filming ended, Netflix just had to put it together.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="The Witcher: Season 4 | Official Teaser | Netflix" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kQGshAJmdBU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>"<em>As a </em><em>Witcher</em> fan, I’m over the moon about the opportunity to play Geralt of Rivia," Hemsworth said, per a <a href="https://www.netflix.com/tudum/articles/the-witcher-season-4-liam-hemsworth">a blog post from Netflix's Tudum website</a>.</p>



<p>Like other streamers, Netflix has added other videogame adaptations since it helped kick things off with The Witcher. It currently has an <a href="https://wccftech.com/assassins-creed-live-action-tv-series-officially-greenlit-by-netflix/">Assassin's Creed</a> show in the works, and on the animated front, <a href="https://wccftech.com/cyberpunk-edgerunners-2-confirmed/">Cyberpunk: Edgerunners</a> is coming back with a second season.</p>



<p>Henry Cavill also isn't done with videogame adaptations, as he's ecstatically working on a <a href="https://wccftech.com/warhammer-40k-tv-series-from-amazon-will-star-henry-cavill/">Warhammer adaptation</a>.</p>
]]>			</content:encoded>



			<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[TV]]></category>
			<media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/The-Witcher-Season-4-Premiere-1456x956.png" width="1456" height="956" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Core Ultra 3 205 Review Shows 16% Single-Core Uplift Over Core i3 14100 And Decent iGPU Performance</title>
			<link>https://wccftech.com/core-ultra-3-205-review-shows-16-single-core-uplift-over-core-i3-14100/</link>

			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarfraz Khan]]></dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 16:10:35 +0000</pubDate>
			<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Core i3 14100]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Core Ultra 3 205]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Intel]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Intel Core Ultra]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/?p=1661292</guid>

			<description><![CDATA[Intel Core Ultra 3 205 offers a similar performance boost as its bigger siblings when compared to its predecessor. First Review of Intel Core Ultra 3 205 Shows Processor's Prowess in Various Workloads: Touches 4.8 GHz on P-Core and Over 4.3 GHz on the E-Core A few days ago, we saw the entry-level Core Ultra 3 205 from the Arrow Lake-S family getting tested by a Korean reviewer, Bulls Lab. The reviewer gave us a glimpse of how the CPU performs in a few workloads, but he just uploaded a dedicated review video on his YouTube channel, showing the true [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Intel Core Ultra 3 205 offers a similar performance boost as its bigger siblings when compared to its predecessor. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-first-review-of-intel-core-ultra-3-205-shows-processor-s-prowess-in-various-workloads-touches-4-8-ghz-on-p-core-and-over-4-3-ghz-on-the-e-core">First Review of Intel Core Ultra 3 205 Shows Processor's Prowess in Various Workloads: Touches 4.8 GHz on P-Core and Over 4.3 GHz on the E-Core </h2>



<p>A few days ago, we saw the <a href="https://wccftech.com/intel-core-ultra-3-205-reportedly-delivers-up-to-48-higher-multi-core-performance-vs-core-i3-14100/">entry-level Core Ultra 3 205 from the Arrow Lake-S family</a> getting tested by a Korean reviewer, Bulls Lab. The reviewer gave us a glimpse of how the CPU performs in a few workloads, but he just uploaded a dedicated review video on his <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4N1qGZ-AeR0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">YouTube channel</a>, showing the true prowess of the processor and how it stacks up against other budget Intel processors in the Arrow Lake and Raptor Lake Refresh family.</p>



<p>Since the Core Ultra 3 205 is aimed at the entry-level market, he utilized a cheap H810 chipset motherboard, which should get the job done for most. The processor performed quite well against its predecessor, the Core i3 14100, offering almost <strong>48%</strong> higher multi-threaded score in Cinebench R23, which we saw earlier. This time, we also saw how the processor performs in the single-threaded workloads. Core Ultra 3 205 scored a good <strong>1983 points</strong> in Cinebench R23, which is roughly <strong>16%</strong> higher than the score by i3 14100. </p>


<figure class="story-gallery">
<div class="swiper-container">

<figure class="wp-block-gallery swiper-wrapper has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-1 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image swiper-slide wp-lightbox size-full"><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Core-Ultra-3-205-Cinebench-R23.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1902" height="954" data-id="1661297" src="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Core-Ultra-3-205-Cinebench-R23.png" alt="Cinebench R23 benchmark comparing Intel Core i3-14100, Ultra 3 205, i5-14400, and Ultra 5 225 with 48% 향상 highlighted." class="wp-image-1661297" srcset="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Core-Ultra-3-205-Cinebench-R23.png 1902w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Core-Ultra-3-205-Cinebench-R23-564x283.png 564w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Core-Ultra-3-205-Cinebench-R23-728x365.png 728w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Core-Ultra-3-205-Cinebench-R23-1456x730.png 1456w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1902px) 100vw, 1902px" /></a></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image swiper-slide wp-lightbox size-full"><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Core-Ultra-3-205-Time-Spy.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1911" height="957" data-id="1661298" src="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Core-Ultra-3-205-Time-Spy.png" alt="3DMark Time Spy benchmark showing Intel Core processors with Ultra 5 225 scoring 1128, Ultra 3 205 scoring 1125, and i3-14100 scoring 643." class="wp-image-1661298" srcset="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Core-Ultra-3-205-Time-Spy.png 1911w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Core-Ultra-3-205-Time-Spy-564x282.png 564w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Core-Ultra-3-205-Time-Spy-728x365.png 728w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Core-Ultra-3-205-Time-Spy-1456x729.png 1456w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1911px) 100vw, 1911px" /></a></figure>
</figure>
<div class="gallery-nav">
			    		<div class="gallery-prev"><svg width="8" height="12"><use xlink:href="#icn-arrowMd"></use></svg></div>
			    		<div class="gallery-next"><svg width="8" height="12"><use xlink:href="#icn-arrowMd"></use></svg></div>
				    	<span class="gallery-counter">2 of 9</span>
			    	</div>
</div>
</figure>



<p>This is similar to the performance uplifts we see when we compare the Core Ultra 5 225 against the Core i5 14400. The generational uplifts look decent, and the single-core performance is on par with the more expensive Core Ultra 5 225 processor. The processor was hitting almost 4.7 GHz on the P-Core and over 4.3 GHz on the E-Core, which is also impressive. The processor was also tested in graphical workloads and games, and we saw its iGPU score 1125 points in Time Spy, which is a 75% uplift over i3 14100. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image wp-lightbox size-full"><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Core-Ultra-3-205-P-Core-and-E-Core.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1912" height="933" src="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Core-Ultra-3-205-P-Core-and-E-Core.png" alt="Intel Core Ultra 3 205 CPU screen showing temperature 51°C and power consumption 62.632 W." class="wp-image-1661296" srcset="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Core-Ultra-3-205-P-Core-and-E-Core.png 1912w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Core-Ultra-3-205-P-Core-and-E-Core-564x275.png 564w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Core-Ultra-3-205-P-Core-and-E-Core-728x355.png 728w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Core-Ultra-3-205-P-Core-and-E-Core-1456x710.png 1456w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1912px) 100vw, 1912px" /></a></figure>



<p>In games, the iGPU won't be enough for intensive titles, but for non-intensive titles such as <em>DOTA </em>and <em>Valorant</em>, it offers smooth performance, and we can see its iGPU running at a constant 1800 MHz. The CPU usage remains in the 40-60% range in these games, and when coupled with a dedicated GPU, the CPU can handle the workload properly, but hits nearly 90% usage in intensive titles like <em>Cyberpunk 2077.</em> </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image wp-lightbox size-full"><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Ultra-3-205-Pre-built.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1718" height="923" src="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Ultra-3-205-Pre-built.png" alt="Ultra 3 205 desktop priced at 499,000₩ with SALE tag displayed on a Compuzone website page." class="wp-image-1661295" srcset="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Ultra-3-205-Pre-built.png 1718w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Ultra-3-205-Pre-built-564x303.png 564w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Ultra-3-205-Pre-built-728x391.png 728w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Ultra-3-205-Pre-built-1456x782.png 1456w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1718px) 100vw, 1718px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Pre-built PC with Core Ultra 3 205, 8GB RAM, 500GB SSD is available at $360; Image Credit: Bulls Lab</figcaption></figure>



<p>All in all, this 4+4 core CPU looks good for entry-level gaming and should be an attractive solution at around $120. Bulls Lab showed that the CPU is available for 199,000 Won, which is equivalent to US$140, which appears somewhat higher, but a pre-built system (without a dGPOU) with Core Ultra 3 205 is selling for as low as 499,000 Won or US$360, which is an attractive price. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="드디어 정신차린 인텔 CPU... 울트라 3 205로 조립해봤습니다" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4N1qGZ-AeR0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
]]>			</content:encoded>



			<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
			<media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Core-Ultra-3-205-CPU-1456x819.jpg" width="1456" height="819" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>This DIY PlayStation 5 Portable Edition Impresses With Compact, Light Design</title>
			<link>https://wccftech.com/diy-playstation-5-portable-edition-compact-design/</link>
			<comments>https://wccftech.com/diy-playstation-5-portable-edition-compact-design/#respond</comments>

			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Francesco De Meo]]></dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 15:49:13 +0000</pubDate>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[PlayStation 5]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[PlayStation 5 Portable Edition]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Sony]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/?p=1661289</guid>

			<description><![CDATA[A few attempts have been made in the past few years to turn the PlayStation 5 into a portable console, but few are as impressive as a recent attempt whose creation has been documented in a video shared on YouTube. User TERA, who has built plenty of impressive DIY console models in the past, documented their second attempt at creating a PlayStation 5 portable edition in a new video which goes over some areas of improvements over the previous attempt, disassembly, cooling system changes to make the new DIY edition of the system possible, the reasons behind the new enclosure [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A few attempts have been made in the past few years to turn the <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/playstation-5/">PlayStation 5</a> into a portable console, but few are as impressive as a recent attempt whose creation has been documented in a video shared on YouTube.</p>



<p>User <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@TERA_PS345">TERA</a>, who has built plenty of impressive DIY console models in the past, documented their second attempt at creating a PlayStation 5 portable edition in a new video which goes over <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=THm4TCUNmIw">some areas of improvements over the previous attempt</a>, disassembly, cooling system changes to make the new DIY edition of the system possible, the reasons behind the new enclosure and LCD panel choices, component assembly, and more. The end results are extremely impressive from every point of view: the system is quite silent considering the new cooling system even during gameplay, its size is relatively small, and its weight is quite light, lighter not only than the previous attempt but also than a regular PlayStation 5 mode, definitely helping portability.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="[DIY] Building a PORTABLE All-in-One PlayStation 5" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XQ87p2Rhb_A?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>Although Sony is likely never releasing a full-fledged PlayStation 5 portable edition, the Japanese company already released different edition of its PlayStation 5 system, including <a href="https://wccftech.com/new-playstation-5-slimmer-revision/">a slimmer version of both the Standard Edition and the Digital Edition</a> that launched in late 2023 alongside a detachable disc drive, and a <a href="https://wccftech.com/tag/playstation-5-pro/">PlayStation 5 Pro</a> model that allows users to enjoy console games at their best thanks to better specs and support for the PlayStation Spectral Super Resolution upscaler, whose <a href="https://wccftech.com/playstation-5-pro-amd-fsr-first-quarter-2026/">next version is set to launch next year</a>. You can learn more about the most powerful console on the market by checking out Kai's<a href="https://wccftech.com/review/playstation-5-pro-hardware-the-next-gen-graphics-upgrade/"> review.</a></p>
]]>			</content:encoded>

			<wfw:commentRss>https://wccftech.com/diy-playstation-5-portable-edition-compact-design/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>


			<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
			<media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/PlayStation-5-Portable-Edition.webp" width="1280" height="720" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>GPD Announces Official MSRP For Win 5 Handheld: Starts At $1,400 With Ryzen AI Max 385+32GB+1TB Configuration</title>
			<link>https://wccftech.com/gpd-announces-official-msrp-for-win-5-handheld-starts-at-1400-dollars/</link>

			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarfraz Khan]]></dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 15:13:55 +0000</pubDate>
			<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Gaming Handheld]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[GPD]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[GPD Win 5]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Ryzen AI Max 385]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Strix Halo]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Win 5]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/?p=1661268</guid>

			<description><![CDATA[The GPD Win 5 gaming handheld is going to be available with different Strix Halo chips, but the price difference between the configurations isn't huge. GPD Win 5 With Ryzen AI Max+ 395 Officially Costs $1600; Pre-Sale Prices Will Allow Users to Buy the Handheld for as Low as $1,400 The prices for the first-ever Strix Halo-based gaming handhelds have just been announced. GPD, which recently launched the WIN 5 gaming handheld, featuring configurations with two different Strix Halo chips, has today announced the official price tags for the console. As you would expect, the Win 5 is an expensive [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The GPD Win 5 gaming handheld is going to be available with different Strix Halo chips, but the price difference between the configurations isn't huge.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-gpd-win-5-with-ryzen-ai-max-395-officially-costs-1600-pre-sale-prices-will-allow-users-to-buy-the-handheld-for-as-low-as-1-400">GPD Win 5 With Ryzen AI Max+ 395 Officially Costs $1600; Pre-Sale Prices Will Allow Users to Buy the Handheld for as Low as $1,400 </h2>



<p>The prices for the first-ever Strix Halo-based gaming handhelds have just been announced. <a href="https://wccftech.com/gpd-win-5-officially-launches-as-the-most-powerful-gaming-handheld-in-the-world-powered-by-ryzen-ai-max-395/">GPD, which recently launched the WIN 5 gaming handheld</a>, featuring configurations with two different Strix Halo chips, has today announced the official price tags for the console. As you would expect, the Win 5 is an expensive one, but fortunately, it's not going to cost $2000 as previously expected. </p>



<p>As reported by <a href="https://x.com/realVictor_M/status/1967589218060062974" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">@realVictor_M</a>, the GPD Win 5 starts at <strong>9999 Yuan</strong>, which translates to around <strong>US$1,400</strong>. This handheld boasts a configuration featuring the Ryzen AI Max 385 processor, 32 GB RAM, and 1 TB storage. The Ryzen AI Max 385 is an 8-core and 16-thread Zen 5 processor, offering Radeon 8050S integrated graphics with 32 GPU cores. This is the weakest configuration you can get on the Win 5 handheld, and the one with Ryzen AI Max+ 395 boasting Radeon 8060S, starts at <strong>11,500 Yuan </strong>or <strong>US$1600</strong>.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image wp-lightbox size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="728" height="670" src="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/GPD-win-5-price-728x670.jpg" alt="GPD Win 5 with pricing chart and images of Mini SSD (1517), GPD Win 5 dock, and battery alongside QR code on yellow background." class="wp-image-1661285" srcset="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/GPD-win-5-price-728x670.jpg 728w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/GPD-win-5-price-391x360.jpg 391w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/GPD-win-5-price.jpg 1080w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 728px) 100vw, 728px" /></figure>



<p>This configuration will offer the same memory but 2 TB of storage capacity. The flagship configuration, which includes the Ryzen AI Max+ 395 and 64GB+4TB combo, is priced at 14,999 Yuan, which is equivalent to US$2,100. It's definitely one of the most expensive, if not the most expensive handhelds we have on the market, and that 64GB+4TB combo is just too much. The fastest yet we have are Strix Point and Lunar Lake-based handhelds, and this is the first time someone has deployed a 16-core/32-threads processor in a handheld. </p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li>GPD Win 5 (Ryzen AI Max+ 395, 64 GB, 4 TB): <strong>$2,100 ($1,824</strong> with Pre-Sale)</li>



<li>GPD Win 5 (Ryzen AI Max+ 395, 32 GB, 2 TB): <strong>$1,600 ($1,400</strong> with Pre-Sale)</li>



<li>GPD Win 5 (Ryzen AI Max 385, 32 GB, 1 TB): <strong>$1,400 ($1,22</strong>0 with Pre-Sale)</li>
</ol>



<p>That said, the prices for the Win 5 appear to be decent since even Strix Halo-based mini PCs cost nearly $1500-$200. The GPD Win 5 can do almost the same job as those mini PCs while also offering a dedicated handheld experience. It's expected that <a href="https://wccftech.com/gpd-announces-128gb-unified-memory-solution-for-win-5-console/">GPD will also debut one more configuration, which will offer a 128 GB system RAM configuration</a>. This is going to be specially crafted for users who want to execute memory-intensive workloads. Based on the prices of the announced configurations, that variant will cost around $2,500.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image wp-lightbox size-full"><a href="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/128-GB-unified-memory-GPD-win-5-1.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1667" height="1409" src="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/128-GB-unified-memory-GPD-win-5-1.jpg" alt="AMD Ryzen AI Max+ 395 showcasing LPDDR5x, 8000MHz, quad-channel, seamless local execution." class="wp-image-1616913" srcset="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/128-GB-unified-memory-GPD-win-5-1.jpg 1667w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/128-GB-unified-memory-GPD-win-5-1-426x360.jpg 426w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/128-GB-unified-memory-GPD-win-5-1-728x615.jpg 728w, https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/128-GB-unified-memory-GPD-win-5-1-1456x1231.jpg 1456w" sizes="auto, (max-width: 1667px) 100vw, 1667px" /></a><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">128 GB variant is coming soon</figcaption></figure>



<p>Nonetheless, if you are planning to buy the GPD Win 5, then the company is offering some good discounts for those who are pre-ordering. Users will get a $200 discount on the base configuration with Ryzen AI Max 385 and Ryzen AI Max 395. So, you can get the Win 5 for as low as $1,220. The one with a 64GB+4TB configuration can be bought at just $1,824, which is nearly a $300 discount.</p>
]]>			</content:encoded>



			<category><![CDATA[Announcement]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Hardware]]></category>
			<media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/GPD-Win-5-Featured-1-1456x819.jpg" width="1456" height="819" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 Reaches 4.4 Million Copies Sold</title>
			<link>https://wccftech.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-reaches-4-4-million-copies-sold/</link>

			<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Carcasole]]></dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 15:06:29 +0000</pubDate>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Clair Obscur: Expedition 33]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Sandfall Interactive]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/?p=1661251</guid>

			<description><![CDATA[Sandfall Interactive's Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 is one of 2025's breakout hits. It currently stands as the best-rated game that came out in 2025 on Metacritic and reached 3.3 million copies sold just 33 days after its launch. Now, thanks to an interview spotted by Gamereactor, we know that the game has reached another sales milestone, hitting 4.4 million copies sold. Speaking to French outlet Clips du lundi, when technical character artist Amandine Marest, producer Benjamin Dimanche, and senior gameplay programmer Florian Torres were asked about an update on sales, they gave away the goose that, while the public number [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Sandfall Interactive's Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 is one of 2025's breakout hits. It currently stands as the best-rated game that came out in 2025 on <a href="https://www.metacritic.com/browse/game/all/all/current-year/metascore/?page=1">Metacritic</a> and <a href="https://wccftech.com/33-days-after-launch-clair-obscur-expedition-33-reaches-3-3-million-copies-sold/">reached 3.3 million copies sold just 33 days after its launch</a>. Now, thanks to an <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4VrnDS-mko0&amp;t=196s">interview</a> spotted by <a href="https://www.gamereactor.eu/clair-obscur-expedition-33-quietly-tops-44-million-in-sales-1601503/">Gamereactor</a>, we know that the game has reached another sales milestone, hitting 4.4 million copies sold.</p>



<p>Speaking to French outlet <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@ClipsDuLundiV2">Clips du lundi</a>, when technical character artist Amandine Marest, producer Benjamin Dimanche, and senior gameplay programmer Florian Torres were asked about an update on sales, they gave away the goose that, while the public number is "<em>officially</em>" still the previously announced 3.3 million, Marest confirmed that sales had hit 4.4 million.</p>



<p>"<em>Officially, 3.3 million, but it's 4.4 million</em>," Torres then clarified.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="L&#039;interview de 3 membres du studio de Clair Obscur par Antoine au ZEVENT ! BO de MK meilleure ?!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4VrnDS-mko0?start=196&feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>It's a strong milestone for an indie game that in many respects came out of nowhere, despite being featured in multiple Xbox showcases. Sandfall Interactive's story is not uncommon in the videogame industry. A studio born out of developers leaving the triple-A space, looking to make the kind of game they've always wanted to see, with <a href="https://wccftech.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-devs-went-to-square-enix/">inspirations drawn from games they loved</a> is old-hat in this industry. </p>



<p>It's less common for studios that share those origins to find the kind of wild success Sandfall has found, especially when considering how much of a game's sales can be eroded by being available through a subscription service, like Xbox Game Pass.</p>



<p>And by the sounds of it, Sandfall isn't looking to waste the opportunity it has with this first game's success, as it is looking to <a href="https://wccftech.com/clair-obscur-expedition-33-start-franchise-post-launch-tease/">build out Clair Obscur into a wider franchise</a>. </p>
]]>			</content:encoded>



			<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
			<media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Clair-Obscur-Expedition-33-1456x819.png" width="1456" height="819" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Super Mario Galaxy 1+2 Is More Than a Simple Port Running at a Higher Resolution</title>
			<link>https://wccftech.com/super-mario-galaxy-12-more-than-port/</link>
			<comments>https://wccftech.com/super-mario-galaxy-12-more-than-port/#respond</comments>

			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Francesco De Meo]]></dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 15:04:58 +0000</pubDate>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Nintendo]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch 2]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Super Mario Galaxy 1+2]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/?p=1661272</guid>

			<description><![CDATA[Super Mario Galaxy 1+2 will be more than simple ports of the original running at a higher resolution, as they will feature some noticeable visual improvements. In a new video shared online today on YouTube, GVG compared the footage released so far, which includes a five-minute-long uninterrupted gameplay video shared on the official website, detailing some of the unspecified visual improvements confirmed shortly after the collection's announcement. Among these are some significantly improved textures, though not all of them will be enhanced, judging by the footage, improved fonts, and re-rendered cutscenes with a new aspect ratio, which look better even [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Super Mario Galaxy 1+2 will be more than simple ports of the original running at a higher resolution, as they will feature some noticeable visual improvements.</p>



<p>In a new video shared online today on YouTube, GVG compared the footage released so far, which includes a five-minute-long uninterrupted gameplay video shared on the official website, detailing some of the unspecified visual improvements confirmed shortly after the collection's <a href="https://wccftech.com/super-mario-galaxy-2-launch-on-nintendo-switch-systems-next-month/">announcement.</a> Among these are some significantly improved textures, though not all of them will be enhanced, judging by the footage, improved fonts, and re-rendered cutscenes with a new aspect ratio, which look better even in a comparison based on the compressed footage available. As all the footage has been captured from the Nintendo Switch version running at 1080p resolution, the two games should look even better running at 4K resolution on Nintendo Switch 2.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Super Mario Galaxy 1+2 is Doing A Bit More Than You Think" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wOF6b0HgxCA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>Besides visual improvements, Super Mario Galaxy 1+2 will include some new features over the original Wii release and the Super Mario 3D All-Stars port of the first entry in the series. Among these new features will be an Assist Mode to make the games more accessible, the ability to listen to the soundtracks of both games, and more.</p>



<p>Super Mario Galaxy 1+2 will launch ahead of the next <a href="https://wccftech.com/nintendo-debuts-the-super-mario-galaxy-movie-teaser-coming-april-2026/">Super Mario Bros. movie</a>, also called Galaxy, on October 2 on Nintendo Switch and Nintendo Switch 2.</p>
]]>			</content:encoded>

			<wfw:commentRss>https://wccftech.com/super-mario-galaxy-12-more-than-port/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>


			<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
			<media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Super-Mario-Galaxy-12-1456x819.webp" width="1456" height="819" />
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>AirPods Pro 3 Review Roundup: Stronger ANC, Richer Sound, Longer Battery, And Smarter Health Tracking</title>
			<link>https://wccftech.com/airpods-pro-3-review-roundup-stronger-anc-richer-sound-longer-battery-and-smarter-health-tracking/</link>

			<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ezza Ijaz]]></dc:creator>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
			<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[AirPods Pro 3]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
			<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/?p=1661229</guid>

			<description><![CDATA[Apple has not only made a mark when it comes to its flagship smartphones, but its wearables have also built up a reputation for offering sleek design and premium features. Apple made a ton of key announcements at the big hardware event held on September 9th, 2025, and its AirPods Pro 3 is one of them, packed with some significant upgrades over its predecessor. Many elements, such as the sound quality and other key aspects, have been improved. If you plan to upgrade to the latest earbuds model, we will bring you some of the key features brought ahead and [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Apple has not only made a mark when it comes to its flagship smartphones, but its wearables have also built up a reputation for offering sleek design and premium features. Apple made a ton of key announcements at the big hardware event held on September 9th, 2025, and its AirPods Pro 3 is one of them, packed with some <a href="https://wccftech.com/apple-unveils-airpods-pro-3-for-x/">significant upgrades</a> over its predecessor. Many elements, such as the sound quality and other key aspects, have been improved. If you plan to upgrade to the latest earbuds model, we will bring you some of the key features brought ahead and some of the video reviews of the new AirPods.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-airpods-3-review-roundup-the-subtle-enhancements-that-tend-to-make-a-huge-difference">AirPods 3 review roundup: the subtle enhancements that tend to make a huge difference</h2>



<p>At first glance, the AirPods Pro 3 may appear closer to its predecessor, but since the changes made go beyond design tweaks, you may not immediately notice them, but they do make a huge difference. Apple seems to be focused on bringing refinement and fine-tuning to its products, and it took the same approach for its AirPods Pro 3, not reinventing but rather optimizing them for its users.</p>



<p>One of the major improvements introduced this time around is the active noise cancellation feature, which is creating waves. The Cupertino giant claims that the capability is now twice as effective as on the AirPods Pro 2 and fourfold stronger than the original Pro model. With the inclusion of new microphones and enhanced computational audio improvements, the audio improvement felt is huge.</p>



<p>The sound quality has also been significantly improved since there is now a redesigned acoustic architecture and next-generation Adaptive EQ addition that allows for deeper bass, clearer highs, and songs that sound more layered, with the vocals standing out. This is one area that remained a constant pain point for users. While the quality is still not studio-level, it still marks a major jump from the offerings of the predecessor.</p>



<p>Battery life is also massively stretched out now. The AirPods Pro 3 now last up to eight hours with ANC enabled, up from 6 hours on the Pro 2 model. However, with the case included, the listening time with ANC is surprisingly less than that of the Pro 2 version. The Pro 3 models come with foam-infused silicone ear tips, and more variation is added in the available sizes, making the device more comfortable to wear and a better fit. Due to this upgrade, the passive noise isolation is also enhanced.</p>



<p>One of the changes that truly stand out as futuristic is the heart-rate sensor, making the earbuds a health-tracking accessory as well. While the Apple Watch remains the go-to when it comes to fitness, its ability to measure heart rate during workouts simply through the earbuds reflects Apple’s long-term vision for its wearables.</p>



<p>The AirPods Pro 3, all in all, seem to be evolutionary rather than revolutionary and would be a perfect upgrade for athletes, travelers, and gym enthusiasts, where such enhancements in the sound quality and features go a long way. While the changes might not be radical, they elevate the new model in just the right way. The AirPods Pro 3 are available for pre-order and will launch on Friday, September 19th. For more detailed insights, we have curated some of the reviews that could help you decide whether to upgrade to the new earbuds or stick to the model you have.</p>



<p><strong>Video Reviews:</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="AirPods Pro 3 Review: These are Shockingly Good!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/d0j4O4Lq7qc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="AirPods Pro 3 Review: I Understand It Now!" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GB0b6KFZVq0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="AirPods Pro 3 - worth the upgrade?" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kOU1Q8H4nho?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
]]>			</content:encoded>



			<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
			<media:content medium="image" url="https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/AirPods-Pro-3-2-1-1456x819.jpg" width="1456" height="819" />
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
