<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dcterms="dcterms" xmlns:dc="dc" xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi" version="2.0">
  <channel xmlns:dcterms="dcterms" xmlns:dc="dc" xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi">
    <title>Saga Magazine Apple News Feed</title>
    <link>https://www.saga.co.uk/helix-api/magazinerssfeed/getfeed</link>
    <description>Saga magazine article feed for Apple news</description>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <item xmlns:dcterms="dcterms" xmlns:dc="dc" xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi">
      <title>Older drivers: what are the rules now?</title>
      <link>https://www.saga.co.uk/magazine/life/older-drivers-what-are-the-rules-now</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Following the announcement for eyesight tests for older drivers, we find out what the changes could mean for you – and what the rules are now]]></description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi" url="/helix-contentlibrary/saga/magazine/articles/2025/08aug/older-driver-gettyimages-523556820.jpg" medium="image">
        <media:text xmlns:media="media"><![CDATA[<p><span class="NormalTextRun SCXW197075492 BCX8" style="background-color: #ffffff; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Following the announcement for eyesight tests for older drivers, we find out what the changes could mean for you</span><span class="NormalTextRun SCXW197075492 BCX8" style="background-color: #ffffff; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;"> &ndash; a</span><span class="NormalTextRun SCXW197075492 BCX8" style="background-color: #ffffff; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">nd what the rules are now</span></p>]]></media:text>
        <media:title xmlns:media="media">Older drivers: what are the rules now?</media:title>
      </media:content>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:24:56 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">{8AD08DF4-C768-47D8-B506-6FD32F367D0E}</guid>
      <cf:isSponsered xmlns:cf="cf">False</cf:isSponsered>
      <cf:hasAffiliateLinks xmlns:cf="cf">False</cf:hasAffiliateLinks>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;">Earlier this month, the government announced proposals that could require <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.saga.co.uk/car-insurance/cars-for-over-50s-drivers?icid=magazine|article|insurance|car-insurance|cars-for-over-50s|older-drivers" target="_blank" title="view page">older drivers</a> to take an eye test every three years, with the first being carried out when they turn 70 and have to renew their driving licence.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>The move is part of a radical shake up of driving laws, with the first Road Safety Strategy in more than a decade due to be unveiled in the autumn.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The announcement has left many older drivers asking what exactly this will mean for them.&nbsp;</p>
<p>We&rsquo;ve studied the proposals and reviewed the current rules.&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Why the proposed changes to the law are being made&nbsp;</h3>
<p><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/czrv1g2yl0xo" target="_blank" title="view page">Dr James Adeley</a>, the senior coroner for Lancashire, is said to have prompted the proposals. In April he sent a report to Heidi Alexander, the Transport Secretary, highlighting what he feels are failings in the way we licence older drivers.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The report came after three inquests into the death of four people in a two-year period, saying, "The four fatalities shared the same feature that the driver's sight was well below the standard required to drive a car.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>
<p>Dr Adeley says that the UK&rsquo;s regulations are the &ldquo;laxest in Europe&rdquo; and &ldquo;ineffective and unsafe&rdquo;, and while all three drivers were jailed, the new law aims to prevent tragedies like this ever happening again.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The solicitor representing the three families, Terry Wilcox, of Hudgell Solicitors, explained the problem: "We presently have a system under which the DVLA relies upon drivers to self-report, hand over their licence and stop driving when they've been told by a qualified healthcare professional that their eyesight is not to the required standard. This inquest has shown that simply doesn't happen."&nbsp;</p>
<p>Rob Heard, chairman of the <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://olderdriversforum.com/" target="_blank" title="view page">Older Drivers' Forum</a>, is a former police officer who attended more than 300 fatal traffic incidents in his career, many of them caused by older drivers with poor sight. His experience led to him being called as an expert witness during these inquests.&nbsp;</p>
<p>He acknowledges that while the majority of older drivers take their responsibilities seriously and wouldn&rsquo;t dream of driving if they knew their sight wasn&rsquo;t up to scratch, &ldquo;for a minority, a mandatory test is the only answer, something I&rsquo;ve been pushing for since 2021&rdquo;.&nbsp;</p>
<p>And it&rsquo;s not just a question of dishonesty and selfishness, because many drivers simply don&rsquo;t realise their eyesight isn&rsquo;t up to the required standard.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Police forces conducted a series of voluntary roadside eyesight tests in 2024, and the Older Drivers&rsquo; Forum reports that <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://olderdriversforum.com/2024/12/05/is-your-vision-roadworthy-2/" target="_blank" title="view page">10.2% of drivers aged between 81 and 90 failed the test</a>.&nbsp;</p><h3>What are the current eyesight standards for driving?&nbsp;</h3>
<p>Currently, <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.gov.uk/eye-conditions-and-driving" target="_blank" title="view page">The DVLA says</a> that drivers must be able to:&nbsp;</p>
<ul class="list list--accent">
    <li>read a number plate from 20 metres away </li>
    <li>have no double vision&nbsp; </li>
    <li>have a normal field of vision in at least one eye.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<h3>The proposed change to eyesight tests for driving</h3>
<p>Dr Adeley&rsquo;s concerns have cross-party support, with Alex Davies-Jones, the Justice Minister, telling BBC Breakfast that the government &ldquo;will keep everything under review&rdquo;. Conservative leader Kemi Badenoch has said she <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c5yllgezjk3o" target="_blank" title="view page">agrees with compulsory eye tests for the over-70s</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Davies-Jones stressed that the proposed changes remain part of a consultation process, but media, <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.autocar.co.uk/car-news/consumer/elderly-drivers-facing-mandatory-eye-tests-road-safety-push" target="_blank" title="view page">including Autocar magazine</a>, report that if passed, the new legislation will mean drivers over the age of 70 will need to have their eyesight tested every three years. &nbsp;</p>
<p>Heard&rsquo;s research suggests there is overwhelming support for the changes: &ldquo;Of the drivers I asked, the majority of whom were over 70, 93% supported the idea of mandatory eyesight testing.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>
<p>As for the additional costs, eye tests for the over-70s are free in <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.nhsinform.scot/care-support-and-rights/nhs-services/eyecare/nhs-community-eyecare/" target="_blank" title="view page">Scotland</a>, <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.nhs.uk/nhs-services/opticians/free-nhs-eye-tests-and-optical-vouchers/" target="_blank" title="view page">England</a>, <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.nidirect.gov.uk/articles/health-cost-and-free-sight-tests-over-60s#toc-1" target="_blank" title="view page">Northern Ireland</a>, and <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.nhs.wales/sa/eye-care-wales/wgos/other-healthcare-professionals/free-eye-tests/" target="_blank" title="view page">Wales</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Regular eye tests can also identify many other medical conditions, and if a problem is picked up early enough, it could help extend your driving career.&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Other proposed changes to the driving laws&nbsp;</h3>
<p>These are reported to include:</p>
<ul class="list list--accent">
    <li>Lowering the drink-drive limit from 35&micro;g per 100ml of breath to the current limit in Scotland of 22&micro;g. </li>
    <li>Medical tests for conditions like <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.saga.co.uk/car-insurance/driving-and-dementia?icid=magazine|article|insurance|car-insurance|driving-and-dementia" target="_blank" title="view page">dementia</a>. </li>
    <li>Issuing penalty points to drivers carrying passengers who are not wearing a seatbelt. </li>
    <li>Allowing roadside swabs to be used when prosecuting drivers for driving under the influence of drugs.&nbsp; &nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<p>These are still proposals and may not pass into law and, in the meantime, you should continue to report any issues with your eyesight <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.gov.uk/eye-conditions-and-driving" target="_blank" title="view page">online</a>.</p>
<h3>What are the rules now for older drivers?</h3>
<p>There are currently a number of <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.saga.co.uk/car-insurance/driving-with-a-medical-condition?icid=magazine|article|insurance|car-insurance|driving-with-a-medical-condition" target="_blank" title="view page">medical conditions</a> that you must inform the DVLA about. If you don&rsquo;t, you risk harming yourself and others, your car insurance may be invalid, and you may even be committing an offence. These conditions include:&nbsp;</p>
<ul class="list list--accent">
    <li>Diabetes</li>
    <li>Epilepsy</li>
    <li>Sleep apnoea</li>
    <li>Fainting spells</li>
    <li>Heart conditions</li>
    <li>Stroke</li>
    <li>Glaucoma&nbsp; &nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<div class="rich-text__container fill--white">
<div class="container container--sm">
<h4><strong>Driving insurance and medical conditions&nbsp;</strong></h4>
<p>The experts at Saga Insurance have more information on&nbsp;<a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.saga.co.uk/car-insurance/driving-and-dementia?icid=magazine|article|insurance|car-insurance|driving-and-dementia" target="_blank" title="view page">driving and dementia</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.saga.co.uk/car-insurance/driving-with-a-medical-condition?icid=magazine|article|insurance|car-insurance|driving-with-a-medical-condition" target="_blank" title="view page">driving with a medical condition</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<p>If you have Saga Insurance, you don&rsquo;t need to get in touch about health issues or medical conditions as long as the DVLA has not restricted or removed your licence.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;">Other car insurance companies may take a different view, and if you are in doubt about whether you need to declare anything, get in touch with them.&nbsp;</span></p>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:dcterms="dcterms" xmlns:dc="dc" xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi">
      <title>This standing Pilates video for older people is the most watched on YouTube</title>
      <link>https://www.saga.co.uk/magazine/health-and-wellbeing/standing-pilates-for-seniors-workout</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Boost your balance, stability and strength: Why millions of older people are benefiting from this free Pilates video.]]></description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi" url="/helix-contentlibrary/exceptional/2023/09/standing-pilates.jpg" medium="image">
        <media:text xmlns:media="media"><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;">Boost your balance, stability and strength: Why millions of older people are benefiting from this free Pilates video</span></p>]]></media:text>
        <media:title xmlns:media="media">This Pilates video for older people is the most watched on YouTube</media:title>
      </media:content>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:23:29 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">{4D824DDE-6890-44D5-BFA3-E1163C45C4E4}</guid>
      <cf:isSponsered xmlns:cf="cf">False</cf:isSponsered>
      <cf:hasAffiliateLinks xmlns:cf="cf">False</cf:hasAffiliateLinks>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than four million people have watched a free Pilates video by a Brighton-based instructor &ndash; making it the most popular Pilates workout for older people on YouTube according to our research. </p>
<p>The gentle <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://youtu.be/i3PYS_jsA1c" target="_blank" title="view page">30-minute standing workout</a> by Pilates instructor Rachel Lawrence &ndash; AKA <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.youtube.com/c/TheGirlWithThePilatesMat" target="_blank" title="view page">The Girl With The Pilates Mat </a>&ndash; aims to improve balance, coordination and core strength.</p><p>Lawrence told Saga: &ldquo;The video is only 30 minutes long and is a series of gentle stretches, balancing and strengthening exercises.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;">"People contact me almost every day to tell me how doing it regularly has changed their lives."</span></p>
<p> "For example, one woman was overjoyed that she could get down to the floor to play with her grandchildren again and another is now confident enough to carry a bag of shopping in each hand home from the shops &ndash; before, she was too scared, thinking she would trip and fall.&rdquo;</p>
<p>So if you&rsquo;re feeling wobbly on your feet, struggling to play with your grandchildren or reach for a high shelf in the kitchen, then give this a go.</p><h2>What the standing Pilates workout involves</h2><p>The session includes simple balancing exercises, ankle-strengthening exercises, stretches and arm lifts to help upper body strength. </p>
<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s a slow session,&rdquo; Lawrence explains. &ldquo;There&rsquo;s a lot of foot work and ankle strengthening. This can be a big problem for older people. If your ankles get too stiff and you trip, then it&rsquo;s a lot harder to save yourself from falling. </p>
<p>&ldquo;But there&rsquo;s also exercises to help your knees, hips, back and core strength, but all done in a very slow and safe way. A lot of people have commented that the workout wasn&rsquo;t as bad as they thought it would be! </p>
<p>"Pilates is all about being able to function better in your own body to allow you to do the things you want in your life.&rdquo;</p><h3>Can anyone do the video?</h3><p>Lawrence, who is recommended by <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.sportengland.org" target="_blank" title="View page">Sport England</a>, explains that the exercises in the video are suitable for almost anyone; however, she cautions that if you have any health concerns then speak to your doctor first. </p>
<p>She says: &ldquo;You don&rsquo;t need any special equipment and if you are worried about being unsteady on your feet, then use a chair or stand by a wall to help you balance.&rdquo;</p>
<p>In the video, Lawrence advises doing the exercises on "a nice, soft carpet" - however you could also consider an suitable exercise mat, such as the <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Core-Balance-Extra-Thick-Eco-Friendly-Exercises/dp/B01MZ74I83/?tag=exceptional0fc-21" target="_blank" title="view product">Core Balance Pilates Mat</a>.</p><h2>How Pilates helps older people</h2><p>Pilates is a low-impact form of exercise, involving a series of movements which focuses on core strength, posture, balance and flexibility. </p>
<p>It was developed by German-born Joseph Pilates, who believed mental and physical health were closely connected. Since then, practising Pilates has been proven to benefit people&rsquo;s wellbeing as well as general fitness, especially for older people. </p>
<p>Lawrence had been leading daily Pilates classes in London before the Covid pandemic struck, which inspired her to film <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://youtu.be/i3PYS_jsA1c" target="_blank" title="View page">the video</a>. </p>
<p>She says: &ldquo;I was really, really worried about the elderly people I was teaching in my over-65 classes. Most were over 70 and the oldest was 86. I thought, what are they going to do during lockdown?</p><p>&ldquo;It was the first video I&rsquo;d filmed, and I used the same exercises as I did in my classes every week, so I knew they would be safe and make a difference.&rdquo;
</p>
<p>Lawrence uploaded the video to YouTube so her clients could watch it for free and it went viral. </p>
<p>Now she has more than 300,000 subscribers to her channel and almost 900 free videos on offer.</p><h3>What else can we do to stay fit as we get older?</h3><p>Personal trainer <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://workoutwoman.co.uk/" target="_blank" title="view page">Rebecca Fuller </a>says exercise can make a big difference to our quality of life as we get older.
</p>
<p>&ldquo;There are many benefits of exercise &ndash; including that it helps us to live longer,&rdquo; she says. </p>
<p>&ldquo;<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0091743517301470" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="View page">Researchers</a> have found that those who exercise can have as much as a nine-year biological advantage over those who are sedentary. It also helps lower blood pressure, improve heart health, aids weight loss and may even protect against Alzheimer's."</p><h3>Start at a level that&rsquo;s right for you</h3><p>&ldquo;I always say that something is better than nothing, and it's important to start at a level that's applicable to you.&rdquo; says Fuller. &ldquo;Try to break up long periods of sitting with some form of movement, whether it's just moving around the house or getting outside for a walk. </p>
<p>&ldquo;It's recommended that we aim for 150 minutes of physical activity a week &ndash; this can be broken up however you like.&rdquo; </p>
<p>Great ideas for cardio exercise include swimming, <a href="~/link.aspx?_id=3C43B9BC16D142B399FAC449AC26A82E&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="View page">walking</a>&nbsp;or cycling.&nbsp;</p>
<p>"<a href="~/link.aspx?_id=584F30DA81DF447693F980A5522FE2CB&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="view page">Strength training</a>&nbsp;is also important, since it helps to build muscle&nbsp;and protect against the loss of muscle mass (sarcopenia).&nbsp;<span style="font-weight: lighter;">Two sessions a week is ideal, and it can take the form of using resistance bands, </span><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.saga.co.uk/magazine/health-and-wellbeing/how-to-use-kettlebells-to-build-strength-in-later-life" target="_blank" title="View page">kettlebells</a><span style="font-weight: lighter;"> or your own bodyweight.&rdquo;</span></p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:dcterms="dcterms" xmlns:dc="dc" xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi">
      <title>12 easy ways to keep your brain sharp and beat memory loss</title>
      <link>https://www.saga.co.uk/magazine/health-and-wellbeing/keep-your-brain-sharp-and-beat-memory-loss</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Limber up and give your brain a fun neurobics work out to help prevent cognitive decline as we get older.]]></description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi" url="/helix-contentlibrary/exceptional/2023/12/brain.jpg" medium="image">
        <media:text xmlns:media="media"><![CDATA[Limber up and give your brain a fun neurobics work out to help prevent cognitive decline as we get older.]]></media:text>
        <media:title xmlns:media="media">12 easy ways to keep your brain sharp and beat memory loss</media:title>
      </media:content>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:14:33 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">{0F092DF1-E874-4B30-9668-D7E3A94DDC78}</guid>
      <cf:isSponsered xmlns:cf="cf">False</cf:isSponsered>
      <cf:hasAffiliateLinks xmlns:cf="cf">False</cf:hasAffiliateLinks>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Do you keep forgetting where you&rsquo;ve put your keys? Struggle to remember people&rsquo;s names from time to time or even walk into a room and totally forget why you went in there?
Y<span style="font-weight: lighter;">ou aren&rsquo;t alone. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;">Many of us believe that </span>memory loss<span style="font-weight: lighter;"> is simply another part of getting old. However, while mild cognitive impairment affects </span><a href="https://www.alzheimers.org.uk/about-dementia/types-dementia/mild-cognitive-impairment-mci#:~:text=It%20is%20estimated%20that%20between,the%20benefits%20of%20diagnosing%20MCI.#:~:text=It%20is%20estimated%20that%20between,the%20benefits%20of%20diagnosing%20MCI." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="view page">up to 20%</a><span style="font-weight: lighter;"> of older people in the UK, it&rsquo;s not inevitable. For most of us, if we keep exercising our mind, then we can help prevent memory loss and keep our brain as sharp as ever.</span></p>
<p>
We&rsquo;ve got some fun, quick and easy ways of challenging your brain that you can introduce into your life every day, from neuroscientist <a href="https://drracheltaylor.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="view page">Dr Rachel Taylor</a>.</p><h2> Is mental decline inevitable as we age?</h2><p>Our brain does <a href="https://www.alzheimers.org.uk/about-dementia/symptoms-and-diagnosis/how-dementia-progresses/is-it-getting-older-or-dementia" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="view page">change </a>as we get older, it&rsquo;s part of the body&rsquo;s ageing process and many people find it harder to remember some facts and learn new skills.
</p>
<p>Research has also revealed that the pandemic took its toll on the health of our brains. <a href="https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lanhl/article/PIIS2666-7568(23)00187-3/fulltext" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="view page">A study</a> by the University of Exeter and Kings College London found it caused sustained cognitive decline among people aged over 50, whether they caught Covid or not.
</p>
<p>
Researchers said mental decline was exacerbated by a number of factors during restrictions, including the increase in loneliness and depression, a fall in exercise and higher alcohol consumption.
</p>
<p>
It feels like we&rsquo;ve had a double whammy, our brains are ageing and we&rsquo;ve been knocked back by the pandemic &ndash; so is there anything we can do?</p><div class="rich-text__container fill--saga-blue-20">
<div class="container container--sm">
<h4>Brain facts</h4>
<ul class="list list--accent">
    <li>It takes 56 days to create new neural pathways &ndash; that is just eight weeks from bringing something new, to it being engrained in the brain.</li>
    <li>75% of the brain is water. Dehydration<span style="font-weight: lighter;"> affects the brain. A lot.</span></li>
    <li><span style="font-weight: lighter;"></span>There are 100 billion neurons inside an adult brain. That means it is more than two thirds more complex than our closest relative, the chimpanzee.</li>
    <li>250mph is the fastest speed information passes in our brain.</li>
    <li>20% is the amount of blood and oxygen your brain uses in your body.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div><p>Dr Taylor says what we do every day can make a big difference to the health of our brains &ndash; and simple changes in behaviour can improve our memory, sharpen up our thinking and improve our reactions.
</p>
<p>
She calls it Neurobic Intense Plasticity Training (NIPT) &ndash; it&rsquo;s quite a mouthful, so what does it mean?
</p>
<p>&ldquo;A neural exercise program needs to involve multiple brain areas in new ways in order to increase brain connections and develop new brain pathways,&rdquo; she explains.</p><p>&ldquo;I call it Neurobics and it contributes to making your brain more responsive and flexible so it can take on mental challenges such as maintaining memories, learning new tasks and information or being creative with your cognitive capacity.&rdquo;
</p>
<p>
She explains that the brain is able to produce natural growth factors called neurotrophins, which help prevent the effects of mental aging and damage to the brain from injury, disease and pathogens.
</p>
<p>
&ldquo;A different way of thinking can go a long way in having a plastic and flexible brain that has neuroprotective mechanisms built into it,&rdquo; she explains. To do this she says we need to change our behaviour and shake up our daily routines.</p><h2>12 easy ways to keep your brain sharp</h2>We already know that <a href="~/link.aspx?_id=582B67FFAB184949A55EFDE2602BA0F7&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="view page">puzzles</a>&nbsp;and online games are a great way of keeping our brains active. But here Dr Taylor has 12 other easy and surprising ways we can shake things up every day and keep our brain sharp and beat memory loss.<h3>1. Sniff out a new smell</h3>
<p>Change the aroma you wake up to every morning which might be tea or coffee. Try baking bread, see what smells you can identify on a walk or warm some spices in a dry pan. </p>
<p>A new smell after you wake will help activate new neural pathways.</p><h3>2. Aim to be ambidextrous</h3>
<p>Use your non-dominant hand to brush your teeth, eat your food, brush your hair or even write with a pen. </p>
<p>Doing this creates new neural pathways and synapses, so increases plasticity and growth in the brain</p><h3>3. Close your eyes</h3>
<p>To activate the side of your brain that you don&rsquo;t normally use, close your eyes when you wash, dress, open the front door or even search for your keys in a drawer without looking.
</p>
<p>
This won&rsquo;t just activate your brain, but strengthen your sense of touch too.</p><h3>4. Turn things upside down</h3>
<p>Turn your calendar, pictures, artwork, notes on the fridge, clock and anything else you&rsquo;d like, upside-down.
This challenges the visual cortex to work harder and then the thalamus to relay the information to the correct part of the body/brain. </p>
<p>It works like a brain workout by increasing blood flow and nutrients.</p><h3>5. Meddle with your morning routine</h3>
<p>Mix things up with your morning routine &ndash; try eating breakfast first and then getting ready. You can also change your breakfast as well. </p>
<p>Anything that&rsquo;s different to the norm gives your brain its own wake up call.</p><h3>6. Start a new hobby</h3>
<p><a href="~/link.aspx?_id=4CFB2E5DB7E34990B39378846BC81584&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="view page">Hobbies</a> that require the use of more than one sense and that are not routine are great for your brain. </p>
<p>Creative writing or sitting down with a good book are both great for you. We are not hardwired to do either of these, so they challenge the brain.</p><h3>7. Make the familiar unfamiliar</h3>
<p>Repositioning the location of familiar items reactivates spatial networks and forces your visual and somatosensory areas of the brain to get busy adjusting your internal maps. </p>
<p>So, rearrange the furniture, change the order of the clothes in your wardrobes, change your cupboards around in the kitchen or bathroom, move your watch to the other wrist &ndash; anything that can help ring in the changes.</p><h3>8. Tantalise your tastebuds</h3>
<p>Once a month try a new food that incorporates exotic tastes and smells. Choose a recipe for breakfast or dinner and shop at a different shop or market for the ingredients.
</p>
<p>
T<span style="font-weight: lighter;">his helps to create a break in the pattern of familiar and gets you out of your comfort zone &ndash; the more we can do this, the more resilient our brain becomes.</span></p><h3>9. Broaden your horizons</h3>
<p>Travelling exposes your senses to the novelty of new surroundings. Spatial maps used for normal navigation are no longer useable and new pathways must be constructed. </p>
<p>Any discomfort or stress you might feel taking in the new sounds, sights and smells is actually your brain kicking it up a notch.</p>
<div class="rich-text__container fill--white">
<div class="container container--sm">
<h4>Try new flavours on holiday</h4>
<p>You can give your brain an extra boost, by combining new flavours and surroundings on holiday.</p>
<p>Saga offers tempting itineraries to Greece, Spain, Italy and Malta, which include tasting trips and expert-led cookery demonstrations.</p>
<p><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://holiday.saga.co.uk/holidays/holiday-types/special-interest/food?icid=magazine|article|travel|holidays|special-interest|food|find-out-more" class="button" target="_blank" title="view page">Learn more</a></p>
</div>
</div><h3>10. Learn a new language</h3>
<p>Take an evening class or give language apps like <a href="https://www.duolingo.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="view product">Duolingo</a> a go. Any discomfort or stress you might feel taking in new languages, sounds and sights is actually your brain kicking it up a notch.
</p>
<p>Learning a new language has <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC3890428/" target="_blank" title="view page">been shown</a> to improve our cognitive function and keep our brain sharp and reactive.</p><h3>11. Shop around</h3>
<p>Change your shopping routine by stopping by a market, butcher shop, bakery, fish market, produce stand or flea market. Specialist food stores usually have staff who know all about their products. </p>
<p>Ask about where items come from and how they are used.
Just by talking about a new topic then seeing, touching and smelling the products (when possible), you are forming new associative links.</p><h3>12. Feel the experience</h3>
<p>Visit a park, beauty spot or safe place in the countryside. Get comfortable and close your eyes. Use your other senses to determine what&rsquo;s happening around you. </p>
<p>Free-associate using the smells and sounds, and &ldquo;feel&rdquo; the experience.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:dcterms="dcterms" xmlns:dc="dc" xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi">
      <title>How to improve your grip strength – and why it matters</title>
      <link>https://www.saga.co.uk/magazine/health-and-wellbeing/how-to-improve-your-grip-strength</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Grip strength doesn’t just allow you to open jars and lift shopping bags, it’s now been found to be a vital indicator of how well you are ageing.]]></description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi" url="/helix-contentlibrary/saga/magazine/articles/2025/08aug/grip-strength/grip-strength-gettyimages-182707964.jpg" medium="image">
        <media:text xmlns:media="media"><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;">Grip strength doesn't just allow you to open jars and lift shopping bags, it's also an indicator of how well you are ageing.</span></p>]]></media:text>
        <media:title xmlns:media="media">How to improve your grip strength (and why it matters)</media:title>
      </media:content>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:21:27 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">{A9028128-7AAD-48BA-9988-8F6E0EC059EC}</guid>
      <cf:isSponsered xmlns:cf="cf">False</cf:isSponsered>
      <cf:hasAffiliateLinks xmlns:cf="cf">False</cf:hasAffiliateLinks>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;">Grappling to open a jar or struggling to carry the weight of a heavy bag are all red flag warning signs that your grip strength is declining.&nbsp;</span><span style="font-weight: lighter;">It&rsquo;s not just a minor annoyance either.</span></p>
<p>&ldquo;Your grip strength should be taken seriously as it&rsquo;s regarded as a powerful indicator of overall health and ageing,&rdquo; explains physiotherapist Sammy Margo, director of <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.smartphysio.co.uk/our-team" target="_blank" title="view page">Smartphysio</a> in London.</p>
<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s not just about how strong you are, or how good you are at grabbing something either, it&rsquo;s a window into what&rsquo;s going on in your body. Lots of research has shown that declining grip strength correlates with <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/jcsm.12857" target="_blank" title="view page">increased rates</a>&nbsp;of mortality and cognitive decline,&nbsp;<a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://bmcgeriatr.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12877-022-02898-8" target="_blank" title="view page">fragility</a> and even deaths from heart disease.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Will Harlow, head physiotherapist at HT Physio, in Farnham, Surrey, and author of <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/1837824118?tag=uklinktagdefault-21&amp;th=1&amp;psc=1&amp;geniuslink=true" target="_blank" title="view page">Thriving Beyond 50</a>, says weakening grip strength is the &ldquo;canary in the coal mine&rdquo; &ndash; a sign that all is not well elsewhere in the body and a biomarker of poor health.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Some <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.bmj.com/content/361/bmj.k1651#:~:text=After%20adjustment%2C%20grip%20strength%20showed%20the%20strongest%20association%2C,1.26%29%20and%20total%20physical%20activity%20%281.06%20and%201.07%29.#:~:text=After%20adjustment%2C%20grip%20strength%20showed%20the%20strongest%20association%2C,1.26%29%20and%20total%20physical%20activity%20%281.06%20and%201.07%29." target="_blank" title="view page">studies</a> have shown that grip strength is actually a better indicator of your risk of dying than high blood pressure,&rdquo; Harlow adds.&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Why is grip strength so important?&nbsp;</h3>
<p>&ldquo;Poor grip strength is an early sign of muscle weakness elsewhere in the body,&rdquo; says Margo.</p>
<p>&ldquo;But it&rsquo;s also an indicator of overall strength, bone mineral density, risk of fractures and falls, malnutrition, cognitive impairment, sleep problems, diabetes and quality of life. All of these can affect your longevity and vitality.&rdquo;</p>
<p>On a practical level, a strong grip is vital for an independent life in older age. &ldquo;Grip and hand dexterity is so important for independence,&rdquo; says Harlow. </p>
<p>&ldquo;You need it for getting dressed, opening jars, driving, turning keys in locks. Life gets so difficult when you can&rsquo;t do these things.&rdquo;</p><h3>Does grip strength relate to dementia risk?</h3>
<p><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://experts.exeter.ac.uk/36926-chris-fox" target="_blank" title="view page">Dr Chris Fox</a>, an old age psychiatrist and professor of clinical psychiatry at the University of Exeter, as well as medical technology industry lead at NIHR HRC England, explains that grip strength also depends on nerves.</p>
<p>&ldquo;A lower grip strength has been associated with cognitive impairment and neurodegenerative diseases,&rdquo; Fox says.</p>
<p>One <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/2793510" target="_blank" title="view page">study</a> based on data from the UK Biobank found that poor hand grip strength in midlife was associated with cognitive decline a decade later. </p>
<p>The authors concluded the association between grip strength and dementia may be due to the presence of vascular disease (which affects the circulatory system). They even suggested increasing muscle strength in midlife &ldquo;may hold promise for maintenance of neurocognitive brain health&rdquo;.</p>
<h3>Why does your grip get weaker as you age?</h3>
<p>&ldquo;We know that grip strength peaks between the ages of 20 and 30,&rdquo; says Margo. </p>
<p>&ldquo;After the age of 45/50, we typically lose approximately one per cent of muscle mass per year as part of the ageing process &ndash; this is known as sarcopenia. This muscle loss increases to approximately 1.5% a year between 50 and 60 and 3% a year after that.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Another equally important cause of weaker grip in the over 65s is osteoarthritis in the small joints of the fingers, caused by the wearing down of cartilage in those joints, says Harlow. </p>
<p>&ldquo;This can make those joints swollen and painful, and it can also result in loss of dexterity and power,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;I&rsquo;ve got patients as young as 50 who have lost grip strength, but it tends to accelerate in the 65-plus age group.</p>
<p>&ldquo;The good news is that loss of grip strength isn&rsquo;t inevitable as you can counter the effects of this with specific exercises designed to maintain and build up muscle strength.&rdquo; (see below).</p>
<h3>What muscles affect your grip strength?</h3>
<p>How hard you can grip is determined by the strength of the muscles in the hands, but also those between your wrist and elbow, says Harlow.</p>
<p>The flexor muscles in the forearm and wrist are particularly important as they control movements of the hands and fingers.</p>
<h3>How can I measure my grip strength?</h3>
<p>Gadgets called <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Dynamometers/b" target="_blank" title="view page">dynamometers</a> to measure and improve your grip strength are now available to buy. </p>
<p>&ldquo;You squeeze them as hard as you can with both your dominant hand and then non-dominant hand to measure your grip strength and log improvements when you start exercising,&rdquo; says Margo. </p>
<p>&ldquo;Many of them combine testing with training your muscles &ndash; I recommend them to my patients.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Average grip strengths vary according to age. According to one study, average grip strengths were:</p>
<ul class="list list--accent">
    <li>60 to 64: 39kg for men and 24kg for women</li>
    <li>70 to 74: 35kg for men and 22kg for women</li>
    <li>80 to 85: 28kg for men and 20kg for women</li>
</ul>
<p>Another <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://academic.oup.com/biomedgerontology/article/69/5/559/672523?login=false" target="_blank" title="view page">study</a> published in the journal Gerontology, which involved measuring the grip strength of 9,897 men and 10,950 women, classified weak grip strength in men as less than 26kg and less than 16kg in women.&nbsp;</p>
<h3>What exercises can I do to improve my grip strength?&nbsp;&nbsp;</h3>
<p>You don&rsquo;t have to go to a gym to improve your grip strength. Everyday activities such as carrying shopping bags, wringing out a wet towel, using a watering can or weeding the garden can all help.</p>
<h2>7 easy exercises to strengthen your grip&nbsp;&nbsp;</h2>
<h3>1. Squeeze a sponge or towel</h3>
<p>&ldquo;Hold a sponge in your hand and grip it as hard as you can, really pushing your fingers into it for ten seconds and then releasing it and doing this three times in a row,&rdquo; says Harlow. </p>
<p>&ldquo;Alternatively, you could grip it and release it quickly and repeatedly. You might do ten or 15 of these shorter squeezes consecutively.</p>
<p>&ldquo;If you can do these morning, lunchtime and evening that will go a long way towards improving your grip. Some people may notice instant improvements &ndash; in others it might take four to six weeks.&rdquo;</p><h3>2. Pinch your thumb to your forefingers</h3>
<p><strong></strong>&ldquo;Open out your palm and then bring your thumb and forefinger together and pinch, then move your thumb onto each of the other three fingers and repeat the pinch,&rdquo; says Harlow. &ldquo;Practise it in 30 to 60-second bursts. This one is great for improving dexterity.&rdquo;</p>
<h3>3. Do the farmer&rsquo;s carry</h3>
<p><strong></strong>&ldquo;For this exercise you can either carry weights in both hands or fill up watering cans in the garden (or something else quite heavy) and then walk ten paces forward and ten paces back, and repeat three times,&rdquo; says Harlow. </p>
<p>&ldquo;Start with a weight you can manage and gradually build up. Some people like to do this in the garden watering their plants. It&rsquo;s a good whole-body workout, as well as a grip strengthener.&rdquo;</p><h3>4. Strengthen your hands and wrists with a wrist curl</h3>
<p><strong></strong>&ldquo;Take a light dumbbell weight (1-2kg) or a can of beans/litre bottle of water and then rest your forearm on a table with the hand holding the weight hanging off the table so your wrist is almost bent down,&rdquo; says Harlow.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Bring your knuckle up towards your wrist, so you&rsquo;re pulling the back side of your arm up towards your forearm and then slowly back down. Repeat ten times or as many times as you can manage to start with.&rdquo;</p><h3>5. Expand a rubber band with your fingers</h3>
<p><strong></strong>&ldquo;Expand a rubber/elastic band around your fingers and stretch your fingers out as far as possible and then slowly close,&rdquo; says Harlow. </p>
<p>&ldquo;Repeat ten times and do three sessions a day. With all these exercises I&rsquo;d say doing one set is better than none but doing two or three sessions a day would be ideal.&rdquo;</p><h3>6. Grip a towel with one hand and pull with the other</h3>
<p><strong></strong>&ldquo;This exercise combines grip with resistance,&rdquo; explains Margo.</p>
<h3>7. Squeeze a stress ball</h3>
<p><strong></strong>&ldquo;Squeeze a rubber ball &ndash; the firmer the better &ndash; holding for three to five seconds and releasing and repeat ten times,&rdquo; says Margo. &ldquo;Try to do progressively more repetitions.&rdquo;</p>
<div class="rich-text__container fill--saga-blue-20">
<div class="container container--sm">
<h4>Can eating more protein improve my grip strength?</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;"></span><span style="font-weight: lighter;"><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23867520/" target="_blank" title="view page">Studies</a> suggest that people over 65 should aim for a daily protein intake of 1 to 1.2g of protein per kg of body weight, to maintain muscle strength and those with chronic or acute medical conditions, or who are active and exercise, should consume 1.2g or more per kg of their body weight.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;">&ldquo;Protein sources include eggs lean meat, poultry fish, dairy products, nuts and seeds, beans and pulses, plus tofu and soya,&rdquo; says Fox. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;">&ldquo;Creatine supplements [a compound that helps supply energy to muscles and speed up muscle repair] may be helpful for maintaining muscle mass. I take them.&rdquo;</span></p>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:dcterms="dcterms" xmlns:dc="dc" xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi">
      <title>The 7 foods you should add to your diet</title>
      <link>https://www.saga.co.uk/magazine/health-and-wellbeing/foods-you-should-add-to-your-diet</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Are you getting enough of the foods that keep us healthy as we age? If you want your diet to help you feel well and stay well, here’s what to choose.]]></description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi" url="/helix-contentlibrary/saga/magazine/articles/2024/08-august/gettyimages-1646597107-colourful-tomatoes-healthy-foods-mirceax-768.jpg" medium="image">
        <media:text xmlns:media="media"><![CDATA[Are you getting enough of the foods that keep us healthy as we age? Here's what to choose.]]></media:text>
        <media:title xmlns:media="media">The 7 foods you should add to your diet</media:title>
      </media:content>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:17:04 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">{6454B4C7-4F37-412F-B66E-7D74F2A2EB04}</guid>
      <cf:isSponsered xmlns:cf="cf">False</cf:isSponsered>
      <cf:hasAffiliateLinks xmlns:cf="cf">False</cf:hasAffiliateLinks>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Eating healthily doesn&rsquo;t need to be about depriving yourself &ndash; adding to your diet can be just as effective. We&rsquo;ve all read about &ldquo;superfoods&rdquo; that can supposedly work miracles, but you&rsquo;re better off with the simple things we need to stay healthy.</p>
<p>And you can easily add them to your shopping list, or eat them a bit more often if you buy them already. </p>
<p> Read on to discover an expert dietitian&rsquo;s top choices.</p>
<h3>1. A rainbow of fruit and vegetables</h3>
<p>We all know we should be getting our&nbsp;<a rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" href="https://www.nhs.uk/live-well/eat-well/5-a-day/5-a-day-what-counts/" title="View page">five portions a day</a>&nbsp;&ndash; or even&nbsp;<a href="~/link.aspx?_id=4B44EA3646A1442883747A6C1302F9A5&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="view page">30 plants a week</a>&nbsp;&ndash; but are you getting enough variety?&nbsp;</p>
<p><a rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" href="https://www.dietitianuk.co.uk/" title="View page">Priya Tew</a>, director of Dietitian UK, says: &ldquo;If you&rsquo;ve traditionally stuck to broccoli, peas and carrots, experiment with something new.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Try and get as many different colours as you can into your meals and you&rsquo;ll be getting a range of different antioxidants,&nbsp;<a href="~/link.aspx?_id=19F33E2A2CF54A4F9D9C1575C34DAD5D&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="View page">vitamins</a>&nbsp;and minerals into your diet, which is really great in terms of ageing and overall health.&rdquo;</p>
<h3><strong>2. Sardines on toast (and other oily fish)</strong></h3><p>We&rsquo;re all recommended to eat two portions of fish a week, including one (about 140g) of oily fish, because it helps to keep the heart healthy (and because fish contains a range of vitamins and minerals). Most of us don&rsquo;t manage that, but you don&rsquo;t need to buy it fresh because frozen or tinned works just as well.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Oily fish such as salmon, herring,&nbsp;<a href="~/link.aspx?_id=B8BD85EBD25A4DBABE13977ABEC4C33F&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="View page">sardines</a>&nbsp;and mackerel is a great source of&nbsp;<a href="~/link.aspx?_id=D217B7743DE54396A81ECC95BF520857&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="View page">omega-3</a>, which is important for heart health and keeping your blood pressure steady,&rdquo; says Tew. &ldquo;Tinned sources are fine as well, so your sardines on toast are ideal.&rdquo;</p>
<h3><strong>3. Seeds</strong></h3>
<p>Are you eating enough fibre? It&rsquo;s recommended that we have 30g a day, but&nbsp;<a rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" href="https://www.nhs.uk/live-well/eat-well/digestive-health/how-to-get-more-fibre-into-your-diet" title="View page">research</a>&nbsp;suggests most adults only manage 20g. Fibre supports your gut health, and there&rsquo;s evidence that wholegrains, seeds and <a href="~/link.aspx?_id=E1FA2D009A344C41A523D59C9760D4F6&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="View page">nuts</a>, which are all high in fibre, are associated with heart health, too. </p>
<p>While breakfast cereals, such as Bran Flakes are high in fibre, there are plenty of other ways (without the added sugar and salt that Bran Flakes contain).</p>
<p>&ldquo;Chia seeds and linseeds will add more fibre in a compact way. They contain soluble fibre which helps you form a softer stool and helps it pass through your digestive system,&rdquo; says Tew. </p>
<p>&ldquo;If you&rsquo;re struggling with gut health issues or diverticulitis, being aware of fibre is so important. Sprinkle the seeds on your breakfast cereal or add them to porridge or smoothies. Once you soak them in water they swell up, so that&rsquo;s a nice, easy way to get your fibre in.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Wholemeal varieties of bread and pasta, porridge oats, brown rice and skin-on potatoes will also help increase your fibre intake, and the fibre content is another reason why vegetables and fruit are always worth adding to your diet.&nbsp;</p>
<h3><strong>4. Greek yogurt</strong></h3>
<p>It&rsquo;s delicious, it&rsquo;s creamy and it goes with breakfast, lunch and dinner, but Greek yogurt has health benefits too. </p>
<p>Tew says: &ldquo;Greek or live yogurt is a good probiotic for your gut, bringing the beneficial bacteria in. It&rsquo;s good for calcium too. Although our bones are no longer growing as we get older, we want to be looking after them.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p>
<p>Standard Greek yogurt is higher in fat than standard plain yogurt (usually around 10% fat), so choose a low-fat version if you&rsquo;re watching your weight or your cholesterol levels.</p>
<h3>5. Tofu or chicken&nbsp;</h3>
<p>Lean protein is an important part of a balanced diet, particularly as we age. Milk, fish, eggs and chicken are all sources you might already be eating, but there&rsquo;s another protein source that&rsquo;s packed with nutrients.</p>
<p>&ldquo;I know tofu is a bit of an unusual one, but it&rsquo;s a really good source of calcium and iron as well as protein,&rdquo; says Tew. </p>
<p>&ldquo;Eat protein-rich foods at every meal. Protein becomes more important as we age, but rather than measuring it out, think: &lsquo;Let&rsquo;s make sure I have a portion of protein with breakfast, lunch and dinner&rsquo;. </p>
<p>&ldquo;Use the palm of your hand as a guide. If you&rsquo;re thinking about chicken and fish, eat a portion that&rsquo;s the size of your whole hand, including your fingers, whereas for a piece of red meat such as steak you just need the size of your palm.&rdquo;</p>
<h3>6. Berries</h3><p>Fruit is good, but berries deserve their own place on the list due to their multi-tasking goodness. </p>
<p>&ldquo;There&rsquo;s evidence-based research on the&nbsp;<a rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34334393/" title="View page">MIND Diet</a>&nbsp;which finds that eating berries improves your cognitive function, which can help with memory and how your brain is working,&rdquo; says Tew.</p>
<p>&ldquo;We think that&rsquo;s due to the antioxidants and phytochemicals that are in berries, plus they&rsquo;re a good way of getting fibre in. Go for a variety of colours &ndash; and whichever ones you like.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Mix blueberries with&nbsp;<a href="~/link.aspx?_id=3D402D03A15140F39D715684AB30BE3E&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="View page">strawberries</a>&nbsp;or raspberries and add <a href="~/link.aspx?_id=223AE11BE0884826AA00B467FBA61C0F&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="view page">blackberries</a>&nbsp;when they&rsquo;re in season. &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t forget it&rsquo;s OK to use frozen berries &ndash; it can be so much easier if you&rsquo;re living on your own and don&rsquo;t want expensive fruit to go to waste if you don&rsquo;t eat the whole pack,&rdquo; says Tew.</p>
<h3>7. Nuts</h3>
<p>Good news for snackers: swap your crisps for&nbsp;<a rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" href="https://www.saga.co.uk/magazine/health-and-wellbeing/which-nuts-are-healthiest-6-of-the-best-with-benefits" title="View page">nuts</a>&nbsp;and you&rsquo;re onto a winner. &ldquo;Nuts are little powerhouses of different nutrients. They&rsquo;re great in terms of protein, they have fibre and contain lots of different vitamins and minerals,&rdquo; says Tew.</p>
<p>&ldquo;If you like a snack, nuts are a good way to fill you up. Research shows they&rsquo;re great for weight maintenance if you have sensible portions, which is a handful a few times a week. </p>
<p>&ldquo;They&rsquo;re included in the&nbsp;<a rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank" href="https://www.bhf.org.uk/informationsupport/heart-matters-magazine/nutrition/mediterranean-diet" title="View page">Mediterranean diet</a>, which is one of the healthiest ways to eat because it&rsquo;s based on lean proteins, fruit and vegetables, and nuts and seeds.&rdquo;</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:dcterms="dcterms" xmlns:dc="dc" xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi">
      <title>Don’t store these 7 foods in the fridge</title>
      <link>https://www.saga.co.uk/magazine/homes/foods-you-should-not-store-in-the-fridge</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Cool rules – these foods will lose their flavour and freshness if you store them in the fridge.]]></description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi" url="/helix-contentlibrary/saga/magazine/articles/2024/10-october/gettyimages-1334792004-tomatoes-in-fridge-hero.jpg" medium="image">
        <media:text xmlns:media="media"><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;">These foods will lose flavour and freshness if you store them in the fridge.</span></p>]]></media:text>
        <media:title xmlns:media="media">Don’t store these 7 foods in the fridge</media:title>
      </media:content>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 09:58:53 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">{CD1CF015-BB0C-48C4-8EAC-670E87A4B31D}</guid>
      <cf:isSponsered xmlns:cf="cf">False</cf:isSponsered>
      <cf:hasAffiliateLinks xmlns:cf="cf">False</cf:hasAffiliateLinks>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s tempting, especially during hot weather, to stash away as many groceries as possible in the fridge &ndash; after all, cool temperatures of 5&deg;C (41&deg;F) or lower help keep perishables fresher for longer, right?</p>
<p>In most cases, yes. The colder the temperature, the slower microorganisms will grow. But like the best of us on a typical morning in deepest winter, there are some foods that simply can&rsquo;t stand the cold.</p>
<p>These popular staples lose flavour, texture and freshness if they&rsquo;re exposed to the nippy environment of the fridge, and should ideally be stored alongside your tins and jars in a larder or cupboard, or left out on the counter top.</p>
<h2>7 foods you should not store in the fridge</h2>
<p>Make a note of these seven foods that should never be chilled and free up some space in your fridge.</p>
<h3>1. Tomatoes</h3>
<p>Sunshine-loving&nbsp;<a href="~/link.aspx?_id=35AD2F39D521448B972FB6C074D8A817&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="View page">tomatoes</a> loathe the cold and deteriorate rapidly when chilled.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;">Tomatoes produce savoury umami compounds, which give them their distinctive aroma and flavour. Chilling the salad favourite inhibits the activity of the enzymes that create these compounds, impacting fragrance and flavour.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>Cool temperatures also damage the cell membrane, creating an unpleasant mealy texture. Tomatoes should always be stored on the counter top at room temperature (ideally around 20&deg;C / 68&deg;F).</p>
<h3>2. Bread</h3>
<p>If you think that storing your <a href="~/link.aspx?_id=609521D8C4494E27B25A30F5153B62C4&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="view page">bread</a>&nbsp;in the fridge will prolong its shelf life, it&rsquo;s time to think again. In his seminal <span style="font-weight: lighter;"><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Food-Cooking-Science-Lore-Kitchen/dp/0684800012" target="_blank" title="View page">On Food and Cooking</a>&nbsp;</span><em style="font-weight: lighter;"></em>book &ndash; considered the bible of food science &ndash; Harold McGee stresses that bread should never be kept in the fridge.</p>
<p>The cool, drying environment rapidly dehydrates the loaf and changes its molecular structure, speeding up staling &ndash; you end up with stale, dry-textured bread.</p>
<p>Weirdly, freezing rather than chilling actually slows down this process, so either store your loaf in a bag or bread bin on the counter top or whack it in the freezer for later use.</p>
<h3>3. Basil</h3>
<p>Delicate Mediterranean herbs such as basil come from warm, sunny climes and have no time for the cold. The lower temperatures of the fridge speed up oxidisation, turning the leaves black and ruining the herb&rsquo;s heady scent and flavour.</p>
<p>To avoid this, blanche&nbsp;the herb in boiling water for a few seconds, then immerse in ice-cold H2O before drying the leaves completely &ndash; heat kills the enzymes that cause oxidisation, so this handy culinary trick should keep your basil vibrantly green for longer.</p>
<p>Store your basil at room temperature on the counter top in a jar filled with water to prolong its shelf life and prevent premature discolouration.</p>
<h3>4. Cucumbers</h3><p>Super-refreshing and crisp, cucumber is often stored in the fridge, but according to <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://postharvest.ucdavis.edu/produce-facts-sheets/cucumber#:~:text=Chilling%20Injury.,areas%2C%20pitting%20and%20accelerated%20decay.#:~:text=Chilling%20Injury.,areas%2C%20pitting%20and%20accelerated%20decay." target="_blank" title="View page">researchers</a>&nbsp;at the University of California, temperatures under 10&deg;C (50&deg;F) actually cause damage.</p>
<p>Cucumbers develop what the experts describe as &ldquo;chilling injuries&rdquo; in the fridge &ndash; at low temperatures, the skin shrivels and pits, and the pulp turns mushy.</p>
<p>Store your cucumbers in a bowl on the counter top or in a cupboard if you can, and if you prefer them cold, pop them in the fridge an hour before you want to eat &ndash; this should do the trick without causing significant damage.</p>
<h3>5. Garlic</h3>
<p>The cold environment of the fridge mimics the growing conditions of garlic, so it&rsquo;s no wonder bulbs are prone to developing shoots if they are stored this way.</p>
<p>Unless you fancy planting the shooting bulbs to grow garlic greens, storing your garlic in the fridge is best avoided.</p>
<p>Cool-ish room temperatures with low humidity make for the ideal storage conditions for garlic. An airy larder or cupboard is perfect, but try to keep the garlic away from foods that might take on its pungent odour.</p>
<h3>6. Chocolate</h3>
<p>The fridge may seem like a great place to store your <a href="~/link.aspx?_id=7817C3C30A2B4356A836802DFBC5BC6D&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="view page">chocolate</a>, especially if you&rsquo;re concerned about it melting, but you&rsquo;d be better off eating it there and then.</p>
<p>Chocolate is sensitive to sudden temperature changes and can develop an unappealing white &ldquo;bloom&rdquo; if placed in the fridge. The molecular changes that cause the bloom spoil the smooth texture and the chocolate can become unpleasantly gritty.</p>
<p>Chocolate readily assimilates odours, so it can absorb unpleasant smells as well as lose its smoothness if it&rsquo;s stored in the fridge. </p>
<p>Ideally, keep your chocolate well-wrapped at cool-ish room temperature in a larder or cupboard, away from strong-smelling foods.</p>
<h3>7. Honey</h3>
<p>Naturally antibacterial, <a href="~/link.aspx?_id=4A1B4A14C0074C84B0BCB4D0730A9C08&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="View page">honey</a>&nbsp;lasts for ages when stored at room temperature in properly sealed packaging. There&rsquo;s really no need to squirrel away this sweet treat in the fridge &ndash; the cold temperatures won&rsquo;t do the honey any favours.</p>
<p>When chilled, honey tends to crystallise and turn gritty &ndash; it is still edible in this state, but many people prefer the smoothness of uncrystallised honey.</p>
<p>If you want to reduce the risk of your honey solidifying and going lumpy, always store at room temperature in a larder or cupboard.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:dcterms="dcterms" xmlns:dc="dc" xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi">
      <title>The unusual heart attack symptoms you need to know</title>
      <link>https://www.saga.co.uk/magazine/health-and-wellbeing/the-unusual-heart-attack-symptoms-you-need-to-know</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Do you know the symptoms of a heart attack? Here’s what to look out for - and how to prevent one.]]></description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi" url="/helix-contentlibrary/exceptional/2023/08/shutterstock_2344737895/heart-image.jpg" medium="image">
        <media:text xmlns:media="media"><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;">Do you know the symptoms of a heart attack? Here&rsquo;s what to look out for, and how to prevent one.</span></p>]]></media:text>
        <media:title xmlns:media="media">The unusual heart attack symptoms you need to know</media:title>
      </media:content>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:09:49 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">{8EC90C2F-6855-4C05-8F43-A5547CA2E2C8}</guid>
      <cf:isSponsered xmlns:cf="cf">False</cf:isSponsered>
      <cf:hasAffiliateLinks xmlns:cf="cf">False</cf:hasAffiliateLinks>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Would you recognise a heart attack if you were having one? An <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/2023/08/nhs-launches-lifesaving-campaign-to-help-people-spot-a-heart-attack/" target="_blank" title="view page">NHS survey</a> suggests that while most people know about chest pain, they&rsquo;re not aware of some of the other important symptoms.</p>
<p>Fewer than half the people responding knew that another heart attack symptom is sweating and only a third would spot other signs, which include feeling weak, lightheaded or generally uneasy.</p>
<p>The NHS is highlighting the lesser-known symptoms &ndash; and although there&rsquo;s a chance they could be nothing to worry about &ndash; it&rsquo;s important to call for help quickly rather than ignore them.</p>
<h3>It&rsquo;s not just chest pain</h3>
<p>NHS figures show that the number of people admitted to hospital in England with a heart attack has risen to one of the highest levels ever: 100,000. </p>
<p>The British Heart Foundation says that currently there are&nbsp;<span style="font-weight: lighter;">more than 7.6 million people living with heart and circulatory diseases in the UK, but there could be one million more by 2030, and two million more by 2040.&nbsp;</span></p>
<h2>The symptoms of a heart attack</h2>
<ul class="list list--accent">
    <li>Chest pain &ndash; this could be severe or minor, similar to indigestion.</li>
    <li>A feeling of pressure, heaviness, tightness or squeezing across your chest.</li>
    <li>Pain in other parts of your body &ndash; and a feeling that pain is spreading from your chest to your arms (particularly the left), jaw, neck, back and stomach.</li>
    <li>Feeling lightheaded or dizzy.</li>
    <li>Sweating.</li>
    <li>Shortness of breath.</li>
    <li>Feeling or being sick.</li>
    <li>A feeling of unease or anxiety, similar to a panic attack.</li>
    <li>Coughing or wheezing due to a build-up of fluid in your lungs.</li>
</ul>
<div class="rich-text__container fill--white">
<div class="container container--sm">
<h4>Experiencing these symptoms? Call 999 immediately</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;">If you notice any of these symptoms, it&rsquo;s important to dial 999 and get them checked immediately.</span></p>
</div>
</div><h3>Don&rsquo;t wait! Every minute matters</h3>
<p>If you&rsquo;re having a heart attack, it means the supply of blood to your heart has become blocked, which can starve it of oxygen, potentially causing serious muscle damage. </p>
<p>You could still be conscious and breathing. </p>
<h3>Women are worse at recognising heart attack symptoms</h3>
<p>Heart attack symptoms can vary from person to person and it&rsquo;s better to dial 999 early than ignore them if you think something&rsquo;s wrong. Women, in particular, are being advised to take heart attack symptoms seriously, as their risk increases after the menopause. </p>
<p>The British Heart Foundation warns that <strong><a href="https://www.bhf.org.uk/informationsupport/conditions/heart-attack/signs-and-symptoms-of-heart-attacks-in-women" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="view page">women</a></strong> tend to not recognise the symptoms because they believe it&rsquo;s more of a male problem. </p>
<p>In fact, 30,000 women are admitted to hospital following a heart attack every year &ndash; and they should look out for the same symptoms as men.</p>
<p><span>A <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.bhf.org.uk/what-we-do/news-from-the-bhf/news-archive/2019/august/no-difference-in-key-heart-attack-symptoms-between-men-and-women#:~:text=%EE%80%80Chest%EE%80%81%20%EE%80%80pain%EE%80%81%20%EE%80%80was%EE%80%81%20%EE%80%80the%EE%80%81%20%EE%80%80most%EE%80%81%20%EE%80%80common%EE%80%81" target="_blank" title="view page">2019 study</a> found that c</span><span>hest pain was the most common symptom for both men and women, with 93% of both sexes reporting this symptom.</span></p>
<p><span>A similar percentage of men and women reported pain that radiated to their left arm (48% of men and 49% of women). </span></p>
<p><span>More women had pain that radiated to their jaw or back and women were also more likely to experience nausea in addition to chest pain (33% vs 19%).</span></p>
<h3>Call for help straight away</h3>
<p>Your chances of surviving a heart attack are boosted if you seek care earlier: around one in seven people survive, but that increases to more than nine out of ten (94%) if you seek help as soon as possible after the onset of symptoms.</p>
<p>A heart attack is a medical emergency, so don&rsquo;t worry about wasting paramedics&rsquo; time: call 999 for an ambulance immediately.</p>
<p>Professor <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/author/professor-nick-linker/" target="_blank" title="view page">Nick Linker</a>, cardiologist and NHS national clinical director for heart disease, said: &ldquo;Cardiovascular disease causes one in four deaths across the country, so it is vital that people are aware of the early signs of a heart attack.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Every moment that passes during a heart attack increases heart muscle damage and nearly all of the damage takes place within the first few hours, so if you experience symptoms such as a sensation of squeezing or tightness across the chest alongside sweating, nausea, or a sense of unease, please call 999 so you have the best chance of a full recovery.&rdquo;</p>
<div class="rich-text__container fill--saga-blue-20">
<div class="container container--sm">
<h4>Every minute counts</h4>
<p>Dr Charmaine Griffiths, chief executive at the British Heart Foundation, said: &ldquo;Every minute matters when somebody is having a heart attack, and could be the difference between life and death. </p>
<p>"Even if the symptoms don&rsquo;t seem severe, such as a feeling of squeezing or tightness across the chest &ndash; call 999 immediately.</p>
<p>&ldquo;A heart attack is a medical emergency and immediate action could save your life.&rdquo;</p>
</div>
</div>
<h3>My heart attack symptoms were silent</h3>
<p>Louise Finan, 60, from West London, told Saga Magazine there are more heart attack symptoms than just chest pain. </p>
<p>&ldquo;My first heart attack happened when I was under a lot of stress,&rdquo; she said. &ldquo;I&rsquo;d been in bed with pneumonia and I knew I didn&rsquo;t feel right, but I didn&rsquo;t have the traditional symptoms such as chest pains.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Fortunately, my daughter called an ambulance &ndash; the paramedics spotted I was having a silent heart attack and took me to hospital. Just as the doctors were treating me, I felt a huge pressure across my chest. It felt like someone had put a concrete slab on me.</p>
<p>&ldquo;I had to have a blood clot removed and I later had a stem cell transplant. </p>
<p>"There are so many scenarios with heart attacks, so if you think something&rsquo;s wrong you should never ignore the feeling.&rdquo;</p>
<h2>What can I do to help prevent heart attacks?</h2>
<p>The&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bhf.org.uk/informationsupport/conditions/heart-attack#risk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="view page">British Heart Foundation</a>&nbsp;has advice on keeping your heart healthy:</p>
<ul class="list list--accent">
    <li></li>
    <li>Keep active: <a href="~/link.aspx?_id=3C43B9BC16D142B399FAC449AC26A82E&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="view page">walking</a>, <a href="~/link.aspx?_id=A5AF31E106DD4360995A3D6713A6A70B&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="view page">gardening</a>&nbsp;and any movement is good for you. Find out more about the benefits of <a href="~/link.aspx?_id=F1D1DAD8C45E46398A8BF868BF0EEFF9&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="view page">cardio exercise</a> and <a href="~/link.aspx?_id=584F30DA81DF447693F980A5522FE2CB&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="View page">strength training</a>.</li>
    <li>Maintain a healthy weight and <a href="~/link.aspx?_id=04652E0489C84612AB1AAEB00C5C570B&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="View page">eat well</a> to prevent extra strain on your heart.</li>
    <li>Limit your alcohol intake to less than the recommended 14 units a week.</li>
    <li>Stop smoking.</li>
    <li>Keep an eye on your blood pressure and cholesterol levels.</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:dcterms="dcterms" xmlns:dc="dc" xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi">
      <title>Surprising foods that could be keeping you awake at night</title>
      <link>https://www.saga.co.uk/magazine/health-and-wellbeing/foods-that-keep-you-awake</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Ever wondered why you can’t sleep? Your diet might be to blame.]]></description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi" url="/helix-contentlibrary/saga/magazine/articles/2025/08aug/foods-that-keep-you-up/sleep-struggles-gettyimages-1325620947.jpg" medium="image">
        <media:text xmlns:media="media"><![CDATA[<p>Ever wondered why you can't sleep? Your diet might be to blame.</p>]]></media:text>
        <media:title xmlns:media="media">Surprising foods that could be keeping you awake at night</media:title>
      </media:content>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:12:32 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">{D886793D-8C50-4FDD-8C64-1B4B80035E29}</guid>
      <cf:isSponsered xmlns:cf="cf">False</cf:isSponsered>
      <cf:hasAffiliateLinks xmlns:cf="cf">False</cf:hasAffiliateLinks>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&rsquo;ve all heard the saying that eating cheese before bed gives you nightmares, but is it really true? Well, new research has revealed that consuming cheese can cost Brits up to 18 days of sleep a year and increases dream frequency by 146%, with 57% of those classed as nightmares.</p>
<p>Over four nights, luxury sleep brand&nbsp;<a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://oddmattress.co.uk/" title="view page" target="_blank">The Odd Company</a> asked 30 participants to dine on four of the UK&rsquo;s most popular cheeses - Brie, cheddar, Stilton, and mozzarella - to determine whether they disrupt sleep, and if so, which variety was the worst offender.</p>
<p>According to the research, just 30g of cheese before bed was enough to disrupt sleep and increase night waking, with mozzarella and Stilton causing the greatest sleep loss.</p>
<p>But it&rsquo;s not just cheese that can interrupt our sleep and as well as the usual suspects such as alcohol and caffeine keeping us awake, foods including spicy dishes, sweets, tomatoes, citrus fruits and even the amount of water you drink.</p>
<p>We spoke to Dr. Naomi Newman-Beinart (PhD), nutritionist,&nbsp;chartered psychologist and health expert, and Kyle Crowley, nutritionist and Chief Product Officer at <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.theproteinworks.com/" title="view page" target="_blank">Protein Works</a>, to ask about the effect certain foods have on our sleep, what we should avoid and what we need to consume to have a good night&rsquo;s rest.</p>
<h4><strong>Does cheese really ruin sleep?</strong></h4>
<p>According to Dr Newman-Beinhat, it all depends on the amount you eat and what type you consume.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Cheese isn&rsquo;t off-limits before bed, but portion size and the type of cheese seems to matter,&rdquo; she explains. &ldquo;A small amount of cheese may even promote relaxation due to its tryptophan content, which supports melatonin production, but rich, aged cheeses may be harder to digest and could disrupt sleep in sensitive individuals.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Aged cheeses like Stilton, cheddar, and parmesan contain high levels of tyramine, a compound that can stimulate the brain and potentially interfere with sleep, particularly if you&rsquo;re prone to insomnia.&rdquo;</p><p>And Crowley agrees that it&rsquo;s certain cheeses which can negatively impact sleep and cause nightmares.</p>
<p>&ldquo;There are several reasons as to why cheese may negatively affect sleep,&rdquo; he explains. &ldquo;One suggestion is that the tyramine found in certain cheeses can trigger the release of noradrenaline, a stimulating neurotransmitter that may disrupt REM sleep and, thus, lead to vivid or disturbing dreams. Cheeses high in tyramine include aged or hand-made varieties such as blue cheese and parmesan.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Another theory attributes sleep disruption to digestive discomfort caused by lactose intolerance, where gas or stomach pain may intensify or cause nightmares.&rdquo;</p>
<h4><strong>What other foods can affect sleep?</strong></h4>
<p>According to our experts, there are quite a lot of foods that can impact how much rest we get at night, and some may surprise you.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Spicy food before bed can sometimes lead to heartburn, which is hardly a recipe for a restful night. In addition, chilli peppers may raise your body temperature, which can make it harder for your body to transition into deep sleep,&rdquo; Crowley says. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s also a good idea to avoid acidic foods like citrus fruits, which can increase the risk of heartburn, as well as fatty or greasy meals, since research shows these can reduce overall sleep quality.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Dr. Newman-Beinhat added, &ldquo;I suggest avoiding spicy meals, heavy or fatty foods, and anything high in caffeine or sugar before bedtime. These can cause indigestion, raise your core body temperature, or stimulate your nervous system, all of which make it harder to fall and stay asleep. And when it comes to water, hydration is important, but drinking too much water close to bedtime can disrupt sleep with overnight bathroom trips.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Nightshades, such as tomatoes, potatoes, aubergine and peppers, can also affect individuals&nbsp;<a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.alaskasleep.com/how-your-dietary-choices-affect-your-sleep/" target="_blank" title="view page">according to the Alaska Sleep Clinic</a> as some people may be more sensitive to certain compounds found in nightshades and experience increased anxiety, restlessness, or insomnia.</p>
<p>Foods high in fat and sugar, such as cookies, cake and sweets can interrupt healthy sleep patterns, especially when eaten close to bedtime. The high saturated fat content of these treats can contribute to acid reflux which can keep people awake.&nbsp;</p><h4><strong>What should you eat/drink to get a good night&rsquo;s rest?</strong></h4>
<p>&ldquo;To support restful sleep, opt for foods rich in magnesium, tryptophan, and complex carbohydrates, such as bananas, oats, or a warm chamomile tea,&rdquo; Dr Newman-Beinhat &ldquo;For a targeted supplement,&nbsp;<a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://betteryou.com/products/magnesium-max-sleep-powder?srsltid=AfmBOopvCD0OJkWBLxqk_1gUlow1IfLzmuY7RqA4I_0QuVpCqBmnjpoa" title="view page" target="_blank">BetterYou&rsquo;s&nbsp;Magnesium Sleep Powder</a>&nbsp;combines different types of magnesium with passionflower extract to help promote a feeling of calm and a more restorative night&rsquo;s rest.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;d recommend eating no more than two hours before bed to avoid any digestive issues reducing the chances of physical discomfort that could interfere with your rest.&rdquo; Crowley adds. &ldquo;However, some good snacks to opt for are those that contain melatonin, so pistachios and bananas. In terms of drinks, herbal teas are a</p>
<p>good choice as these can have a calming effect - magnolia tea and chamomile&nbsp;<span style="font-weight: lighter;">tea, in particular.&rdquo;</span></p>
<h4><strong>Does what you eat and drink in the morning and afternoon have an impact on your sleep?</strong></h4>
<p>Yes, it&rsquo;s not just what you consume before you go to bed, according to Dr Newman-Beinhart. &ldquo;Your daily diet plays a big role in your sleep-wake cycle. A balanced intake of protein, healthy fats, and complex carbohydrates throughout the day helps regulate blood sugar and hormones like cortisol, setting you up for better sleep at night.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Crowley concludes, &ldquo;Ideally, try to leave a gap of two to four hours between your last meal and going to sleep. This allows your body enough time to digest, reducing the chances of physical discomfort that could interfere with your rest.&rdquo;</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:dcterms="dcterms" xmlns:dc="dc" xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi">
      <title>Win an all-inclusive Saga holiday for two to Spain</title>
      <link>https://www.saga.co.uk/magazine/travel/win-an-all-inclusive-holiday-to-spain</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Your chance to win a 7-night stay for two at Hotel RH Ifach in the Costa Blanca region of Spain, worth more than £2,000.]]></description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi" url="/helix-contentlibrary/saga/magazine/articles/2025/08aug/spanish-coastline.jpg" medium="image">
        <media:text xmlns:media="media"><![CDATA[Your chance to win a 7-night stay for two at Hotel RH Ifach in the Costa Blanca region of Spain, worth more than &pound;2,000.]]></media:text>
        <media:title xmlns:media="media">Win an all-inclusive Saga holiday for two to Spain</media:title>
      </media:content>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:19:21 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">{DE920820-426E-4DAF-A925-BA59C03592A9}</guid>
      <cf:isSponsered xmlns:cf="cf">False</cf:isSponsered>
      <cf:hasAffiliateLinks xmlns:cf="cf">False</cf:hasAffiliateLinks>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s all about location here. Your home for the week is the <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://holiday.saga.co.uk/holidays/europe/spain/costa-blanca/hotel-rh-ifach" target="_blank" title="view page">Hotel RH Ifach</a>, in Calpe, which is set between the marina and the town centre, with the seafront promenade and sandy beach a couple of minutes&rsquo; walk away. </p>
<p>In front of the hotel lies the Salinas de Calpe &ndash; a salt lake that&rsquo;s a haven for flamingos.Behind it, you&rsquo;ll see the looming figure of the Rock of Ifach, rising some 300 metres above the waves. You can spot it from your lounger by the palm-lined pool. The recently refurbished rooms have balconies overlooking it too. </p>
<p>There&rsquo;s a gym, Jacuzzi, sauna, laundrette and an indoor pool which is heated seasonally. </p>
<p>There are plenty of bars and restaurants close by, and the hotel puts on live music several nights a week.</p><h3>Included in your prize</h3>
<ul class="list list--accent">
    <li>Seven nights in a twin room, from 8 April, 2026</li>
    <li>Nationwide shared car service</li>
    <li>All-inclusive food and drink</li>
    <li>Flights from London Gatwick and transfers&nbsp;<span style="font-weight: lighter;">to your hotel</span></li>
    <li><span style="font-weight: lighter;"></span>Saga host</li>
    <li>20kg checked luggage per person</li>
    <li>Travel insurance and cancellation cover if required</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;">Closing date 30 September 2025. For more information and for <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://Saga.co.uk/spain-prize-draw" target="_blank" title="view page">terms and conditions</a>.</span></p>
<p><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="http://Saga.co.uk/spain-prize-draw" class="button" target="_blank" title="view page">Enter now</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item xmlns:dcterms="dcterms" xmlns:dc="dc" xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi">
      <title>Dizziness – all you need to know </title>
      <link>https://www.saga.co.uk/magazine/health-and-wellbeing/dizziness-what-causes-it</link>
      <description><![CDATA[Feeling dizzy is common in people over 60. We explore the main causes and the easy exercise that can help.]]></description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="media" xmlns:mi="mi" url="/helix-contentlibrary/saga/magazine/articles/2025/08aug/dizziness.jpeg" medium="image">
        <media:text xmlns:media="media"><![CDATA[Feeling dizzy is common in people over 60. We explore the main causes and the easy exercise that can help.]]></media:text>
        <media:title xmlns:media="media">Dizziness – all you need to know </media:title>
      </media:content>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:29:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">{4C563E41-85DC-4165-AF8C-229BA9A0C003}</guid>
      <cf:isSponsered xmlns:cf="cf">False</cf:isSponsered>
      <cf:hasAffiliateLinks xmlns:cf="cf">False</cf:hasAffiliateLinks>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Do you sometimes feel that you or the world around you are spinning and wonder what on earth is going on? You are not alone. </p>
<p>Three in ten people aged 60-plus <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC4306472/" target="_blank" title="view page">complain</a> of persistent dizziness, which often remains unexplained despite specialist assessment.&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Dizziness increases as we age</h3>
<p>Feeling dizzy, lightheaded or off balance are usually signs of vestibular disorders, problems with parts of our inner ear and brain that process incoming sensory cues and control balance and eye movement.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Such problems are increasingly common as we get older &ndash; our ageing society probably explains why they&rsquo;re on the rise.&nbsp;</p>
<p>But while the cause of dizziness is rarely life threatening, it is not an inevitable part of ageing so it&rsquo;s important to get it checked out. </p>
<p>"A bad episode of vertigo or lightheadedness, especially if someone has a fall or near fall, can be scary and affect confidence and quality of life," says consultant neurologist <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.research.ed.ac.uk/en/persons/jon-stone" target="_blank" title="view page">Professor Jon Stone</a> from the Royal Infirmary of Edinburgh.</p>
<p>This is borne out by a <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://hqlo.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12955-021-01864-z" target="_blank" title="view page">2021 Swedish study</a>, which found that 54% of participants, average age 79, complained of dizziness. </p>
<p>They took more medication, experienced greater fatigue, walked more slowly, were more afraid of falling and rated their overall health worse than those unaffected.&nbsp;</p>
<h3>We&rsquo;re better at treating dizziness now</h3>
<p>Dizziness and balance problems have until recently often been poorly recognised and treated. However, a new discipline called neuro-otology is helping to highlight them and there is an increasing number of vestibular rehabilitation services.&nbsp;</p>
<p>"By far the most common cause [of dizziness] in older people is benign paroxysmal positional vertigo (BPPV)," says <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.finder.bupa.co.uk/Consultant/view/319110/thomas_wright_physiotherapy" target="_blank" title="view page">physiotherapist Tom Wright</a>, who runs a falls prevention service at the East Sussex Healthcare NHS Trust.&nbsp;</p>
<h3>What exactly is BPPV?</h3>
<p>"It&rsquo;s when small crystals get stuck in the semicircular canals in the ear and stop them working properly to maintain balance," says Wright.</p>
<p><a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC4306472/" target="_blank" title="view page">One study</a> found that the over-60s were seven times more likely to be affected by BPPV than 18-39s. The risk is raised by diabetes and/or <a href="~/link.aspx?_id=C40946E8D3054361B92FA295A4DC1FED&amp;_z=z" target="_blank" title="view page">vitamin D</a>&nbsp;deficiency, head injury or whiplash. </p>
<p>"Sufferers experience episodes of spinning, usually when rolling over in bed or looking up," says Professor Stone. During these bouts they often experience nystagmus &ndash; rapid, involuntary eye movements when the eyes visibly jump or twitch.&nbsp;</p><p>Unfortunately, GPs often misdiagnose BPPV as labyrinthitis, infection of the inner ear, and prescribe antihistamines that don&rsquo;t tackle the underlying problem and can even make matters worse. </p>
<p>"Back in the 1980s and 1990s doctors were taught that this kind of vertigo was due to squashing of the arteries in the neck, which is untrue," says Professor Stone. </p>
<p>"Although many more doctors are now aware of BPPV, knowledge catches up slowly so people can still be misdiagnosed." </p>
<p>A simple repositioning technique called the <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://www.entuk.org/patients/conditions/90/bppv_and_home_epley_manoeuvre/" target="_blank" title="view page">Epley manoeuvre</a> that clears crystals out of the ear canals can be effective and often works in just one session, says Wright. </p>
<p>Essentially it&rsquo;s a specific sequence of head and neck movements that you do while lying in various positions, guided by a physio. It&rsquo;s increasingly offered at physiotherapists and GPs, as well as ENT and neurology professionals.</p>
<div class="rich-text__container fill--white">
<div class="container container--sm">
<h4><span style="font-weight: lighter;">The quick exercise that cured my dizziness</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;"></span><span style="font-weight: lighter;">Several years ago Anna Smith, now 74, experienced an intense bout of dizziness and nausea while walking upstairs. She got to the bathroom but once there couldn&rsquo;t stand for fear of falling, lying on the floor for two hours.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;">"Every time I moved my head, I experienced this terrible spinning. Eventually I managed to crawl into bed where I stayed for two days. If I moved my head the spinning would kick in and my eyes were jumping," says the former further education teacher from Hove.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;">"Initially my GP thought I might have an inner ear infection and prescribed sea sickness tablets, which I decided not to take as I wanted to tackle the root cause, rather than the symptoms. I couldn&rsquo;t walk in a straight line and could only stand if I had something to hold on to. I had to cancel all my usual activities &ndash; the gym, a Charleston class, my art group and other social events. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;">"My symptoms began to ease after a week but by then my confidence had taken a battering. Eventually I went online and discovered my symptoms were typical of benign paroxysmal positional vertigo (BPPV). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;">"I found a local physiotherapist who came to my house, tested me and then performed the Epley manoeuvre, which involved moving my head in a set sequence to dislodge the offending crystals.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: lighter;">"I had to stay still for the rest of the evening but when I woke next morning I was no longer dizzy &ndash; it was a brilliant feeling. I know BPPV can return but I&rsquo;ve now learned online how to do the manoeuvre so if it comes back I&rsquo;ll know what to do."</span></p>
</div>
</div><h3>What else causes dizziness in later life?</h3>
<p>Another common cause is vestibular migraine, an underdiagnosed condition that often doesn&rsquo;t cause a headache but may involve a visual aura and/or light and sound sensitivity.&nbsp;</p>
<p>A condition called multisensory dizziness &ndash; presbyequilibrium or presbyvestibulopathy (PVP) &ndash; caused by age-related decline in the eyes, ears and nervous system, is another potential culprit in people in their eighties and nineties.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Other causes include:</p>
<ul class="list list--accent">
    <li>Postural hypotension &ndash; a sudden fall in blood pressure when you stand up, often because of dehydration.</li>
    <li>An irregular heart rhythm.</li>
    <li>Side effects of medication, such as anti-epilepsy and blood pressure lowering drugs, tranquillisers, sleeping pills, and drugs to reduce anxiety or depression.</li>
    <li>Dizziness can also be a feature of Long Covid or ME/chronic fatigue syndrome.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<p>Then there are conditions that affect one or more of the senses needed for balance &ndash; including Parkinson&rsquo;s, MS, stroke, heart disease and diabetes. But dizziness won&rsquo;t be the only symptom for these.</p>
<p>The good news is that vestibular rehabilitation &ndash; specially tailored head, neck, eye and balance exercises &ndash; is effective for many types of dizziness (but not if they are heart-related or medication-induced) and can restore quality of life, although it doesn&rsquo;t always provide a complete cure. </p>
<p>Life for dizziness sufferers is finally looking up, says Professor Stone: "Although there is still lack of awareness, things are now improving as doctors become aware of how treatable many of the causes of dizziness are."</p>
<h2>Tips for tackling dizziness</h2>
<h4>1. Slim down your prescription </h4>
<p>Taking three or more medications (known as polypharmacy) is linked to an increased risk of dizziness and falls. </p>
<p>Ask your GP or pharmacist for a medicines review to work out if you still need all your medication. </p>
<h4>2. Eye exercises can help</h4>
<p>What experts call gaze stability &ndash; the ability of eyes to stay fixed on a stable point when the head is moving &ndash; is vital for balance. Vestibular rehabilitation specialists can suggest exercises tailored to you, including teaching you to do an Epley manoeuvre if you have BPPV. </p>
<p>"I wish more people with BPPV realised how easy it is to learn the Epley manoeuvre themselves," says Professor Stone. "A huge amount of unnecessary worry and suffering could be relieved if people learn about this one thing, so do ask your GP about it."</p>
<h4>3. Maintain muscle strength</h4>
<p>Strong muscles help you act on the messages your brain receives from your eyes, joints and movement centres in the brain. </p>
<p>Aim to do strength (resistance) training or whole-body weight exercises twice a week. </p>
<p>A <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC8037700/" target="_blank" title="view page">2021 study</a> found that Pilates was effective. </p>
<h4>4. Foot health can make a difference</h4>
<p>Poor circulation and arthritic changes can make you unsteady on your feet. See the podiatrist or chiropodist regularly. </p>
<p>Choose firm, supportive, well-fitting shoes.</p>
<h4>5. Check your heart and circulation</h4>
<p>Heart and circulatory problems can cause vertigo or light headedness, especially in people with diabetes. Check with your GP.</p>
<h4>6. Eat and drink well </h4>
<p>Low blood glucose caused by skipped or irregular meals and dehydration can cause dizziness. </p>
<h4>7. Stay active </h4>
<p>Exercise and regular physical activity is the best way to restore function of the vestibular system. </p>
<p>The <a rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://laterlifetraining.co.uk/product/otago-follow-dvd/" target="_blank" title="view page">Otago exercise system</a> designed to challenge balance is especially effective.</p>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
